THE NEW YORK MUNIOIPAIi SOCIETY.
■ ■ ' 1■ " * - ■ ■ *'■1* - >
DELUSIVE METHODS
Municipal Financiering.
BY
WILLIAM F. FORD.
—
* i.	»	>‘,pk
i •-• •	_ „	*	*
.flnh‘r
PU U3.ARY
J£fl#37
TILOCN KWHOATIOM*'
1899.	__


>V*V JSvi » -- r,. < V r w	.it, . . J *
0	* ' ■<
	.
rtrwA&i	• ‘
	<
	
,	J
• .	* %»• 1'
	
	t
	i ■f ir **
	
	
	/
' .iir	
> j • i	<
* -rifcCHl	• #
.	
* , ; x*KT:t	
tr«A‘	t
	1 ■<
.►, J rVf btU	
J
' • 1
DELUSIVE METHODS OF MUNICIPAL PINAHCIERWG.
I* relation to the municipal question it will doubtless be admitted that a given system of finance or government plays into the hands of nnecrnpalons officials as it beeomea more complex. It follows from this that in seeking to improve the mode of conducting the business of a city, the aim should be*to simplify, rather than further complicate eariet-ing systems. It is, of course, entirely logical that the operations of its treasury should be the main index by which the tax-payers of a city judge the conduct of their servants, and therefore that any device which tends to complicate the municipal cash account, is especially calculated to work injury, aa in this way a false showing with regard to the condition of the treasury can more easily be given. The first requisite to intelligent voting is that tax-payers shall clearly understand the exact situation of affairs, the state of the treasury being the basis of judgment. As most influences in the official life of a city, whether for good or evil, have, so to speak, their beginning and ending at the treasury, it becomes evident that measures of municipal reform should first be directed thither, having regard both to the manner of regulating the supply of money, and of keeping the treasury accounts.
The mode of governing cities that has held sway during the first century of the republic, may be defined as a crude compromise between representative government and government by legislative commission. The salient feature of its working has been the use made of the funding or borrowing system, together with the effect of such use upon the moral and material condition of the municipality. As the habit of anticipating the proceeds of taxes, first Of the
4
current year, and, second, of several successive yean, has gone to complicate the operations of municipal treasuries, the mode of conducting this borrowing business is worthy of patient study. 1 have, then, to refer first to the manner in which the custom of contracting municipal indebtedness came to be formed ; second, to the means that have been adopted for reducing the debts of cities, and the success attained ; third, to the influence which the creation of debt has exerted, and still exerts upon the voters, and through them upon the property interests of a municipality, and, finally, to the best method of dealing with city debts as they now exist in this country.
On the first point but little need be said, beyond pointing out that the custom of mortgaging the property and industry of American cities grew up with but very little reflection, by the municipal financiers of other yean, with regard to the delusive and treacherous character of the system. From a volume on the Municipal History of Boston, by Josiali Quincy, it appean that in 1823, Mr. Quincy then being mayor,'the expediency of providing by loan for carrying on so-called permanent improvements was recommended for consideration in one of the mayor’s messages. This plan was favored by the mayor, who contended that the only thing required in raising money by loan was that limitations should be adopted to guard against excess and abuse of the borrowing power. Apparently it did not occur to the mayor that to devise effective restrictions might be impossible. *1116 proposition was referred to a committee of city fathers, who came to the conclusion, as reported by Mr. Quincy, “ that the apprehension of a city debt, and the difficulty of preventing such a system in after time from abuse, were considerations sufficient to counterbalance the certain expediency of the measure in its pecuniary effects on the cost of improvements in the city.” There may exist more than this instance of a disposition to hesitate on the part of municipal officers at the creation of a funded debt; but so far as I have been able to learn, the above is the only marked illustration of the kind in the history of our principal seaboard cities.
*
ft
When the policy of anticipating the proceed* of municipal taxes was onoe entered upon, the difficulty of stopping was soon found to be practically insurmountable, inasmuch as like ressons for extraordinary expenditures are constantly arising in the history of a city. In fine, if taxes are not leried and collected when funds are needed for particular purposes, the incentive then being greatest, they will scarcely He collected afterwards when the exigency has passed. It does not appear that those who instituted the custom of municipal borrowing, any more conceived that they were laying the foundation ef such unwieldy debts as now repress the energies of New York and Philadelphia, than did the monarch* of the House of Stuart suppose that their merely temporary anticipations of the revenue would give rise to the plan of mortgaging the resources of futurity as instituted by William III.
It is interesting to note the easy stages by which at first the city of Philadelphia and your own metropolis adopted the Micawber system of finance. In the case of Philadelphia, I cannot learn that any systematic borrowing existed until after the incorporation of the city in 1789, when the mayor was authorized by Councils to borrow from time to time, in anticipation of the annual taxes. So far as appears from the records, the possession of credit in the money market was assumed by the city as something inherent in a municipal corporation. Having once begun to anticipate the collection of taxes, the next step was to mortgage the revenues of a considerable number of yean. The first considerable loan by the Quaker City was made in 1799, when the sum of $150,000 was borrowed for the constnfc-• tlon of water works. This done, the custom arose of creat- • ing loans for the prosecution of all enterprises which by any possible construction could be called permanent improvements. Money was borrowed freely for building sewen, grading and paving streets, and so great was the temptation to incur debt, that to a considerable degree the ordinary current expenses of the city for wages, etc., came to be supplied from loans, intended to be temporary, but which would afterwards be transformed into funded debt.

. • AJ'
6
The financial philosophy of the time ia revealed bj an expression in an ordinance of the Philadelphia councils passed in 1807. In authorizing a loan for expenditures hut little above the ordinary, it was declared that the funds needed u ought to be provided for by money borrowed, than by a tax on the citizens. ”
Without essaying to enter minutely into the histoiy of the debt of New York, I have learned that the funded debt, properly so called, had its inception in 1812. Prior to that time, bonds or obligations of the corporation had been issued to creditors, but apparently with no intention of indefinitely postponing pay day. The accnmulation of these obligations, however, soon came to be troublesome, and an act of the Legislature bearing date June 8, 1812, recites that by reason of various expenses incurred for improvements in the city of New York, it had been found necessary “ to raise money by bonds under the corporate seal.” To meet the demands produced by these expenses, the ordinary income of the corporation had been found to be “ altogether inadequate,” and as further expenditures were intended, it was set forth that a sum of money would become requisite which they (the Common Council) despaired “ of being able to raise without legislative interference in their behalf.” The Legislature was therefore asked to authorize the funding of the then existing debt, and at the same time to permit making provision for additional expenditures “ by creating a stock not exceeding nine hundred thousand dollars.” A general plea was entered in regard to the desirability of “ establishing the credit of the corporation on a solid basis.” Suffice to say that the desired legislative authority was readily granted, and since 1812 New York has enjoyed the luxury of a funded debt. I shall not seek to conjecture what might have been the effect on the history of the metropolis had the Legislature in 1812 directed the municipal authorities to levy taxes adequate to paying the obligations they had incurred in the name of the city.	s
In considering how the men of that day and the years , immediately suoQOeding established the system of borrow-
ing money for municipal purpose*, to be paid, if at all, at a remote period, we are led to conclude that one main oanae * of the heedlem manner of contracting debt waa the indifference to correct ijatema resulting from the boundless faith in the future of the country, and particularly in the growth of American cities. It appears to hare been thought, so far as any thinking was done, that any thing waa possible , in this country, and that there existed, therefore, little need to learn from the experience of other nations in dealing with schemes of finance. “ What hare we to do with Europe!” whether uttered or* unexpressed, has, at least until recent years, been in a great degree the ruling sentiment of the country. The time has now come to take our bearings anew ; and. so far as is possible, agree upon wise and well-defined lines of action for the future. It will hardly be a matter of surprise if it is found that along f with our asserted disregard of Europe, we hare persistently imitated its discarded errors. -
Concerning the means that hare been employed to secure and render certain a reduction of public indebtedness, we are at once confronted with tlte scheme of finanoe known as a sinking fund, and fchioh has been adopted by the national government, the authorities of various States, and nearly all the important eities of the Union. In the early history of the funding system, when particular taxes, ample for paying in a determinate number of years both the interest and principal of the original loans, were repeatedly mortgaged until it was only with great difficulty that the interest alone could be met, the return of the principals came to be deferred indefinitely. It was then that ingenious minds sought to devise a system of saving, whereby a nation could place an effectual check upon its own prodigality. To this end the plan afterward called a sinking fund was introduced. The impelling motive appears to have been that of national self-distrust, and therefore the State sought to bind itself by artificial and imaginary devices in order to insure an annual saving of revenue for a series of years. The salient feature of the scheme consisted in the purchase by the State of a portion of its out-

I
I
f
j;
. * J
A

standing obligations at regular intervals of time, in the open market. The interest on said purchases were, so to speak, to be paid by the State to itself to swell the fund for additional purchases of stock. The process was to be continued indefinitely, and in this way a fund for the reduction of debt was to be made to accumulate at a compound interest ratio—the fund itself, bear in mind, to consist of re-i deemed portions of the nation's obligations. So far as can 1 be learned, at the inception of the scheme, it was not proposed to make purchases for the fund otherwise than with surplus revenue. A reduction in the rate of interest on the national debt having given the English government * surplus of revenue, it was resolved to apply such surplus to the redemption of debt. To facilitate the work, Sir Robert Walpole, then Chancellor of the Exchequer, adopted in 1717 the machinery of the sinking fund, which had previously been in use on the continent. The nation was enamored with the prospective operation of the fund ; and it was fondly expected that relief would soon be afforded from all financial'difficulties. It is said by Grellier, in his “ His-, tory of the British Debt,” that the false hopes created by the fund had much to do with the origin and growth of • the South Sea Bubble. A slight progress had been made ■ in debt reduction when Walpole found the revenues of the - fund, which he himself had instituted, a much more oon-i f venient means of meeting current expenditures than the imposition of fresh taxes. Adopting this method, the machinery of the fund soon fell into disuse, though it oon-] tinned to have place in the national accounts. This policy was kept up until 1786, when England was struggling under the load of debt which the profligacy of Lord North . had created. The despondency was then so great that almost any scheme promising to give relief would have been hailed with enthusiasm. j It so happened that a few yean previous to 1786, a pamphlet had been published by Dr. Richard Price, the I celebrated expert in financial calculations, in which he deplored in piteous terms the manner in which Walpole’s sinking fund had been allowed to fall into disuse. This
9
was the individual of whom Franklin spoke aa “ the good Dr. Price,” and who, in 1778, was invited by the American Congress to become a citizen of the United States, to assist in regulating the finances of the country. Price had become imbued with wild and exaggerated notions of the effect of compound interest in connection with the operation of a sinking fund. He declared that had Walpole’s fund not been “ premature!j and cruelly destroyed by its own j>arent,” it would have made England (at the date of writing, 1778), not only tax free, but in possession of an enormous surplus. The scheme was regarded as “ a means by which a vast treasure was to be accumulated out of nothing 1” It was the theory of Price that the influence of a sinking fund operating at compound interest was “ omnipotent.” In other words, that the debts of the nation could be wiped out by borrowing money to be used in buying stock through the medium of the fund ; the point being that owing to the magical effect of compound interest, the sinking-fund side of the account would gain so fast as to quickly annihilate any amount of debt. It was confidently declared that war, by increasing the rate of interest, would facilitate the operations of the fund. The most intelligent men in Britain were made to believe that by the working of a sinking fund the public debt might be diminished, notwithstanding the contraction of new loans. *
The calculations of Price were rescued from oblivion by William Pitt, who made them the basis of his afterward famous sinking fund. The machinery of the fund was rehabilitated, and what was thought would prove a surplus revenue of £1,000,000 provided for furthering its operations. Purchases were to be made for the fund quarterly, and as a presumed check against the encroachments of a later ministry, Pitt proposed and put in practice the plan of having Sinking Fund Commissioners. On the morning following the passage of the bill, Pitt received a congratulatory letter from the king, and the operations of the new fund were begun amid the acclamations of the country. The Opposition^ fairly rivalled the ministry in celebrating its * McCulloch on the Funding System, p. 453.
2
praises. The fnnd vu kept up during the entire period of the French war; and although its projectors afterward Oonfewed that its effects had been worse than an absolute nullity, as late as 1807, so great was its hold on the mind of Parliament, the scheme was modified by the introduction «f a system of checks to prevent the evils likely to result from allowing the sinking fund to accumulate without any Hmit, and thus to deluge the country with a flood of wealth £ by a too prompt discharge of the public debt I” * In .818 it was proposed by Vansittart to cease taxation in a great degree for a period of years, and depend upon loans for the conduct of the French war, even to the extent of borrowing for the interest of prior loans, the basis of the Plan being that the sinking fund, sustained by borrowed frioney, would, in the end, balance the account.
The absurdity of longer nursing these delusive dreams began gradually to dawn upon the minds of reasoning men. The worse than folly of borrowing money in the hope of thereby reducing debt was thoroughly exposed by Dr. Hamilton in 1818. He showed conclusively what should live been known before, that the excess of revenue over ex-•enditure constitutes the only efficacious fund by which a public debt can be discharged ; and that all schemes for discharging debt by sinking funds operating at compound interest, or in any manner, unless so far as they are founded on this principle, are illusory, f
Succeeding the French war (it became evident that the groundless confidence in the efficacy of the fund had been one of the main causes of the reckless contraction of debt. During the war the British debt was trebled in amount. By reason of his resorting to loans rather than to fresh taxes, Pitt, according to Mr. Gladstone, was called the “ heaven-born minister.” The portrait of Pitt at Windsor Castle bears upon a scroll held in his hand the words “ reduction of the national debt.” The delusion of the sinking fund received what may be regarded as its death-blow in 1828, when Lord Grenville, who, forty years before, had been
* McCulldbh on the Funding System, p. 465.
f Hamilton on the National Debt, p. 85 . .
11
chairman of the special parliamentary committee whose report was made the basis of Pitt’s sinking fund legislation, published a pamphlet on “ The Supposed Advantages of a. Sinking Fund.” Frankly admitting his sense of former error, Lord Grenville put on reoord the following comprehensive conclusion :
“ To reduoe debt by borrowing to the same amount on terms of equal or greater disadvantage is a manifest fiction in finance—a fiction in that branch of government in which, above all others, fiction is most to be condemned. Its mischief is nothing leas than this : it disguises from the country, and in some degree from the Government and fronr Parliament itself, the real state of some of our most important intereats—throwing over them a false color of progressive improvement in the very moments when the public debt is most rapidly increasing, and when the public revenue has beoome most unequal to its charge. That the British Parliament should at any time have lent itself, and under whatever misconception, to a measure capable of producing these groundless impressions, all men, I think, must bow regret; and who more than those who once participated in that delusion f But when, at last, the fallacy has ceased to deoeive ourselves, it would ill beoome us to impose it upon others. Never again may any just legislature, or any enlightened community, forget that the only surplus from which a nation can with sincerity and truth reduoe its debt, is a surplus accruing, not from loans, but from revenue.”
It has been estimated that the direct loss to the nation on aooount of the expense of conducting the operations of Pitt’s fund was fully £600,000. McCulloch characterised the fund, regarding the part it played in the history of British finance, as “ the grossest delusion by which any civilised people have ever been blinded and deoeived.” In the words of McCulloch, “ so great is the vitality of error, that it was not until 1829 that the triumph of principle and common sense over quackery and folly” was consummated by act of Parliament. The statute of 10 George IV. enacted that thenceforth the sum to be applied to the
I
19
reduction of the debt should be the actual annual surplus of revenue over expenditure. All bonds then in the sinking fund were ordered to be destroyed, and it was further directed that all stock thereafter purchased should be cancelled on the day of transfer. This extended reference to the history of British financiering has been thought necessary in order to bring fully to mind the origin and general character of the scheme which has had much to do with public finance in the United States.
My purpose is to direct attention to the delusive effect of the sinking fund contrivance in municipal finance, (specially as illustrated by the history of Philadelphia’s treasury. It may be observed, however, that the methods pursued by the four principal seaboard cities, New York, Philadelphia, Boston, and Baltimore, are substantially identical, in respect to the office of the sinking fund. The history of Philadelphia’s exchequer is replete with instruction.
1 have already referred to the first considerable loan as having been made in 1799. Other loans followed, and in 1807 the city fathers appear to have advised together touching the need of reducing the debt, as in that year a sinking fund was established. The ordinance of the city Councils instituting the fund, had as a prelude this safe and judicious statement: “ Whereas it is desirable that the reduction and payment of the debt due from this city shall be effected as speedily as circumstances permit.” Pitt’s famous fund tras to prevent the “ inconvenient and dangerous accumulation of debt.” I begin thus early in the history of the city treasury in order to point out the analogy existing between Philadelphia’s methods and the scheme of Pitt, which was erelong to become the laughing-stock of Europe. Recall for a moment that it was in 1807 that checks were provided hy Parliament against a dangerous accumulation of the 1 tad, and consider that the Philadelphia Councils decided 1 i appropriate $5000 annually to secure a reduction of debt, i nd this without seeking to discover whether any surplus revenue existed for Such a purpose. It is perhaps significant that on the veiy day the sinking fund ordinance was
approved there appeared in Paulson's Daily Advertiser, a Philadelphia newspaper, an article from a Liverpool journal, giving an account of the parliamentary system of checks referred to above. The article was entitled “ A New Plan of Finance.” It is plain that the Philadelphia Councils had caught the infection of the English scheme, as almost immediately after $6000 had been appropriated to the fnnd for the reduction of debt, a new loan was authorized for $50,000. The policy here illustrated will serve to indicate the course of the treasury down to 1854, when the old city was consolidated with the outlying built-up districts and the rural portion of the county. It is with the period since 1854 that our narrative has mainly to deal.
At the date named, the debts of the old city and districts were united, and were afterward known as the debt of the consolidated city. The securities in the old sinking funds' were cancelled and a fresh start made. The enlarged city of 1854 received as a legacy a net debt of $16,578,614. The interest centres, however, in the clause of the act of 1854, known as the consolidation act, relating to the creation of new debt. The act directed that no debt should “ be incurred or loan made, .	.	. without a contem-
poraneous appropriation of a sufficient annual income or tax, esoduswe of loans, to pay the interest and sink the principal of such debt in thirty years.” Standing by itself the clause cannot he said to have any definite meaning, the truth being that its precise import was left to be construed from facts and customs outside of the statute.
In 1792 Pitt instituted the plan of providing one per cent sinking funds for all new loans created. Taxes were to be levied for the interest of each new loan, and also for one per cent of the principal to be appropriated yearly to a sinking fund. In the words used at the time, each loan was to be burdened with the seeds of its own destruction. It was calculated that in this way a particular loan would be paid in about forty-five years. By the Philadelphia legislation, it was sought to improve upon Pitt’s plan by requiring that no loan should be created for more than thirty yean, and that a special tax should be levied to
14
insure redemption at maturity. The intention was, it is presumed, to follow out the idea of Thomas Jefferson as set forth in a letter written to John William Eppes in 1813. Jefferson’s notion was that no government has any right to contract a debt for a longer period than the life ef one generation ; also that no money shonld be borrowed on the faith of the public “ without levying a tax, in the same instant, for paying interest annually, and the principal within a given term ; and to consider that tax as pledged to the creditors on the public faith.’* It was apparently conceived by the lawmakers of 1854 that the conditions laid down would act as effective restrictions on the creation of municipal indebtedness. The aim was, should money „be borrowed, to put the city’s exchequer into leading-strings. Reliance was to be placed upon a statute to compel municipal officers, in the event of their creating loans, to save money with which to meet them at maturity. Again, it was'thought that if councils were forced to levy taxes against the maturity of loans, they would hesitate at contracting thpm. Let us see how the scheme has worked. In examining the subject one should keep in mind the simple fact that the principles regulating the financial affaire of a state or city, and those relating to the money drawer of the individual are identical. A neglect of this obvious truth has led to much of the confusion that exists.
It may be further observed that in the event of the creation of a loan, the city was directed to maintain until the loan should mature, a constantly increasing surplus of revenue. It was expected that variable beings would be able to pureue an invariable course ; in other words, that men could do for a city what they are never able to do for themselves. A surplus revenue was to be maintained for three decades, notwithstanding that in the light of history, this period would comprise one or more commercial revulsions at which times it might not be the part of wisdom to tax a community to the extent of providing an excess of revenue. Little did the projectors of such a scheme realize of the difficulties in the way of framing a financial theory which is possible in execution. ~
s
It
All the loan* contracted by Philadelphia ainoe 1854, under the legislation outlined above, beer six per oent interest. It was calculated that an annual appropriation of one and two-tenths per oent on the principal of a given loan, in quarterly payments to a sinking fund, would “ sink the principal in thirty yean.” It may be again noted that Pitt’s scheme was run on the quarterly payment theory. All the loans made by the enlarged dtjJuive been for thirty years, with the exception of a few in am of the gas works, which in Philadelphia are the property of the municipality. In examining the course of the treasury and the state of the debt in relation to the fund, the analysis given will hare reference to the period ending December 81st, 1877.
Consider, then, that a quarter of a century ago Philadelphia set out upon the policy of contracting thirty-year loans for so-called permanent improvements with the inteutiou of levying a tax sufficient to pay a given debt in thirty years, when applied through the medium of a sinking fund. Although debts for permanent improvements might be contracted in particular years, the annual balahoe sheet was to always exhibit a surplus of revenue as compared with the amount required for current expenses. Having begun tov create new debt, the city Councils in 1855 passed a general ordinance establishing a sinking fund, and pledging the faith of the city that the taxes for the fund should be maintained until the final extinction of the debt. Sinking fund Commissioners were provided, and the machinery of the scheme was oomplete.
At the dose of 1877 the consolidated city had contracted new debt to the amount of $55,889,860. Against this principal on December 81st of the year named, the several sinking funds, an independent fund having in theory been maintained for each loan, held $18,758,987 of city securities. On the face of the returns it would appear that since 1864 the city had contracted fifty-five millions of debt, and had saved twelve millions for its redemption. But this is not enough, and we are in duty bound to go behind the returns in older to determine whether the accumulation of savings is real or fictitious. If it can be shown
16
%
that a surplus of revenue in excess of current expenditures has not been uniformly maintained, and that, on the contrary, annual deficiencies have been the rule, we shall have demonstrated that the fund must have resulted from the proceeds of loans, and to that extent is a financial snare. It has been extremely difficult to obtain absolute facts in regard to the course of the city treasury since 1864, owing to the absence of explicit details in the annual reports. A thorough analysis, however, reveals that from 1864 to January 1st, 1861, a period of six years, loans aggregating $1 ,680,498 were incurred to provide for the city’s ordinary expenses, thus revealing an average annual deficit for the years named of $271,749. From 1861 to 1867 the average yearly deficiency was $693,896. It was in 1867 that floating liabilities were last transformed into funded debt. For the decade from 1867 to 1877, taking one year with another, the average annual deficit was $1,046,172. Summing up, it is learned that for the entire period of twenty-three years, ending with 1877, taking one year with another, the average annual deficiency in the ordinary operations of Philadelphia’s treasury was $742,942. Apparent annual surpluses have been accompanied by apparent deficiencies. The deficiency loans of $6,193,877 added to the warrants outstanding on January 1st, 1878, the warrants being the city’s floating debt, give an aggregate debt of $17,087,687, which had no other apology for its existence save the failure to levy and collect sufficient taxes to provide for both the city’s current expenses and the appropriations to the sinking funds.
Here, it should be explained, that floating debt is created in Philadelphia by the device of issuing interest-bearing treasury warrants; or, to be more explicit, appropriations being made by Councils with but little regard to the amount of the tax levy, ordero are drawn by the heads of the various departments on a deficient treasury. These checks or warrants, instead of being paid on presentation, are stamped “ for interest” and registered by the Controller. Nearly $10,000,000 of Philadelphia’s interest-bearing warrants are now outstanding in the hands of banks and individuals.
IT
The plan is not unlike that of England in reapeet to the baaing of exchequer bilk. In Philadelphia the ajatem haa been deluaire and treacherous to the laat degree. The warranta are payable to bearer, and are much sought after by the banka aa a means of temporary investment The specially dangerous phaae of the warrant syatem b the great demand for them by oaaual investors. An unwritten alliance haa thus arisen between the money-lending classes and the establishment. Intelligent men hare oome to believe so great b the influence of the tyrant custom, that it b a wiae and proper function of a municipality to fur-nbh means of investment for the dealers in money and individual capitalists.
The conclusion that b forced upon us b that the taxes ostensibly levied for a sinking fund have, in effect, been diverted to the ordinary expenses of the establishment. Whether consciously or unconsciously, the Councib have managed to make the annual appropriations about equal, taking one year with another, to the total receipts of the treasury, including even the collections from the tax-payers on account of interest on the securities held by the sinking fund commissioners. The yearly deficiencies have had a gradual growth, and a more rigid analyab reveals the very signifi-cant fact that the rate of increase has about kept pace with the growth in the accretions to the suppoeed sinking fund. More light may be gained by a further comparison of figures. The purchases for the fund during the decade from 1867 to 1877, were $10,061,067, and the increase of floating debt for the same period was $10,461,791. What was thb but decreasing the actual sinking fund to something leas than the presumed waving of January 1st, 1868. But as like reasoning will hold good for the years preceding 1867, it should be patent, even to unreflecting minds, what a burlesque the sinking fund of Philadelphia has beau upon honest methods of finance. The sinking fund tax has always been levied and collected ; but at the same time the city Councils uniformly refused to levy additional taxes sufficient for the ordinary expenses of the establishment. It b seen, therefore, that the “ pledge” of the city in 1866
s
18
to levy a sinking fund tax, so long as debt should exist, was % naught save a show of words. An individual may leave incumbrances upon his estates for his heirs to redeem, but he cannot execute an effective guarantee that his successors will be wise and frugal. The attempt to regulate the operations of the city treasury for a series of years by a mathematical formula is now a confessed failure. The finances of a city can no more be controlled by formulas than can those of individuals.
Particular features in the management of Philadelphia’s debt-paying scheme are worthy of attention ; but before referring to them, it may be oliserved that it is essentially absurd to divide up the revenues of a state or city, calling part of them a sinking fund. It is wholly artificial, and simply results in the keeping of two sets of books, so that at times profligate officials are enabled to claim and secure credit for the condition of the sinking fund set, without due attention being given to the forbidding condition of the other side of the account. The state of the fund simply depends on the mode of keejfing the books. In truth, the fund itself is no more than an arrangement of the Accounts. It confuses the reports of a city, so as to perplex and mislead the inquiring tax-payer. To suppose that the fund increases at compound interest is entirely erroneous. To be made to increase at compound interest, money must be put to some productive employment. Any increase in the securities held by the fund must come from the proceeds of taxation.
To speak of “ interest” and “ dividends” in connection therewith, is to attempt a gross deception.
During late years, owing to the high price of the city bonds, the Philadelpliia sinking fund commissioners found difficulty in making their purchases. Resort was i therefore had to the happy plan of purchasing securities for the fund, in the shape of new loans direct from the city treasury. In this way the taxes collected ostensibly to pay old debt go to buy in a new one. The fund is said to be a trust, and the commissioners the trustees ; but owing to the manner of conducting it, as illustrated by the sale of loans direct to the commissioners, and other devices less easily un-

19
derstood, it become* a jugglery, or, better still, thimble-rigging in finance. The custom of creating imaginary loans by selling new bonds to the commissioners, is what Ricardo called “ getting the sinking fund by stealth. ” The result of such a method is to gradually substitute a new debt for the old one ; and in all essential respects, this is the method that has been pursued for yean by Philadelphia. The commissioners hare become trustees to the establishment, and accumulate money for the uses of the machine.
The following facts illustrate how this particular feature of the scheme works: On page 408 of the report of the Philadelphia Sinking Fund Commissioners, for the quarter ending March 81st, 1878, appears the account of “ Sinking Fund of Loan No. 60, for $886,000, approved June 16th, 1876.*' Therein is set forth what purports to be information that on the date first named tlie city had saved against the maturity of this particular loan, the sum of $86,746. But, on making inquiry with regard to the “ investments" of the several funds (keeping in mind that each loan has in theory a corresponding sinking fund), the point is brought out that every dollar of the supposed loan for $836,000 is held by the commissioners, the actual fact being that notone of these 1 »onds was ever in the street. The so-called loan was sold m bloc to the commissionon direct from the treasury. Or, to be more precise, the city, in 1876, being in want of cash, printed its due bills for $886,000, passed these over to the commissioners, who by a convenient fiction are held to be something apart from the city, and then transferred the cash credit for the amount named from the set of books called the sinking fund to the city fund sat, and used the money for city purposes. And yet taxes are levied to meet this imaginary loan. Here is theory run mad. The penalty is such, as must always follow a neglect of Burke's doctrine, that government is simply a matter of practical business.
The tax-payers are deceived in the grossest manner by being led to regard the price of the bonds, the credit of the corporation, as the only proper touchstone of the city’s financial health, and yet during late years the price was in great part sustained by purchasing funded debt at a round
90
premium, with money borrowed by rating other securities at par. The municipal financier* hare pointed with pride to the high price of the bonds as a proof of wise management, regardless of the fact that the bonds might be high with taxation so onerous as to compel trade and industry to flee the city.
The influence of the sinking fund has been pernicious from first to last. It has gone to deceive good men in the city councils. What need, it may be asked, had the officials to be economical, inasmuch as by the fiat of the Legislature, and the foresight of their predecessors, a scheme had been instituted possessing inherent debt-paying energy. We have here a veritable fulfilment of the prediction of Ricardo that a really efficient sinking fund would tend to increase debt and encourage expenditure. The conclusion has been reached that this has been the effect in Philadelphia, not from abstract reasoning, but, instead, by studying the opinions of past and present officials. In this way the conclusion has been abundantly confirmed. As an illustration of the hibits of thought engendered by the scheme, I may mention that recently a prominent Philadelphia official confided to me the fact that he had been making calculations as to the advantages that would accrue from f funding the present floating debt at five rather than at four or four and a half per cent, as in the former case the sinking fund would pay the debt much faster. The fund is constantly referred to as having inherent debt-paying powers, while the simple fact is that it is no more than a particular mode of presenting the accounts. By means of the sinking fund in connection with municipal bookkeeping, it is possible to present false balance sheets, and hold out groundless hopes to tax-payere. Imagine the fate of a court chamberlain who would juggle the accounts to deceive his king, and then decide as to what should be thought of a scheme of finance which enables municipal officers to mislead their sovereign, the people. And yet a powerful sentiment, strange to say, abounds in Philadelphia, that the fund has been the palladium of the city’s credit Is it not clear that in this is revealed the apotheosis
tl
of error then which, According to Bacon nothing is more miechierone.	*
While it wm e false municipal fringe bank, the Phila-delphie fund worked noiselemly and withont friction ; hot recent developments show that to soon as the attempt ie made to conduct an honest fund, one which will really re-dnce debt, the contrivance tends to break down of its own weight. In plain terms, the tendency of making purchases of stock with an actual surplus of revenue, is to bull the bonds and block the game. During the last two yearn several hundred thousand dollars have been paid out in the way of premiums on bonds purchased for the fund. Aa the bonds in question bear six per cent interest, the general decline in the rate of interest has had something to do with the sdvanoe in the prioe of the bonds ; but the oowee of the market has been such as to show that the broken for the sinking fund commissioners cannot avoid putting np the prices of the bonds. Suggestions are freely made that the floating debt, created in the teeth of the sinking fund legislation, shoold be transformed into funded debt, in order to facilitate the operations of the fund. It should be noted that under the sinking fund ordinances, the commissioners are directed to purchase only city bonds. Some of tlie loan ordinances actually, include a proviso, which, it is asserted, is a part of the contract, that the investments for the accompanying sinking fund shall be oonflned to the securities of the said loan, thus in effect agreeing to buy back tho bonds before maturity, and, of ooorae, on the holders’ terms. Like true profligates, the Philadelphia official! were willing to sign any thing. Such bungling shows how tyros in finance have bean allowed to manage the affaire of great cities. It also serves to illustrate the pernicious effect of the peculiar American doctrine that all men are equally fitted for the assumption of any public doty ; that special training is neither here nor there. One of the moat surprising things is the way in which men, who would quickly confess their unfitness for other lines of endeavor, will heaitate at nothing in the field of finanoe.
It may be said that had it not been for the sinking fund
22
contrivance the outstanding debt of Philadelphia would now be increased by the securities held by the fund, and that the floating debt would exist just the same. This view is entirely erroneous. The Council would not have ventured to create alisolute deficiencies for ordinary expenses. Councilmen, acting under the knowledge that the sinking fund tax would offset the apparent deficiency, made appropriations for every dollar in sight. The machinery of the fund enabled the officials to levy a tax under a false pretense.
During 1878, owing to the menace of the enormous floating debt, the course of Philadelphia’s treasury resulted in a surplus of some $800,000, which went to the reduction of the floating debt, this surplus being in excess of the appropriations to the sinking fund. The budget for 1879, however, gives no reason to anticipate a further reduction of the floating debt for the year. The clumsy working of the sinking fund machinery as soon as an attempt is made to apply an actual surplus to the reduction of debt, gives abundant proof of the absurdity of supposing that a municipal debt can l>e speedily redeemed by making purchases for a sinking fund in the open market. In truth, no practical proof should be needed ; the proposition is absurd and ridiculous on its face, and had not the public men of the U nited States, in the early part of the century, been dazed by the imaginings of Pitt and his compeers, the scheme would never have found a lodgment in this country.
I find that the sinking fund of New York city dates from 1813, the year following the inception of the funded debt proper. The scheme had its origin in a report made to Common Council on April 19th of the year named, by Thomas R. Marcein, Comptroller. To use his own words, he had applied himself since his appointment, “ to the consideration of a plan for the gradual extinction of the funded debt.” As though debt could be extinguished in some ingenious manner otherwise than by providing a surplus of revenue I The city then owed in round numbers $700,000, which was to fall due December 31st, 1826. Mr. Marcein had figured out that by applying the revenues from the sale of certain real estate, the income from city property, etc.,
23
to the purchase of stock through the medium of a sinking fund, there would be paid $400,000 of the then existing debt at its maturity in 1826, leaving $800,000 unredeemed. It was proposed to secure an extension for this amount for ten or twelve years, the theory being that in this time the sinking fund would extinguish the whole debt. It does not appear that any calculations were presented, going to show that a surplus of revenue could be maintained. In fact, from all I can glean, no reference whatever was made to the necessity of an excess of revenue over expenditure, in order to insure a reduction of debt. Comptroller Marcein, in his report, suggested the appointment of Sinking Fund Commissioners, and said : “ In order to facilitate the operations of the Commissioners, they may be permitted to have a credit with the city treasurer (when in funds) for the amount of their quarterly revenue, and thus by antici]>ating their own quarterly payments and being at all times prepared to make advantageous purchases of city stock, whenever it was offered for sale, they will render the fund more certain and productive.”
On July 2d, the Finance Committee of Common Council reported that after giving to the comptroller’s “ valuable report” serious consideration, they were prepared to “ recommend the adoption of a system for the gradual extinction of the city debt.” The report was signed by R. H. Lawrence, Peter Mesier, James Palmer, and John Nitchie. DeWitt Clinton was then mayor of New York. The report was favorably considered by the Common Council, and on the 18th of the following August a sinking-fund ordinance was adopted. The ordinance recited that it was highly desirable to establish a fund out of which purchases of the New York city stock may be made from time to time, whenever the same can be done at par, or the true value thereof ; whereby the said stock will be prevented from depreciating, and the redemption of the same will be regularly progressing. Therefore it was resolved that certain moneys “ shall constitute and form the fund for the purpose aforesaid, until the final redemption of the whole of said stock.” The Mayor, the Comptroller, and other
i

24
officials were named as sinking fnnd commissioners, after the idea of Pitt, and the scheme was well on its feet. ' So great was the confidence in its efficacy as a debt-extinguisher that the financiers for the dty speedily entered upon the creation of new loans.
In 1844 the sinking-fund ordinance was revised and reenacted in order to “ establish a permanent policy in the management and sale of the property of the city pledged” to the fnnd. The new legislation set forth that “ the object to which the sinking fund was to be devoted was twofold—the liquidation of the principal and payment of the interest as it accrued.” The revenues of the fund were sacredly pledged to the payment of interest and principal “ until the whole of the stocks of the city of New York shall be finally and fully redeemed.”
It is not necessary to trace minutely the course of New York’s treasury, as, taking one year with another since the sinking fund ordinance of 1818, the couree of events has not materially varied. Always that will-o’-the-wisp known as de)>t reduction exists only in the future, and always the wonder-working sinking fund has been the reliance of both officials and tax-payers, and all have leaned upon a broken reed. The worse than egregious folly of seeking to redeem prior debt in the open market while constantly creating other loans, appears not to have occurred to those having most to do with the management of New York’s finances from 1813 until now.
In the creation of New York’s funded debt, it has been the custom to provide that certain portions of it were to be paid from the sinking fund while other loans were payable from taxation. The distinction is more apparent than real, as every one who will take trouble to think for a moment can see, that, as was remarked touching Philadelphia’s jugglery, the fund is no more than a peculiar and compli- . cated system of book-keeping. It appears that in 1877 the securities belonging to the fund were largely in excess of the bonds, for the payment of which the fund was pledged by law. This condition of affaire prompted the Comptroller to secure the passage of an act at Albany “ pledg-
Jj
35
ing” the fond to the payment of the entire funded debt of the city. The discussion* that have taken place concerning this act, passed in 1878, go to show how slight is the knowledge of the public with regard to the real operations of the city treasury, and the significance of its tender the sinking fund. The Comptroller in his report for the year ending August 1st, 1877, referring to the so-called surplus in the fund, said : “ This surplus could be applied to bonds payable from taxation, and thus provide for the payment of the whole funded debt. ... It has been estimated, indeed, that if the sinking fund is not disturbed, but is applied also to the redemption of that part of the city debt now payable from taxation, and the debt itself is not increased by special legislation beyond the amount now authorized by law, the sinking fund, with its present revenues, will alone provide for the extinction of the debt, without resort to direct taxation for the payment of the principal of the funded debt. ” The confidence with which the Comptroller speaks of paying debt without resortiqg to taxation, prompts a query as to where the money is to oome from if not from taxation ; the fact that a portion of the city taxes are labelled “ sinking fund” does not conceal the fiction offered in referring to them as “ revenue” with the purpose of creating an impression that by some hocus-pocus relief is granted to the tax-payev. Surely the keeping of an extra set of books called a sinking fund, has no power to lessen the number of dollars to be demanded in the tax levy. It has been well said that a complicated system may confuse and mystify, but it can never ameliorate.
• The new law of 1878 relating to the funded debt of New York provides that whenever any new loans are negotiated, there shall be included in the annual tax levy from year to year a sum sufficient, with the accumulation of interest thereon, to redeem the said bonds at maturity. This plan is identical with the Pennsylvania legislation of 1854, which we have been considering, and whose operation has been so disastrous. The memorial of the Mayor, Aldermen, and Commonalty, which was sent to Albany in relation to this feature of the measure, recites that it ** is a very impor-4
96
tant and necessary provision to restrict the issue of bonds and prevent the increase of the city debt.” The blind confidence manifested in a legislative device, which has been tried in Philadelphia for a quarter of a century, and found wanting, shows that New York’s exchequer is in need of scientific treatment.	•	♦
I have been informed by those in authority that in conducting the operations of New York’s sinking fund, it has not been found necessary of late to buy bonds in the open market, for the reason that it has been more convenient to make transfers of new bonds direct from the treasury. In	/
fact, the commissioners of the fund have not to any extent bought in the market old bonds of the city since about 1865.
During all of the fourteen years the accretions to the fund have been entirely made up of new issues of bonds. In other words, the portion of the taxes called a sinking fund h$yQ been turned over to the establishment from year to year, in exchange for freshly executed due bills. It is thus seen that, judging the future by the past, and we have no other guide, the fund will continue to increase by the system'of direct transfers without at all decreasing the debt now outstanding. A convenient means of “ investment” for the	*
New York sinking fund is found in the revenue bonds issued in anticipation of yearly taxes.
Regarding the possibility of stopping further debt-making by any large city that has once become familiar with the allurements of public credit, a page from the history of *. Boston’s treasury is instructive. Notwithstanding that the Boston officials decided, in 1898, to avoid creation of a funded debt, they soon after eidbarked in the business, and by 1897 they had incurred debt to the amount of $1,000,000. Early in 1897, when discussing the debt qnes- * tiou, Mayor Quincy said : “ Looking forward to the duties of the coming year, it is a subject of congratulation that the foresight and enterprise of past years have limited to a comparatively narrow sphere the necessity of future expenditures.” This in 1897, while at this time the city of U Boston is borrowing millions of dollars for the construction of sewers.
-I
87
The experience of Philadelphia doubtless affords the most conspicuous and instructive illustration of the utter failure of State legislation, to regulate the use of credit by a municipality. The sinking-fund legislation of 1864 was simply an attempt to regxdaU the borrowing power. The whole history of debt-making by American cities goes to prove that it is madness to suppose that the borrowing business can be satisfactorily regulated. The only efficient regulation is absolute prohibition. *On this point I am supported by no leas an authority than Mr. Charles O'Conor. In 1878, when he was fresh from a study of municipal borrowing and its results, as illustrated by the operations of the Tweed ring, Mr. O’Conor, in his letter to the Louisville convention, put on record the following opinion :
“ The power of borrowing money on public credit, either on paper issues or otherwise, should be absolutely annulled. Neither the Federal Government, nor any other down to the smallest civil division of a State, should possess it; it is inconsistent with the prosperity of free republican institutions. It is the very life-blood of aristocratic rule, for it fetters labor *s the bond slave of capital .	.	. Pay as you go is a maxim not less sound in political eoonomy than in private affairs. .	.	. The power
to borrow money is mischievous just in proportion as government is liberal in form and as the nation is prosperous. The very constitution of human nature precludes any effectual regulation of it. In a monarchy there may be some support, but in a republic the tendency to abuse is absolutely incorrigible. No human skill can devise or human diligence put in force adequate checks upon its exercise. If allowed to exist at all it must inevitably be abused, and the abuse must progress to an extent absolutely intolerable. The mere burden of taxation induced by it is the least evil among its foul progeny. Fraud and corruption become virtues under its influence: statues to be set up as objects of popular reverence, and similar honors have been proposed for its cultivators, and, if it be not extirpated, will hereafter be decreed to them.”
The events of the years that have elapsed since the
38

above w« written bnt go to confirm the soundness of the judgment. The attempt in Pennsylvania to regulate municipal borrowing by constitutional restrictions is an acknowledged failure. The debt of Philadelphia has been increased in the teeth of the constitution, and in the interior of the State assessed valuations have been multiplied in order to give opportunity for fresh issues of debt.
I am not of those who would charge the average voter with responsibility for the existence of the enormous municipal debts. Iiather should it be said that the influence of the funding principle has been to induce voters to relax their vigilance at the ballot box. The character of municipal officers has been lowered in consequence of the fact that almost any sort of officials can conduct a city government on the credit system, so long as their drafts on the tax-]>ayers continue to be honored. The veriest prodigal would meet with no trouble if some Fortunatus would but look after the maturity of his paper. The fault lies more with the property-owners than with the rabble, that debts have beea incurred recklessly. Property-holders in municipalities most need to be protected from themselves. I am convinced that the only efficient protection will be found in a constitutional prohibition of debt-making. The citizen of a municipality, under a representative government, unlike the citizen of a State, has but one incentive to vigilance at the ballot box, namely, the jear of taxation. Remove this by borrowing for “ posterity” to pay, and that moment representative government in cities is a failure.
It may be said that so-called permanent improvements could not be carried on except by the aid of loans. This is the original and radical error from which a baleful progeny have sprung. Before the city assumed the task of supplying drainage facilities, water and gas to the people, individuals looked after these necessities, each in his own way. The work in the large cities has devolved upon the corporation, owing to the need of securing uniformity of method. It never logically proceeded from this, however, that the money required should be borrowed for all th6 contributors to the common fund. It would have been
99
quite m consistent if the city, arrogating to iteelf the prerogatives of a State, had volunteered, while the work waa carried on by individuals, to aid them with money and materials. A city should no more borrow money to build a sewer or lay a water-pipe in front of the taxpayer's dwelling than the city in embryo—the village—should do the same thing to aid the householder in digging a well or a ditch. Every successive year has its own burdens, and the only true system is to make each year take care of itself. The taxpayers of a municipality should contribute directly whatever funds are needed, no matter what may be the purpose of the expenditure. Such of them as would be obliged to borrow for extraordinary expenditures could obtain the money on better terms, were the city not a bidder in the money market. On no well-founded theory of government should an American municipality oontinue to be entrusted with the attribute called credit. I am convinced that the sooner this principle generally accepted and acted on, the better will it be for the moral and material welfare of the entire country. Mr. O’Conor further says : " However true it may be in a certain view of matters that all taxes are ultimately borne by ]the laboring classes, they are nevertheless in the' first instance collected from those who possess property ; and if by uniform usage every dollar required for expenses of the Government should be at once exacted from the tax payers, a powerful class would be enlisted in the duty of guarding against official extravagance. Government mortgages upon labor, the most safe and desirable of investments, would cease, and in their place affrighted capitalists could contemplate only the approaching tax-gatherer. In self-defence they would then perform a public duty hitherto neglected. Legislative corruption would be effectually opposed. Under their keen scrutiny no man whose record was tainted could pass the ordeal of election."
Ill-conceived attempts to reduce municipal indebtedness, while the interest burdens were already greater than could well be endured have, in some degree, been the immediate cause of the embarrassments that have overtaken various American cities. The mistake is in seeking by ex- *
#
80
centre taxation to reduce debt rapidly at this juncture. No new debts should he incurred in any manner or for any purpose. American cities should be confined to an exclusively cash basis. To diminish the present burdens, the most efficient sinking fund for a city is such a policy as will contribute to an increase of its prosperity and productive energy. As debt and taxation can scarcely be reduced at the same time, the first aim should be to lessen the latter, and thereby lighten the debt burden by developing the city Ja industry and commerce.
a
/