h
TON ' NE
B V '	i	N
ON	■	A
§4-	,	4
;ir*' *'
mtwf*

Wb , It fs;
i i
How b . w->:-L
4 b-
PUBLISHED BY H. FRANKLIN FORD, 7i BROADWAY,
NEW YORK.
h
9
The Value an overpay
meut and ' recognized hy law and PT,Qctice.
Tontine
ConflncatCHi
I lie value.
Ton tine wit'i holds the dividends.
Large results predicted from confiscated over-payments.
Explanation of a rate.
being increased as lie grows older
more than the risk is worth- ah firsthand this overpayment
forms the value .oi the policy, or

■*
Consequently lie pays
what is usually known as
mness or necessity fails to y then the policy shall, be whole value lost to the
period the policy-holder by care 1 < make payment on the day it is du<
forfeited to the company and its; in surer. We quote the clause from; a Tontine policy:
That previous to the completion of its Tontine dividend period, this policy can have no star-render value in cash or in paid-up policy.” v	'
Its total value is confiscated to the company. The insurer can receive not one cent whether; ill cash or paid-u^) policy. Tontine also provides that all dividends shall be retained during the Tontine period by the company, and that the insured shall pay the full premium in cash. The agreement says :	”	^
“ That no dividends shall be; allowed or paid upon this policy unless the person whose life is hereby assured shall survive the completion of its Tontine;.dividend period as aforesaid, and unless this policy shall then be in force.1’
The insured agrees to forego all the usual dividends. Tontine promises, however, that at the end of the Tontine period the accumulations from lapsed policies; and from dividends retained by the company shall be divided among the survivors
* The ordinary life rate on $1,000 at age twenty-five is $19.89.” The real cost of insuring $1,000 for one year at age twenty-five, adding a reasonable amount for expenses, is $10.86 ; at age thirty it is $11.34; at age thirty-five at age forty-five it is $15.03 ; at age fifty it is $18.55 ;; a|t age fifty-five it is $25.00; at age sixty it is $35.92 ; at ;age sixty-five ifctis $51.09 ; and so on	ulliety	flVlTTC	is	$1,000,	less
the interest for one.year. The mathematical average of
1
the reserve. It Belongs to the man who paid it just as much
as any other article does which a man' lias paid for.. His ownership of this overpayment is recognized by the laws of Massachusetts, New York and most other States, and by the practice of the best companies. It is, the confiscation of this value of the policy, this overpayment, made as a matter of convene'nee to secure, an even rath, rather than a constantly increa-4 - . one, which forms the principal element in Tontine.
A life-policy issued at age 25 for I $10,000 has, at the end of the iiist year, a value or reserve! of $67.70; at the end of five years the value is $665:90 ; fit the end of ten years, $808.20 ; at the end of fifteen yeaijs, $1,839.10 ; at the end of twenty years, $1,968.70; at the lend of twenty-five years, $2,700.50 ; at the end of thirty years it is $3,517.50; at the end of thirty-five years it is $4,391.40 ; I at the end of forty years it is $5,284.90 ; and this value constantly increases until at age 96 it would' be $10,000. These accumulations or reserves Tontine confiscates if the policy is forfeited as it generally is ^ in Tontine companies.	i
The Tontine policy provides that if during the Tontine
%
'i
<
A

8
/•
of the period. On the supposition that a large number of ■ ■ lapses will occur, large results are predicted by'the companies . and their agents, and the insured are made*.-to4 believe that-v; o . they will reap enormous profits.
There are two points to be considered by every one before Jp' P^jte making a Tontine contract. The first is that if lie fails to c make his payment for any cause, either inability, carelessness,, or misunderstanding, or .even the dishonesty of an agent, the entire value of the policy is gone as far as he is concerned. By < the agreement it is confiscated to-the company, and it is to, the company’s interest to confiscate it. This is the terrible evil growing out of Tontine. It is a risk too great to be run by any one, no matter what Ids circumstances.' The second i point to 'considered is the probable amount of profit in case of success. Under this head it \vill be shown later that the dividends in leading companies, which do not practicej Tontine, and which have none of -the--.dangers and evils ole Touting about them, are fully equal fo and sometimes in excess1 of the |Contine dividends. We shall also show the'reason why this is [so, and that risk of losing tine entire' policy is taken I>yt"" the inspired, without even a gambler’s hope of extraordinary gains ifi case 'he wins.
As the great danger and great evil of. Tontine lies/in robbing conim-a the injured of large amounts which beJ^fhA to them, we shall fit’s t give numerous examjples of the experience of those Ton!a!H‘ who have tried Tontine and failed to get through tin* period,
■with - the various reasons why they failed, and the a mounts sacrificed in the trial.
ition.
< it , d
I ’ . HM’i U1H
<* ixr. of > (-'ilir-o.
VXoim'bk
niimimt ,o)’ pi'ollt.
I ion the nnWjCvil of
Mr. Patrick. Donalioe, the well-known puhlislier of the Boston Pilot, at one time carried a large amount of Tontine insurance in the companies referred to, but through adverse circumstances -was compelled to lose the entire amount lie had paid, amounting to some thousands of dollars. He could not recover a cent, and says that it is the most unsatisfactory insurance lie has ever had ; lie strongly advises every one to .Jiave nothing to do with it. v .
_ Mr. Dennis Shea, of Portsmouth, N. H., took Policy .No. f79,846 in the Equitable on the Tontine plan in 1873. He paid $50.67 twice a 3 ear for six years, or $60$.04 in all. The last two payments were made to the same agent who had always received them g blit the-.- .agent used them himself, proved a defaulter, and the policy was declared forfeited. This was tlirougjp-no fault or inability of tlie insured. Because he did hot get 611 a train and go to New York with his money, lie lost ,Jiis entire policy and could not recover a cent. *
A gentleman in Baltimore, who desires that his name shall be withheld, paid the premiums on a $10,000 Tontine for some years and then lost the policy through a misunderstanding
The riio-'t, in.8 tl.i^factory insurance.
Tontine policy lost by ■ dishonesty of
airent.
Did not understand the “ days of grace.”
The word of n man and a irmsnn ajmlied to Tontine.
Tontine
Conipnny
unsworn
letter after four
mom Its
Disgraceful
transaction,
$2,817 lost by misunderstanding.
A costly experience.
of die “ days of grace,” and tlie misunderstanding was shared by the agent. But the company would make no concession; they had a contract for the money;and they kept it.
Mr. Alfred Hill, formerly of Chicago, 111., but now of Vermillion, Ks., carried No. 98,723 on the Tontine plan for some years in the New York Life. He lost tlie policy and all he had paid on it—-some hundreds of dollars—in the following manner Alt seems that Mr. Hill and the Company’s agent, Mr. O.hP. Curran, were personal friends, and Curran owed Hill money enough on a note to paV the premium, and promised to pay the premium due January 10,1880, as Mr. Hill was removing from ■ Chicago. But lie did not do so, and the policy was forfeited, tlie Company retaining the money. On February 10,1880, Mr. Hill wrote the Company as follows: “I had told the manager X would let the debt run
i
to meet my premium. On July 1, 1879, I saw Curran, who assured me upon the word of a man and n mason and all that, that he would attend to my policy and let nothing happen to it, and if, perchahce, anything should happen, whereby lie could nob pay it all before the time expired, he would make the policy jpayable (quarterly, then he would be sure to take care of it, and pay tlie difference. So I signed
in case he should want to Company did not reply to
papers to that effect then and there, use them at tlie last moment.” The this letter until June 8, 1880, four months after it was received, probably waiting for the “days of grace” to expire, and then told him the policy with which he had struggled so hard was forfeited, and that he had better suc| Curran for the note he could not recover a cent. A moi’b distressing ..transaction could hardly be recorded. " But it forms a part'of Tontine history,, and is but an illustration ofj the whole scheme. Mr. Hill will, certainly never trust eitheii the man, the plan, or the company again.	[	v
Mr. David Mettauer, of Chicago, 111., took policy No. 92,070 in the Equitable, on the Tontine plan, for $25,000. He paid four years, the animal premium being $704.25, he not knowing anything about the dangerous conditions contained in his policy. When these were shown him he thought it best to abandon the policy and lose $2,817, rather than risk losing a much greater amount later in the ^ period. Mr. M. at once took an insurance in one of the leading companies on an honest plan.	!
hifr. A. B. Boss, of No. 54 Broad) street, New York City, took a policy of $10,000 in the Equitable in ' 1870. He paid three premiums of $478.20, or $1,434 60 in all, and then f?.’led to pay. It was a costly experience, and) he will never try it again.
■ Mr.. .Robert C. Buchan, of No. 126 West Twelfth street, New. York, says that lie took No. 66,^39, on the Tontine plan,
1-
4
4


A
A
A
for $10,000, in the Equitable., id 1872. He paid 'quarterly. Twenty instalments until sometime in 1878, when lie was notified by ter.
11 Tried I o
n t: I kc romo arra menu')]	1
four q. ar-ter.y pi <■-.
the company that the policy had lapsed by non-payment of the premium. Inquiries'showed that the last two premiums dishonest which he had sent the company’s agent, Mad not been paid agy ' over. . He had paid about $1,500 to find out that Tontine is a ■ very unsafe plan. This is'another case where premiums hail been faithfully paid, nevertheless he could not recover a cent.
Mr. M. A. Hamilton, of No. 84 Elizabeth street, Detroit,-Mich., says: “ Several'■ years ago I took a Tontine policy in agreed.' the Equitable, New York, for $10,000. The Detroit agent did not do as he agreed, and on application to the company, they referred me back to the agent. I then gave up the thing.”
It was not Mr. Hamilton’s fault, but what was that to the / company? His bond was forfeit, and the company took the I pound of flesh.
Mr. Henry A. Sage is the president of the Easton, Pa. horse railroad. He paid a large amount of money to tin: Equitable on three Tontine policies of $10,000 each. Ha.vi.ng failed to continue payment of premiums, lie “ tried to make some!arrangement ” with the company.. Of c<i/urse they would not (|o it, and he could not recover a cent. IHe now regrets that he was coaxed into so costly and ilbisory\i plan.
Yfr. A. Howard Clark, of New York, says: 44 1 took out a Codiv nmi Tontjne policy several yeaiy ago in the Eqnyfcdde, which I pilC lv<' was |(>mpelled to stop payment on, and upon application to the company found I had no! redress.” Mr. (lark found out the company had all the money lie could raise, and that they had a contract allowing them to keep:it. They will keep just as much more as they can get their' hands on under similar contracts.
Mr. John Johnston, of No. 119 Langley avenue, Chicago, squeezed 111., had a very sad experience with the Equitable. He paid pay/nl01 them, lie says, $3,850, and got nothing for it. It was on a Tontine policy issued in 1872 for $20,000. He struggled
through' eleven semi-annual payments of $350.80 each, and then! was compelled to abandon his policy and lose thenenti.ro amount. It was a good thing for the company, but anything else for Mr. Johnston.
Mr. E. J. Anspach, of No. 134 South Third street, Phil a- Sacrifices delphia, took a ten thousand dollar policy'on the Tontine policy; plan,1 in the Equitable, in 1873., He paid on the'whole of it for s6me years, when circumstances compelled him to stop hair” payment on $5,000, for which he could not get a cent. He still clings to the other $5,000, but. says he is tired of it. But undoubtedly that is whakthe company wants and it is • what he bargained for. The company w ould be so much the richer if he would abandon the remaining $5,000.
“ Adversity in business,”
A bad
aKent.
To.) 11i11 a
juice.
Bad invest ■iiienl, and no return.
Mr. Ilatt’H experience.
Compelled
to take Tontine to
secure a loan.
Equitable gotthe money, and Mr. Ward got the experience.
Mr. John T. Cummings, of No., 2 N-.fClark street, Chicago, ■111., through adversity in business” lMt with the Equitable $285 on a Tontine policy for $5,000 on which he paid $95 a year for'three years. He says''the company “ would not wait for me.” Why should they ? 'They had the money as they had expected to have when Mr. Cummings insured.
Mr. Geo. W. Hay, of No. 618 Chestnut street, Philadelphia, Pa., abandoned a policy of $5,060 Tontine about a year ago, because lie could not keep the payments up. He says that the agent promises that if he will pass an examination at any time within two years, and pay six months’ back premium, he can reinstate his policy. He misunderstood flie agent or else the agent lied. The company lias the money, and Mr. Hay will never get one cent of it.	r
k Mr. I), Cornwell, of No. 699 Second avenue, New York, paid $11.8.50 to the Equitable on a Tontine policy, and failed to pay the;third premium. It cost himi$227to find out that Tontine is not desirable when one is trying to get protection for his family.
Mas A. 11. 8!iattack, writing jfrom Grand Rapids, Mich., says that he lias paid the New York .Life $838.80 oil a Tontine investment policy of $5,000 in twenty-four quarterly premiums. He made his last payment September 13, 1879. His policy was what was called a Tontine divestment policy. It proved a very bad investment, for it cost a fearful price and yielded
no return.	■	:	j
Mr. Samuel Hatt, of Montreal, Canada, had three policies on the Tontine plan in the Netv York Life, amounting to $10,000. He says lie paid the; company $1,680, and was obliged to drop the policy. Of course he is very sorry that he tried Tontine, as thousands of. others,are, and thousands more will be, unless they profit by experiences similar to Mr.
Halt’s.
Mr. Wm. S. Bayles, of No. 157 Bloomfield street, Hoboken, N. J., has had some experience ini Tontine life insurance. He wanted to borrow some money from the Equitable, and took a policy in order to do so. * Tontine was suggested of course. It was for $5,000, and' issued in 1874.	“	Owing	to
reverses in circumstances,” he was obliged in 1878 to abandon the policy, after paying four years and three months premiums, amounting to $424.20. Mr. Bayles was just the man for tlie company to insure on a Tontine policy, for he was in straightened circumstances when lie took the policy, and was not expected to carry it to the end.
Mr. E. G. Ward, -of No. 461 Macon street, Brooklyn, paid eleven quarterly premiums on a Tontine policy for $5,000 in the Equitable. He £* neglected ” to pay the twelfth until it was too late, and he was out to the extent of $372.35. The company got the money and Mr. Ward the experience.
5
4
4
4
4
4
4
4
4
4
1
<
y
h
.K
t ■ >►
in the Equitable, half years, paying more ;■ lie would some of the all, and lie •will
to pay a commission to get Tontine money back.
get
Chicago, then Equit-
imaginable.
Equ i table makes $1,200, and hunting for, more.
Mr. W. H. Carroll, of Chicago, Ills., had a very deplorable. and expensive experience with the New York Life. "With:much, promises of large profits he was induced to take $20,000 in . two policies. Heepaid the premiums quarterly for seven,'. , ■ years and nine months, and then failing to pay a quarterly installment lost his policy, and learned that it is very unprofit- .. able to try Tontine. It cost him over $2,000 to learn it. It cost him $2,000 too much, for airy honest man who is posted . would have told him better- for nothing.
Mr. Thomas W.| Hungerford, of 1213 Pennsylvania avenue, wouid Hkn 'Washington, I). (1, took policy No, 76,262 on the Tontine plan.; He paid two and oru $292.50’in all. Then he failed to pay an.} like to pay a commission to some one to money back ; but the company will keep it have (to charge it off against his information.
Mri W. S. fJacksbn, of No. 94 Washington street, paid the Equitable some $1,200 on a $10,000 Ton tine, am abandoned it. He won’t try Tontine again. But the able ib-hunting for those who will, by all tire arts
Albert Ealk, of New, York, does n<>t like Tontine. He should has t^ied it. He took a policy in the New York Life, and paid better;nowa from IL875 to 1879, in all, $2,*1}03, and could then pay no more.
He says that he pleaded witli the company for some arrangement by which he could save some of his money, but without success. He should have known better than to take the policy in the first place, ot to plead with the company at all.
They merely took what they had a contract for.
Dr. Joseph Mixwell, of Easton, Pa., kept a $5,000 Tontine FaiIedJ° in force in the New York Life for five years, paying $510. He Sixth pay-failed to make the sixth payment with the usual result.	ment
Mr. John Siders, of Chambersburg, Pa., had a Tontine Looked policy for $3,000 in the New York Life, on which he made four payments of $86.26, or $345.04 in all. The investment looked very tempting when he took the policy, but he does not think so now.	/
Mr. J. D. Peet, a cotton broker, of No. M" Carondelet a graphic
*	  #	*	/	descrintioii
street, New Orleans, had a Tontine dividend-policy, Class A. , of the start. No. 60,795, premium $68.10, date of policy, April 15, 1871.
The Equitable made about $200 out of it. )
Mr. E. Tucker writes from Yonkers, New York, that lie is a a pool carried $50,000 Tontine \ in the Equitable_ for four or five years, paying about $1,700 per year. Being unable to continue it, he says he was tacitated by a proposition from the company to pay the beneficiary $2,400 and cancel the policy. If the policy was a Tontine policy, as Mr. Tucker says, then the company could not pay anything for its surrender, and did not. It was a valuable policy, because large
of the managers ?
I
payments had been made on it, fand it-was nearly through its period. It is not improbable, however, that, some one havirg knowledge of its value purchased it by assignment. It is not :a new feature in Tontine for persons having private means of information to bny np valuable policies, but their secrets are closoly guarded. The whole Tontine scheme is bad enough, but this part of it is worse than: the scheme itself.
Mr. Walter De F. Smillie, of j Montreal, had,- No. 65,051 in years ° 1 the "Equitable on the Tontine I plan/ He paid about eight years, and failing to pay a premium when it was due, lost the .entire amount.
Tho 3--nr, of
Inability, dn-hojOy v
‘i'V.rpl ion,
('tuU'-' -
IH’H-, 'll ^ IIP,',.
111LT.
Hundreds of such. examples; could be given. Thbre are thousands of them in the country. It is not one reason alone which has caused, this large number of Tontine policy-holders who were trying to throw protection around their families, to !<>sr all they invested in Tontine. Tailuredn business and inability to pay is, of course, the great cause. But carelessness, misunderstanding of tlie contract, dishonesty of the agent, and ' anger at deception are additional reasons. Any one of them is liable to deprive a, man of a Tontine policy if lie has one.
It is sale to say that not one man who has tried Tontine and /failed, will ever try it again. Tbntine is a mere bet in which a man bets that he will be a bib to pay a given sum of money for a gi ven number of years, that he will not forget to pay his premiums on time, that- the agent won’t steal them. If he gains his bet, we shall see that lie gains nothing beyond what legitimate insurance would give him. If he loses, he loses everything except the experience which will teach him never
Tontine worn* than horse racing or the gamblers table.
An attempt to take another man’s money for nothing.
to make that bet again. If a man bets on a horse race, or at tins gaming tableland loses, he is very likely to try it again when he gets some more money, unless he reforms fiis morals. But no man will try Tontine the second time if he has once lost at it. He has learned the chances' against him far too well for that.
Tontine, we say, is a bet that the insured will not for any reason, whether failure in business or carelessness or fraud of an agent, fail to pay his premium for a period of ten, fifteen or twenty years. Like all b§ts it is an attempt to take other people’s money for nothing, on the turn of an. unknown contingency. In ordinary life insurance the value of a man’s policy is derived solely from what he has himself paid in. Neither more or less. It is, on the other hand, the theory of Tontine, if managed with perfect scrupulosity by the company, that the insured gets bade at the end of the period the value of what he has paid, and also of all that, such other people have paid as may chance to be unable or forget to keep up their premiums. All the extra profits must come by dividing up the money of unfortunate people1 who have been persuaded to
'J
y
make tlie bet and have lost. The popr people, the people who have failed in business,'the people who most need Cm uch man ■
J	X ■ i~	_	_	_	_	„	-B	rm	A
aurl the
man,
cw can go fh'ough a ■I'ont inc
money they have put into insurance, they lose it all, and po!)r those who need it least, divide up what They have robbed {J| their unlucky neighbors of. Tontine urges people to, make man makes this cruel, immoral robber’s bet. It incites to robbery of theJ^Tthf’ poor. Tontine is a panel thief; stealing a man’s money andj^man cheating him out of the fruits of his immoral bargain at the 'tbing.cvcry same time. It is to its interest to have as many as possible of the weak holders of insurance fall off after paying all they can, so that there may be more to divide among the few that are left. Is it to be presumed that thus inciting to robbery, holding the victims to be robbed, it will not itself keep as much of the plunder as possible, and divide as little as possible among those who hold out ? We shall see as we Proceed what the chances are against the insured continuing their payments through the Tontine period, and also what is the success of those who do so continue.
_Ap long ago as 1810 General Henry S. Dearborn, who was f for twenty years Collector of the Port of .Boston, made th state inent that from a close observation of business men, he i was satisfied that not more than three out of every hundred individuals who embark in trade are successful. In 1847 Mr.
Nalixim Capen, editor of the Massachussetts Stale Record, sent out circulars to;every town i|i the commonweal!^! for the purpose ;,of collecting information as to the number wlio fail in business. Summarizing the information tjxts obtained, Mr.
Capen, in a letter to the Hon. Freeman Clarke,, states :	'
“A trader may begin, with a'capital of $I(),00() on the credit Ninety-system, as now managed, and in twenty-fivfc years there are noK^Jnen ik ninety-seven chances to every one hundred that lie will be tuii>1unflrud $10,000 in debt beyond his means to pay.”	’	■
In 1868 Mr. M. P. St acy, then and now manager of lb G.
Dun’s Mercantile Agency in Philadelphia, wrote :
“We have carefully considered the above statistics and . opinions, and believe that they are substantially correct, as applied to the present time. While our books show" periods of a few years each, attended with mercantile success, they also disclose seasons of great revulsion, so that the experience of this office for the last quarter of a century tends to copfirm the statement of General Dearborn.”
Mr. Cist, the editor of the Cincinnati Advertiser, a very careful statistician, made the following statement some two or three years ago :	1	»
“It is the experience and observation of intelligent persons in the east that there is hardly a firm in existence* now which did business twenty ^sars ago, and that nine out of ten in mercantile life, in- thfy long run, amidst the fluctuations of
Even in ton years one half of th<* hu^iii'^s m'H fail.
< >n<* Imu-1 drrd a n, i } t\\ only (,h|m Kind mein hers |o!1 vo tin- Now York Life and Equitable in thirteen ytart’. .
The Jaw of business failure as regular as the law of the average of life.
Premi urns paid for
10
trade, are broken. Let me, however, bring the subject nearer home. I had prepared a list of the principal active business men who were in trade twenty--yeitrs ago in Cincinnati, of which a brief'extract is all 'th&t'-1 have space for in these 8 columns. My list comprehends:some four hundred business men of which the above is a sample. I know of but five now in business who were so twenty years since, such is mercantile success.”	^
The Chicago Tribune has recently made some investigations on the same subject, but 'Covering a period of the past ten years only. Xfc selected the names of one hundred wholesale merchants, re|iresenting twenty-five different interests, from a bush mss directory of 1870, sent the . names to B. G. Dun’s q hgwiey, and asked how many had failed during the ten years.
Tim answer was that fifty-five of the firms named had either killed or compromised during the time.
The records of: the New York Life and Equitable entirely /:V 1 coiToboraf<1 fie1 opinions quoted. On the first of• January y last hike teat companies had 100,820 policies in force, about equally divided between them ; during the thirteen years, from,1808 to 1880, inclusive, there have been terminated in the two companies by policies surrendered and lapsed 119,5-97 policies. The number of persons who have left the two \ companies is theiefore- largely in excess of the number which remain. The 119,597 members who have abandoned the two Tontine companies since Tontine was adopted, did not all leave on account of business failures. The same causes which have deprived so marry men of their Tontine policies existed 4 to a greater or less extent among this enormous number. Policies were forfeited because of dishonest agents, because, of misunderstandings, and .because of disgust at the anticipated small dividends of the companies. But the great majority of \ the nearly one hundred and twenty thousand members who 1 have left the Tontine companies have done so because of.. business failures and inability to pay. The law of business failure seems to be almost as regular as the law of average of life. Information received from expert sources, from the i records of the companies themselves, is conclusive that if one - -thousand men take Tontine policies for the ten-year period, less than half will be able to get through. If for the fifteen-year ' period, less than one-third will be able to pay for the entire , period, and if the period is made for twenty years, the number A who will be able to reach the end of the period will be so small as to be hardly worth mentioning. The contracts made by the New York Life and by the Equitable Life under their Tontine plans: are contracts made to be broken by the insured in 'ah Mb large majority of cases, and when broken every cent paid on ■ 1 them must be forfeited to the companies.' Let a man picture
to himself his feelings when, after years of deprivation of years and necessities for himself-and for liis family,, business disaster fos7''tLms comes and hundreds and it may be thousandstof dollars, are taken remorselessly from him by a wealthy corporation, because he was foolish enough to sign a contract to that effect in the days of prosperity. Let the tempted remember that the time will come in the great majority of cases, as certainly as the sun rises, and sets. Very few people realize the danger of a Bad business failure and disaster until it is upon them, and it is p,cture' this habit in our natures of carelessly thinking it will be . some one else, that has; been seized upon by the Tontine promoters. It is a wicked and corrupt scheme, well adapted to purposes of deceit, cheat, mud' swindling. ' It is a scheme based upon absolute facts to put into the hands of the companies millions of dollars which belong to poor needy people.
It will oe said, if so many policies lapse, if so many members i are compelled for so many causes to los^ their enth'w paymejnts, then, surely, those who do pay tluyugh the period will ifeap a rich harvest. Their policies must become valuable.! Certainly this is what is promised by the agents W the Companies when they are trying tfi smmre Ton tin* policies. We have said before, however, and we again assert that |lie Tontine results do not show on, policies ■ which have1 gone I all of the way through the first period, any material advantage over the ordinary (dividends in other leading- companies which do not practical Tontine. If there is profit made; from lapsed Tontine, as there certainly is, it goes somewhere j else, and does not reach the insured, as is proved by supputa- j tions and observation of results obtained in other leading;
Tontim*
p 'Helen i-how no t 'ofiO which are rwi, Uiown ill f In-orrii'i >ry poliei ot [no me <’• nnnie
of
Ml
companies.
The Connecticut Mutual Life of JIartford, the Mutual Better * Lite of New York, the Mutual Benefit Life of Newark, and the thuifTolf-State Mutual of Worcester, Massachusetts, are four leading companies. They have always been noted for economy-of t-ino. management, and, as a result, for large dividends to members.
Not one of these companiesv practices Tontine insurance.
Each of them gives large surrender values when members are compelled to stop payment. Jlot one of the companies tries to build itself up on the misfortunes of others. Facts show that Ihe dividends paid by these four companies, give quite as favorable/results as the Tontine dividends of the Equitable. There Is a book issued* by the Equitable, so lately as 1880, in which forty-sfYexamples of Tontine results are given in detail. The book 1 m markedy “ Issued for the use of a Tontine Agents of the Society]” <c Confidential,“ Not for Circu- £X!meJ of Cation,5’ “ To be carriechin the JPoeket.” It is intended to be pfv§]^ait8 very confidential, and we do hot wonder that the company tions. does’not want it in the hands of outsiders. The very first
12

A Tontine le^n.*. from .a '' c xi-Hdoatial ” bowk.
No nrival)-bige in Tontine uividemle.
Tontine largely be-iten in dividends by a coin-p my which nllows liberal s rrender va ues.
A email company with less than thrjge millions of assets pays as good dividends without Tontine as the Equi table does with it.
example of 'Tontine results whifdi lit gives, we take as a “fair specimen of-■■■them' ■all.	' f
Mr. Norman S. -Platt, of-Cheshire, Connecticut, took a policy for $2,000, in the Equitable, in 1870, on the Tontine plan. He: was 26 years old,; and paid a premium of $40.80 for each of the ten years. At the. end of the ten years, that is at the end of the Tontine period, the company- paid him a single Tontine dividend of $171.80. This-included all of his withheld dividends, and his share of the accumulations from forfeitures and dividends on lapsed policies. The succeeding year, he was given .a current dividend of $10.70. The policy was Nod 64,375. We will compare this; with policies in other companies on the ordinary plan, issued in the same year, at tile same age, and for the same amount.
In 1870, the Mutual Benefit Life of Newark, N. J., issued policy No. (14,04.6,also for $2,000, at age 26, on the ordinary plan.
30 niy premium was $40.20 instead of $4(480 as charged by the Equitable. At the end of each year, iftie insured was paid a dividend in cash, which" amounted at the end of the ten years , to $ 110.15. Tli e several dividends, made annually, instead of being consolidated in pne at the end of the ten years, put at seven percent, compound interest (a fair rate
f<.>r tliose years), amount at tlics epd of the ten years to $156.90.
1 f to this be added the difference in premiums also put at interest,-' we have $165.45. The 1881 dividend of the Equitable was $10.70, which, added to the Tontine dividend, gives $182.50. The 1881 dividend of the Mutual Benefit was $15.62, added to the results of ten years’ dividends gives $181.07, practically the same result without Tontine as with it, but leaving a current dividend after the period one half larger. The Mutual Benefit gives a liberal: surrender value in case of forfeiture. I
The Mutual Life of ifew York issued Policy No: 113,838 in 1870- It was for $2,000 at age 26, and the annual premium • was $40.80, precisely the same as in the Equitable, r A dividend was paid the insured at the end of each year in cash. At the end of ten years they had amounted to $136.26. At seven per cent, interest from the time they were paid until the end of the period, the amount is $182.93, or $11.13 more than the Tontine dividends of the Equitable. The Mutual Life gives a liberal surrender value in case of forfeiture.
Policy No. 7,177 was issued by the State Mutual Life, of Worcester, Mass., in 1870, for $2,000, on the ordinary life plan, at age 26. It was precisely in its description like the Tontine policy of the Equitable. At the end of ten years the company had paid the insured dividends to the amount of $115.89. These dividends put at interest from the time they were paid - until the end of the ten years at seven per cent., amount to
i
A

$170.93. The amount paid by tlie Equitable on the same kind of a poMcy, with the Tontine element of lapsed policies added, was only $171.80. Thus it will be seen that the State' Mutual ■ lias paid as good dividends without the Tontine element as the Equitable has with it, and the State Mutual "always gives . . an extremely liberal surrender value.
The Connecticut Mutual, Life Insurance Company, of Tontine Hartford, Conn., issued policy No. 105,400, also in 1870, for bl!tei!uadly $2,000. The policy was on the ordinary life plan. At the end of ten years tlie company had paid in dividends on this policy $128.72. These dividends at seven per cent, from the time they were paid until tlie end of the ten jrears would have amounted to $185.30. This is $13.50 more than the Equitable paid on its Tontine policy of precisely the same description.
The Connecticut Mutual does not practice Tontine, but pays liberal values when parties are forced to discontinue their policies.*
We have been unable to secure a Tontine result sn tlie New Yjork Life of the same description as tlie one given for theEqjiitabie. If, however, tlie dividends on ordinary policies
in the [New York Life, gi ven on pages 15.......-17, be compared
with tfie dividends in tlie Equitable, it will be seen that very little imparity exists. It is naturally the case that very little imparity should exist in Tontine dividersIs. It should, be said also that tlie two companies have very nearly the same assets land liabilities, that the large expense of management has been just about the same in each, and that members have left one company .about as rapidly as the other. They adopted Tontine at the same time thirteen years ago, and have borne each other company ever since in pushing it;. What one of the companies does is a perfect index of what the other does.
Thus the four life companies named have paid as large dividends without Tontine as the Equitable has with it. It should be said that the formulas which are used by different companies in making up their dividends naturally vary more or less. In companies which make the same earnings the dividends vary slightly. In the four companies named we find slight variations in results, but in each case tlie dividends have been as good as those received on ^ similar policy in the Equitable on tlie Tontine plan. Tills
* The detail of the dividends on the policies in the five Companies is as follows : They are given in the order of the years from the date of issue of the policy to the present date.
Equitable-Tontine dividend, $171.80, 1881 dividend, *10.70. -
Mutual'Life—Dividends, $3.10, $19.11, $18.82, $11.18, $13.46, $14.14, $14.56, $15.00, $15,58, $16.28.	!	4	■	■	.	i
Mutual Benefit—Dividends, $9.28, $lt).13, $10.97, $10.97, $10.97, $12.24, 12.88. $13.54, $14.22, $14.90, $15.02
State Mutual—Dividends, $11.05, $11.37, $11.71, $11.91, $12.41, $10.81. $11.21, $11.53 $11.89, $12.00, $12.34. ' *
Connecticut Mutual—Dividends, $9.72, $11.16, $11.50. $11.72, $12.84, $13.28, $13.74, $13.74 $15.30, $15.72, $12.80.
X#

Overwhelming chances of total loss and no profits.
No sane man will touch Tontine.
The Tontine survivor does not get the Tontine accunmla-tions.
i
Eight ' millions of policy-holders’ money used in thirteen years, easily paid out of Tontine accumulations.
!
result in 'the-four, companies named has been accomplished without the aid of confiscated reserves on forfeited policies, for in each of the companies all policies are entitled to a liberal surrender value at time of lapse. When the results realized by the Tontine plan, involving as it does such overwhelming chances of dotal loss, are seen to be no more favorable to the survivors of the Tontine period than those accomplished by first-class companies doing an honest business, without the aid of moneys wrung from the misfortunes of countless needy policy-holders, no one in his sane mind will take a Tontine policy, where lie can expect no profit in any event, and is extremely likely to incur a total loss of all the moneys paid.
But the question here arises*;What becomes of the accumulations from lapsed Tontine policies if they do not show in the dividends paid to survivors ? As bearing upon the question of the-desirability of taking Tontine insurance, it is not - necessary to answer the question. We have shown wliat does not become of it, that it does not go to the insured, or rather that'.it does not benefit the insured in comparison with dividends in companies which do not practice Tontine. It is proper, however, to answer the question, and tell what does become of the Tontine accumulations; and here we must again resort to comparison..	;
During the thirteen Tontine years to January 1, 1881, the average amount of insurance carried by the New York" Life and Equitable was $280,053,993, land their average expense of management was $2,187,529, or an average of $7.81 for each $1,000 insurance carried.
During the same thirteen years the average amount of insurance carried by the Connecticut Mutual, Mutual Life, and Mutual Benefit,,was $577,883,342, and the average expense of management was- $3,239,013, or an average of $5.61 per thousand.	:	1
By expense of management we do not mean losses or endowments, or dividends or surrender values or any policy claims, or any thing else paid, to the insured; but salaries, commissions, etc. Thus it cost $2.26 per thousand more in the two Tontine companies. Multiplying the average insurance of the New York Life and Equitable, viz., $280,053,993, by $2.26, the excess in cost of management on each thousand, we find the average excess for each of the thirteen years to be $616,118.78, and multiplying this by thirteen, we have $8,009,544, which it has been necessary to make up in the thirteen years before the Tontine companies would be on a level with the other companies. This is where eight millions have gone; and where probably o^er a million a year is going now.
We have said before that during the thirteen Tontine
15
years, 119,597 policies were lapsed and surrendered in tile seventy-two Tontine companies. Of these 77,071 were.lapsed. That is, sa^dSi»em-' over seventy-seven thousand members quit these two com-panies who had paid premiums to them, and who received not two tontine
X	X	X_	'	e	_	P OTTItllPH
one cent in return. The stupendous ’ amounts realized. can and do not
easily be imagined. Of course we cannot figure closely ; the S*vc a companies retained money from each one of the seventy-seven . thousand. In some cases thousands I of dollars /were realized.
It could hardly have been less than hundreds in any case. If seventy-seven thousand be multiplied by anything it gives an enormous result. If we take the average amount confiscated ' at $500, the result; is nearly forty millions ; at $300, it is owe twenty millions, and at $100 it is nearly eight in HI ions, v h-enormous with any figure for an average loss to ench ii.m»
Here is the real key-note to Tontine.! It makes no dsffmnii.ee to these two companies what their expenses are; Tonti im will take care of them. There are millions and millions for lee mi!liolmo? way. .But again we say, it does not matter what becomes of -j^ncy, t the money sequestrated in considering our question, for we tR/j/iicy have proved that the insured does not get it.
We\ have said that very large amounts are necessary in’ the twef Tontine companies to make, up for high expense of management, and that this is, where a large portion of the Tontinl accumulations go to. ; If we! look at tlieulivideads in
holders know it not.
.  	j	_	Di vidends
the two companies on policies .not in thefTontine class we find	()f
abundant proof of this. TIieexampl.es which we quote will/” show that the dividends in the hew! York .Life and^ Equitable are far Below those in other leading companies, ‘oftentimes being not over one-half, on policies of precisely tin1 -same description. In the following examples there is nothing whatever of the Tontine element:;
Mr. R. S. McKee, of Ind^inapolis, Indiana, took IN o. 59,246' new York in the Hew York Life, in 1869, at age forty-six, for $10,000, hlo’per11^ premium,' $395.80. His dividend in 1881) was $8604, or cent ' twenty-two per cent of the premium. Mr. McKee also took a Mutual policy of $20,000 at the same time wind at the same rate of thirty-nine premium in the Mutual Benefit Life, Insurance Company of I>fcroeilfc-Newark, New Jersey. , His dividend in 1680 was $800.40, which Was thirty-nine per cent of the premium. The dividend » in the Mutual Benefit was nearly twice as large as in the.-New	\ ,,
York Life. The Mutual Benefit does not practice Tontine, and does not meed to.
Policy tSTo. 36,704 was issued in 1868 by the Equitable for EquitabIe $10,000, premium $471.80. * The dividend in 1880 was $130.00. S130.00 ’ Policy No. 88,672 was issued in 1868 by the Mutual. Life for $m?o. 1 e $10,000, premium $471.80. The dividend in 1880 vras $226.70,: or very nearly twice the dividend of the Equitable. The policies were precisely alike in all regards. ' The Mutual -Life does not practice Tontine, and does not need to/’
fS^510’ -■ In 1870, Mr. F. ;F. 'Frendh,. of'Chicago, Illinois, took $1,000 New York.. ?each iii tiie New York Life and Equitable at age 26, the
Lne, $5,4(5. "	-	:	x	■	  -	-
Mutual Benefit, $V,c>L
premium "being $20.40 in reach Company. His dividend in 1880 in the New York Life was $5,46; in the Equitable it was $5.35. During the same year, Policy No. 68,508 was issued by the Mutual Benefit of Newark, for $1,000 at the same age.
The dividend of 1880 was $7.81. ;
lEan In;1878 the New York Life issued a poley of $10,000 on Mntr.ap’ the life of Mr. Wm. A. Btedman, of Newport, B. I., age 41, Life,$8,j.()2. premillin $324.70. *: The same yearlthe Mutual Life issued a policy for the same amount, at the name age, on the life of Mr, H. E, Bateman, of South Charleston, O., premium $324.70. The dividend in the New York Life in 1880 was $41.40, and in
the Mutual Life it was $85.62, oh more than twice as much.
New York Life, £5.113. Mutual
Benefit,
|8.W.
New York Life, 131.40. Mutual -Benefit,
$03,815.
Equijtable, §2,080.21. Mutual Life,
.$3,129.51.
'New York
Life,
$421.00.
Mutual
Life,
$755.70.
Equitable,
$250.21.
'Connecticut
Mutual,
$385.20.
In. 4868 the New York Life issued policy No. 49,650 at age 25 for $1,000, premium: $20.80. : The dividend in P.881 was $5.48. In the same year the Mutual Benefit issued policy No. 52,799 for the same amount, and at the same age and same plan, premium $20.40. The dividend in 1881 was $8.28.
In 1849 the New York Life issued policy No. 2,473 at age 46 for $2,000, ordinary Life plan. Yhe dividend in 1881 was $32.40. In 1849 the Mutual Benefit issued policy No. 6,628 for the same amount and same plan. The dividend in 1881 was $63.86. There was a difference of two years in the ages in these cases, the policy in the Mu-tual Benefit being issued at age 44, it would slightly affect the dividend, and unfavorably to the Mutual Benefit.
Policy No. 52,210 was issued by the Equitable in 1870. Eleven dividends amounted to $2,020.21. Policy No. 107,726 was issued by the Mutual Life of the same year, on the same plan, the same age, and the same ^premium. Eleven dividends to 1881 amounted to $3,129.54. - j
In 1869 the New York Life issueds policy No. 57,871. premium $189.95,- The'twelve dividends to 1881 amount to $421.69. In the same year the Mutual Life issued policy No. 92,472 at the same premium, age,| and Man. The twelve dividends to 1881 amount to $755.76.!
In 1875 the Equitable issued: policy No. 96,107 at age 43 for $10,000, premium $350.50. The total dividends for five years were $250.21. In the same year the Connecticut Mutual issued policy No. 134,556 for the same amount, same age, same plan, premium $350.30. Total dividends in five years amount to $385.20.	■	*
Equitable, In 1878 Dr. George Tilden, of Omaha, Neb. (age 36), took New* York life policies for $2,500 each in the Mutual Life, New York Mutual8'91 ’	and Equitable. The dividends for the two succeeding
Life,§4i.o2. years were as follows : Mutual Life, $41.02; New York Life, $18.91; Equitable, $18.25.	■
17


*
%
In 1872 Mr. Henry. F? Field, cashier of the .Rutland County National Bank of Butland,} Yt.j? took policies of $2,500 each in	■
the Equitable and the/ltfhlh&l Life on the safrie plan. Nine |[f‘5!hlb|e? dividends in the Equitable, amount to $99.23. Nine dividends huiuni in the Mutual Life amounted to $144.30. V*	.;
In 1873 Mr. J. B. Buchtel, Founder of Buchtel College, in Nrw York Akron, Ohio, took a policy of $20,006 in the New York Bife, Wgg’ and one of $10,000 in the Mutual Life on the same plan. At tervb. the end of six years the dividends on the $20,000 in the New
the dividends on t'J'Scov
York Life had amounted -to $695.33, whik the $10,000 in the Mutual Life had afnounted to $734,07.
"We have thus shown that the great majority of insurers ^£°Shich under Tontine policies lose the entire amount paid to the condemn Tontine companies; that the survivors of the Tontine period. 10 " "" do not realize any profit which they would not have realized, in other leading^companies ; that Tolitine is full of risk and chance lot loss in a great variety of way is. Any one of those reasons is sufficient to condemn Tontine.
Butlthere are others of almost equal force. The agents jYlmNW of the Tontine companies in their zeal for business and coin- w wvh, missions work under circumstances i which compel them to make constant estimates of Tontinej results. .No - fifteen or twenty iyear Tontine policies hlive yeti matured. , Any calculations nlust be estimates. Statements of the roost outrageous nature have been furnished in writing to insurers in regard to the results to be attained. Out of numerous examples one may be given.
Mr. C. .P. Leland, of Cleveland, Ohio, took a fifteen-wear A?oy ___ 7 7 7 _ «/
Tontine policy in the Equitable at age 40 for $10,000. After he had been insured for a time, he'|wrote the agent of .the company in Cleveland, Mri C. B. ■ Gay, and asked him what would be the probable results at the end of the time. Mr.
Gay answered in writing, under date of July 22, 1880, that.
“ from the present outlook the estimated cash results of your h:fi;nt policy will not be far from $8,000.” i By turning to the con- estimate of fidential book of estimated results issued by the Equitable, January, 1876, we find that it is estimated that a Tontine policy , of ten thousand issued at age 40, 15 year Tontine, will give a cash value of $7,100. But this confidential book comprmys of the Equitable’s was changed for a milder one November 1 , mate, same 1878, and in this one the estimated result on a policy of pre-cisely the same description is $6,010' Here then is a predie- company’s tion from the agejit in 1880] of $8,000, one from the company fstimfte in 1876 of $7,100, and another from the company in 1878 of $6,010. What Mr. Leland’s policy will realize if he isJortunate ^ ! . ‘ enough to get through the period no living mortal can tell, and no one but an agent of the company, or the company itself would guess ; but wre will say to Mr. Leland and all
The'Equitable examined. in 18?d, and
the result.
Tontine surplus dors not. belong to
Tontine sur vivors.
So says the New York Insurance Department.
others that it will bejust what the company at that time sees fit to give him, for they are not under obligations under his contract to give him one cent, not even if lie has paid through the entire period. This is readily proved.
In 1876 the Equitable was examined by the New York Insurance Department. When the assets and liabilities had been footed- up, it was found: that the company had a general surplus of $4,641,233.20 on a four and one-half per cent, interest valuation. But by 4he four per cent., or Massachusetts standard, the surplus, was reduced to $2,570,477.20. This, however, included the accumulations belonging specially to the Tontine poli<yHio]der£, amounting to $2,193,577. And w 11 en th Is amount was deducted, it left the company with the bare margin of $376,900.20 as a surplus over liabilities. This was so small that the company would readily be seen to be in danger of failure, and especially by those who construed its liabilities under the Massachusetts law. If the amount wdiich turd been taken out oLJ|ipsed Tontines, and which should belong exclusively to tub survivors, were taken out of the surplus of the company, leaving as we have said but $376,-900.20, or only about one per cent, of the assets of the company, then, we say, the company was in great danger of failure. Tli is the company well knew, and Tontine was made to come in and serve another of its purposes. The claim was at once set up that the Tontine surplus did 'not belong to the Tontine class at-all, but to the -company at large. * The report of the Examiner, in speaking of this point, said :
“ It will be seen by the following extracts from a form of Tontine policy used by the society, that the surplus on these policies cannot be charged as a-fixed liability, but simply noticed to show what portion of the net surplus belongs” to Tontine policy-holders.”
This form will be found on pages 19 and 20, in connection with the non-forfeiting clause m policies of other leading companies.
Thus in 1876 in order to make even a respectable showing of solvency after a rigid official examination, the company set up the claim that accumulations of Tontine members did not belong to the members at all, but to thefgentire company.
'.During the same year in which the examination of the Equitable took place, a Committee of the New York Legislature sent for Mr. Henry B. Hyde to examine him on the subject of Tontine. Mr. Hyde is the President of the Equitable, is the undoubted originator of Tontine, and is the best authority in regard to it. We append a portion of the examination:
Q. Have you any means of approximating the number of Tontine policies which have been forfeited during the past year? Answer by Mr. Hyde, No, sir.
19
Q. Is that to be published in your statement ? Answer by Mr. Hyde, No, sir.
Q. Have you any means of determining the amount of the insurance of the Tontine policies which have been forfeited during the year? Answer by Mr. Hyde, I have no information, sir.	|
Q. Is that to be published in youri statement ? Answer by Mr. Hyde, No, sir.	|	o
Q. Have you any means-of determining the number of Tontine policies forfeited since that system: of insurance began? Answer by Mr. Hyde, No, sip	:
Q. is that to be published in your!statement? Answer by Mr. Hyde, No, sir.
Q. Have you any means of deteinrining the amount of" insurance on Tontine policies since the company comm*meed that system ? Answer by Mr. Hyde, No, sir.
Q. Is that to be published in your|statement ? Answer by Mr. Hyde, No, sir.	■
Q. Have you any means of determining the reserve which, is represented by the Tontine policies since the commencement c|f that system ? Answer by Mr. Hyde, No, sir.
Q. Ts that to be published In your: statement ? Answer by' Mr. Hwde, No, sir.	|
Q. Have you any means of] determining the reserve which is represented by the' Tontihe policies since the company .began? Answer by Mr. Hyde, I have; no information.
Q. Is that to be published? ’ Ahswer by Mr. Hyde, No,
sir.
But lately the company has gone to a further extreme, and now sets up the claim that the assets of the company do not belong to any of the members, Tdntine or otherwise. A policy-holder of the company recently became so much dissatisfied with the uses to which its funds were put, and with the division of the profits among.the officers rather than the members, that he commenced suit against the companyf To the complaint of the plaintiff, the following extraordinary defense is set up by the company, accused officers, and directors of the Equitable Life :
“The plaintiffs, as policyholders,'have no rights which entitle them to bring this action. The policy-holder is not a cestui que trust, and neither the directors nor the company are trustees. The policy-holder is not a partner. He is not, a creditor. He is not a member of the company.” *	*	*
“ The fund produced by the payment of all the premiums does not in any sense belong to the policy-holders, but belongs exclusively to the company.”
On argument the demurrer of the Company was sustained
Tontine
Company
sued.
in answer ing claims policy-holder ia not a mein-her of the pomp any.
“ Purely mutual,” a misnomer.
The Tontine coin tract-in full
No man who will
read it can accept it.
by Jiidg^\Larremore, and the complaint was dismissed oil the
grounds urged by tlie defendants.* .
For years tlie Equitable has puffed itself as a purely mutual company. It claims in its publications that tlie corn- f pany is managed for tlie benefit of policy-holders, but when In ought into court on charges of misappropriation of funds, it sets up the claim that tlie policy-holder haslno rights, and that it is none of his business what the officers do with the funds. We do not believe tlm company would have set up t such a defense as this a few years ago. But the working of Tontine lias been so admirable from the standpoint of the companies ; it has been so pleasant to them, to think and feel tliat-the policy-holder was entirely within their grasp, and absolutely subject to their mercy, that they are doubtless ^ willing to thank thes.policy-holder who brought the suit, which gives them tlie chance to claim equal ownership of all the members, Tontine or not.	'
We ask attention to tlie folio wing ex tracts from,1 tlie policies of tlie c.ompanies named. We quote first from the;Equitable’s
Tontine policy :	,	;
special conditions and agreements and conditions relative ^
TO TONTINE SAVINGS FUND POLICIES.
Frrst—That this policy is issued under the Tontine Savings Fund plan.
Second—Tliat the Tontine dividend period for this policy < x shall be completed on the	day of	in
the year eighteen, hundred and	^
Third—That no dividend shall be allowed or paid upon this policy unless the person whose life is hereby assured shall survive the completion of its Tontine dividend period as T aforesaid, and unless thisepolicy shall be then in force.
Fourth—That all surplus or profits, derived from such policies on the Tontine Savings Fund Assurance plan as shall cease to be in force before the completion of their respective Tontine dividend periods, shall be apportioned equitably ^ among such policies as shall complete their Tontine dividend periodsl
Fifth—That upon the completion of the Tontine dividend period on	provided	this	policy	shall	not	have been ^
terminated previously by lapse or death, the legal holder or holders of this policy shall have the option, either - First, to withdraw in cash, this policy’s entire share of the assets (i. e., the accumulated reserve and surplus apportioned by this
* Bewley vs. Equitable Life Assurance Society, N. Y. Supreme Court, July, 1881, Term. Larremcre, J.
Society to this policy) ; Secondly, to convert the same into a paid-up policy for an equivalent amount, provided always that if the amount of said ; paid-up policy shall exceed, the original amount of the assurance, a satisfactory certificate of good health from one of the; Society’s medical examiners'shall be required ; Thirdly, to:!continue the assurance for the original amount and apply the entire Tontine dividend to the purchase of an annuity to reduce the, subsequent premiums falling due upon this policy, provided that in any year in which the amount derived from such: annuity together with, the annual dividend on this policy shall exceed the amount of premium due thereon, the excess shall be paid in cash, to said
the share of the accumulated surplus apportioned by said
Society to this policy and continue the policy in force oil the
£t If : this policy shall, be proved1 or become void by th O Full renorvc failure of any of the considerations or; by the violation of any SJutuaiy thc of the conditions specified above,1 all payments previously Life-made upon it shall be forfeited to the company ; but, if such forfeiture shall occur by the 11011-payment of any premium at ^ any time after three full annual premiums have been paid, /	4
the company will, upon surrender of this policy, within six y months after such forfeiture, issue a non-participating paid up policy for such sum as the reserve upon this policy at the time of forfeiture, according to the legal standard of the State of New York, will purchase as lYmhgle premium at the company’s published rates.”	a.
Tliej following is the surrender value clause contained in the policies of the Mutual Benefit Life Insurance Company
of New'ark, N. J.
“ But when, after two full annual premiums shall have Fun reserve been paid on this policy, it s shall cease or become void solely f^tuaiy the by the non-payment of any ^premium when due, its entire net Benefit, reserve by the American Experience! Mortality and interest at four per cent, yearly, less any indebtedness to the company on this policy, shall be applied by the company as a single premium at the company’s rates published and in force at this date, either, first, to the purchase of non-participating
or assigns ; or, Fourth.ly, to withdraw- in cash,
Thej following is the surrender, value clause contained, in the policies of the Mutual Life Insurance Company of New
York :
term insurance for the full'amount insured by this policy, or, second, upon'the- written application by the owner of this ^ policy and the surrender thereof to the company at Newark within Three months from sncli non-payment of premium, to 'the purchase of a lion-participating paid-up policy payable at the time this policy would be payable if continued in force. Both kinds of insurance aforesaid will be subject to the same conditions, except as to payment of premiums, as those of this policy. No part, however, of such;term insurance shall he due or payable unless satisfactory proofs of death be furnished to the company within one year after death ; and if ^ death shall occur within three years after such non-payment of premiam and during such term of .insurance, there 'shall be deducted from the amount'payable the sum of all the pnmiiuins Unit would have become due on this policy if it had - «- atinned i n force.”	a
The following is the surrender value clause contained in the policies of the State Mutual Life Assurance Company, of Worcester, Mass. :	;	'	4
“ That if the annual premium shall not be paid at the time and in the maimer prescribed, this policy shall' become forfeited and void, except as provided in the 282d chapter of the acts!of the Legislature of Massachusetts, passed in 1880, entitled i ‘ an act limiting the forfeiture of policies in life insur- 4 ance companies.5 55
The Massachusetts Law provides that after a policy has been in (force for three years, the value of the policy, by the Actuaries’ Table of Mortality, with interest at four, per cent., shall be given to the insured, less a small surrender charge. ^ The value is given in paid up insurance,1 whether applied for or not ; .lor if the insured desires^ and the policy can be legally surrendered, then the value must be given in cash. This law was approved April 23, 1880. The liberal provisions of the ^ Massachusetts Law are incorporated in the policies of the (New England Mutual, the Massachusetts Mutual, and the Berkshire.	■
The practice of the
Connecticut Mutual in regard to , forfeited policies.
The following is the surrender value clause contained in the policies of the Connecticut Mutual Life Insurance Company of Hartford, Connecticut:
“ That if, after the'payment of three -or more full annual premiunis upon this policy, the same shall cease and determine by (default in the payment of any subsequent premium when due,- then this company: will grant a paid-up policy, payable as above, for an amount to be determined as follows:
s
4
¥
23
from the net reserve on account of this policy at the time of . such default, there shall be deducted any indebtedness on account of this policy, and, in addition, the difference, for the year following such default, befweeii the' normal cost of insurance under this policy and the normal cost of insurance under the paid-up policy to be issued ;;| the computations to be based upon the actuaries’ or combined, experience table of mortality and four per centum compound interest: the remainder of said reserve shall be used asjksingle premium for paid-up insurance, at the then present age of the insured; according to the published single premium, tables of this company ;' fr- Provided that this policy shall be released and surrendered to and received by this company,: and written application made for such paid-up policy during the lifetime of the said insured, and within one year after default in payment of , premium hereon shall first be made.”


¥

1
b
Thje points in regard to Tontine life insurance may be summarized as follows :
1.	[Every policy, from the nature; of the rate charged, has, as it grows older, an increasing valufe. T? lis value belongs to the iiifeiirer, and is so recognized by law and practice.
2.	|Tontine totally confiscates this value, if the premium is not paid on the day when it m due. ;
3.	It is for the interest of the company practicing Tontine to take advantage of its contract and confiscate this- value without mercy, if the insurer fails :to pay his premium when due.
4.	There are many reasons why premiums may not be paid when due. They may be enumerated as follows :
a. Inability, arising from failure in business, which, will overtake certainly one-half in Jen years, three-fourths in fifteen 1 years, and nearly all in twenty
b.
c.
d.
years.
Carelessness in not remembering when a premium is due, which will occur with a- large number. Misunderstanding in regard to the termination of the days of grace, b
Dishonesty of agent in j not turning the premium paid over to the company. e. Disgust "at being deluded by the agent.
For one or another of these causes, more than half of * those who enter a short-term Tontine are sure to fail before the period is through, and! nearly all will fail who enter a long-term Tontine. In every case of failure to get through, every cent is lost.
5.
6. The survivors of the Tontine
period do not realize any
ft-
!
24
This 1h Tontine.
benefit which they could not'have had in other leading companies without incurring the Tontine risks.
a.	The reputable ■ companies, under the ordinary,
honest plan of life insurance, repay as.much at the. end of ten years, as is repaid to those who have successfully struggled through the Tontine period.
b.	The companies promoting Tontine do not distribute
to survivors the profits from the robbery of non-survivors of .the Tontine period, but divert them to pay. the expenses of their extravagant management. They rob not only the poor insurers who fail, but also those who succeed in surviving the period.
ex The Tontine .survivors have no legal claim even on their Tontine accumulations. What they receive is of the mere grace of the managers.
7. Tontine is a mere delusion.
a.	ft is a gambling venture of those who insure.
b.	A barefaced robbery of those who fail to go through a Tontine period. ;
a. A. fleecing by the managers of those who succeed in getting through a Ton tin (3 period.
This is Tontine. It is not honest, legitimate life insurance. It antagonizes the very first principle of life insurance, which is proteefion. It does not protect; it deceives with wild will-o’-the-wisp promises, and lures on to destruction. Its principle' is gambling, and gamblers must expect to fall into the hands ofsharpers, and sharpers are the only ones who make money by gambling. The simple, plain facts can lead to no other conclusion. The lamb who ventures amohig Tontine wolves must expect to be devoured.
z9Ari2»'.'