BETTER CREDIT
REPORTING.
A Revolution in Progress Through the Clearing-House Principle*
Rise of the Credit Gearing-House in the West—Its Extension to New York and the Country—Direct Reporting Made Possible.
It is worth recalling that credit reporting, regarded as a distinct branch of business or clear division of labor, began at New York. The first step, as already seen, was taken by a group of dry goods merchants who employed an agent through whom they could exchange freely their several experiences in dealing with applicants for credit. The fact held by each was given in exchange for that of all the others, and to the end that the action of each might be based upon the common intelligence. The impulse proceeded from the merchants, and the exchange involved the actual experiences of all within the trading circle; anything short of this would have had no consideration.
THE PRINCIPLE.
The principle at work is thus disclosed, and we become aware that in the beginning the movement was premised upon the free exchange of experiences on the part of merchants in determining credits. The measure of freedom for the action was of course just in proportion to the degree of communication attained. I have directed attention to the fact that credit reporting arose at the time of the forward movement of the American post-office in 1840. Constantly in need of more exact information on which to base his transactions, the merchant was prompted to new action by the growing intercourse.
DIRECT REPORTING.
So long as this early collecting of credit news was carried on within a restricted area only, the principle was maintained, and merchants were enabled, through a common agent, to report to one another the facts encountered by each. During the intervening years the “mercantile agencies,” in the struggle to turn the principle to account. have overrun the United States and Canada, but in place of gradually building up the exchange of experiences on the part of merchants parallel with the growth in communication, they have erected an unwieldy machine which, owing to an artificial prestige, stands to-day as a positive hindrance to the better credit reporting made possible by new conditions. At the outset, within narrow limits, merchants
were able to Digitized by
Gort directly
OOgl
through
e
designated agents. Under the conditions of the hour, with adequate centers in place, the direct reporting of credit news becomes practicable for the entire country. Communication is so far organized that the United States and Canada, with respect to credit reporting, may be dealt with on the basis of unrestricted intercourse. The truth of this is established by the great extent to which the free interchange of experiences in credit making—the clearing house principle—has already obtained.
THE FUTURE.
As previously indicated, the future of credit reporting is in the hands of those who arc able to give free play to the clearing house principle. And so, the practical outcome of this inquiry lies in the discovery that the Credit Clearing House in America is at the point of passing from the status of a “private” enterprise to recognition as a public institution on a level with the bank Clearing House or the Stock Exchange. In tracing the recovery of the principle of free interchange in credit reporting and the subsequent rise of the institution now known as the Credit Clearing House, the merchant, as such, is again seen as the pioneer; the first impulse proceeded from the merchant—grew out of his needs.
ACTION OF DETROIT MERCHANTS.
The honor belongs to Detroit merchants. The Merchants and Manufacturers Exchange of Detroit was organized in 1878, its membership being made up as its name indicates. One of its purposes, as conceived by its projectors, was an interchange of credit-making news between trade associations. Gradually the work of credit reporting in the manner indicated got under way and was carried over Michigan with some success. Connections were made with boards of trade at Toledo, Pittsburg and Columbus. The movement failed to extend itself for lack of comprehensive plans and vigorous direction. Detroit has wide business connections and it was found that far-away facts were wanted quite as much as those nearer home; Detroit isolated was unreal: its affairs had to be held in relation with those of the country and the world. Moreover, the M. and M. concern of Detroit, as it was called,
lacked the mainspring of a narrow interest—the individual selfishness. The salary of its actuary was a fixed sum, and it was paid out of the contributions of the members without direct reference to the amount of business done. With the individual out of it there was no propelling force. Under such conditions the principle could not get expression, and it wras scarcely heard of under Detroit auspices outside of Michigan beyond the two Ohio cities named and Pittsburg. But the fact remains that Detroit’s men of business were first to propose under present conditions the direct exchange of experiences in credit making on the part of merchants. The advance thought came in with the telephone, and it arose west of New York.
SPREAD OF THE IDEA.
Tlie work was continued in a halting way, but its real effect lay in finding a lodgment for the clearing house idea in the minds of certain individuals. It got to Rycrson Ritchie, who appeared in Kansas City, Mo., in 1886 or thereabouts, and organized the Commercial Club. As an adjunct of the Club an interchange of credit news was begun, and it became very successful under Mr. Ritchie’s direction. But its decadence followed upon Ritchie’s departure, which was prompted by a more inviting connection at Cleveland, O. Mr. Ritchie is now secretary of the Ohio State Board of Trade.
WORK OF ROBERT J. LYLE.
It was through contact with Ritchie that the idea of a free interchange of credit information— the clearing house principle— found lodgment in the mind of the right man. This man was Robt. J. Lyle, who became associated with Ritchie at Kansas City in the credit-reporting work of the Commercial Club. The idea came to possess Mr. Lyle, and being a man of great fertility in working out details of this order, he conceived of several improvements over the plans in use by Ritchie. Taking these with him he went to St. Paul in 1888, and placed his developed plan before the merchants of the Twin Cities. These men of business at once grasped the advantages to be gained and took hold with enthusiasm. Mr. Lyle’s St. Paul and Minneapolis enterprise took shape as the “Mercantile Exchange,” It w'as the forerunner of the Credit Clearing House.
Mr. Lyle furnished the division of labor which the Detroit project lacked. Credit reporting is one department of the great traffic in news, and as such is itself an interest independently of the transactions reported. The centers through which the facts of credit making are cleared have to be in charge of men who possess the habit and passion of the reporter. The reporter’s calling, it should be understood, is a clear division of labor in the social body in the same sense as that of the chemist or the architect.
Original from
NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY
At the end of three years Mr. Lyle’s success at St. Paul in providing for merchants a free interchange of credit making news was so great that a demand for the reports came up from Chicago; such Chicago merchants as were selling largely in the Northwest insisted upon sharing in the benefits of the clearing house principle. In consequence an office of the “Mercantile Exchange” was opened in Chicago in 1892. This name was continued down to May, 1895, when the Credit Clearing House was incorporated under the statutes of Illinois.
A NBVOLUTION.
So much for the beginning of a movement which is revolutionizing the whole business of credit reporting. The Credit Clearing House has now fifteen main centers in the United States. The fifteen offices are in the following cities, and they were opened in the order named: St. Paul and Minneapolis, Chicago. Louisville, Detroit, St. Louis, Cincinnati, Baltimore, New York, Philadelphia, New Orleans, Cleveland, Memphis. Atlanta, Boston and St. Joseph. The New York office was opened in January, 1896.
Through these centers merchants are freely exchanging their experiences; credit reporting is recovering its lost principle. The rapidity with which the Credit Clearing House is obtaining justifies the largest treatment of the matter. Its function is to connect together the credit departments of the great mercantile houses of the country, so that each may act in the light of the experience of all.
The merchants of the United States are themselves extending the system through special advocacy. To illustrate. the office of the Credit Clearing House at Detroit was opened in 1894. owing to the representations of Detroit merchants as to the need thereof.
In a concluding article I will set out the chief characteristics of the clearing house system in credit reporting. and its importance as a safeguard of commercial integrity. The necessary relations of the Credit Clearing House with the system of bank clearings will have attention, together with the further development of the principle and the effect of such development on the organization of commerce.
FRANKLIN FORD.