CUSTOMS TEXTILE ASSOCIATION.
Summing-up of the Evidence Thus Far Given.
Statements of Importers Considered—Also
Those of Officers of the C. T. A.
—Appointments to the Appraisers' Office.
The importing business of textiles for the port of New York is practically that of the United States, r.s 90 per cent, of these are entered at this port. It goes without saying that it should be the aim of a Government whose chief source of income is derived from a tariff in the main based on value to make the administrative machinery of the tariff, i. e., the appraising department of the port, as nearly perfect in its efficiency as human ingenuity can devise.
Yet the assertions of the officers of the Customs Textile Association, printed in the several issues of Textile America, would leave little doubt that the Government machinery is sadly inefficient. and requires the assistance of an outside agency. For the gratuitous rendering of service of this kind the C. T. A. was organized during the late administration of Mr. Cleveland. Their assertions indicate, an ex-president of the Association so plainly stated to a reporter of Textile America, that perhaps one half of the importers are undervaluers and smugglers.
imfbrbrcm from tmk forbooirq.
If this was the case, even to a less degree than here stated, the necessity of an organization like the C. T. A. would be obvious. The Government’s incapacity to administer its own business could find no better proof. Lamentable as this would be in itself, it would further imply that the importing business of New York has been brought to its immense proportions by virtue of fraud and undervaluation. It is against experience, in an age so entirely based on publicity, that achievements such as shown by our leading importing houses, built up by some of them through two generations of uninterrupted success, could be grounded on anything but integrity.
hbfortbrb’ btatmmknts.
The leading importing houses interviewed by Textile America gave an entirely different version than the officers of the C. T. A. They hold that such a thing as undervaluing by houses, who purchase their goods, is an impossibility. Even if it were attempted it would be easily detected in the appraiser’s department, where all the invoices converge. They say that in the woolen and worsted division, where the C. T. A. have been mosLactive in spreading the
Digitized by (jQOQIC
belief that their services were required, that a great many advances were made by the assistant appraiser, but all without the aid of the officers of the C. T. A.
It is stated by no less an authority than the president of the Board of Appraisers to a representative of Textile America that the late assistant appraiser had advanced within ten months’ time twice as many invoices as had been advanced by his predecessors in four years in bona-fide advances. These advances, it is said, were chiefly on consignments and the prices of these were rigidly brought up to the price established by purchasing importers by the assistant appraiser, lately removed. That undervaluations were actually extirpated by an efficient officer and the appraising machinery put to a high state of perfection is fully attested from many sides, including the members of the Board of Appraisers, and is contradicted by no one.
O. T. A. WITHOUT BFmCIAL IRFORMATIOR.
The importers who have been interviewed all hold that the C. T. A. can have no means to supply information other than what the Government has from first hand. They hold that the C. T. A. aim at creating an impression that their interference is required for the protection of Government interests; that they create an atmosphere of suspicion by innuendo; that they are unable to supply valid facts to sustain their assertions; that their real aim is to regain the position the predecessors of the C. T. A., the Woolen Manufacturers’ Association, held to the appraisers’ department, which led to such official abuses that President Cleveland felt constrained to apppoint a Commission of Inquiry in the Summer of 1893. This commission disclosed facts which would hardly find belief as characterizing official conduct.
VV/OC/VC« BKFORB COMMfMION.
To refresh the memory of readers a portion of the hearings which brought out the facts from the reluctant admissions of the assistant appraiser then in office is given below, immediately following this article. The holding up of goods, often leading to great loss, and the chicanery to which importers were exposed in other ways by virtue of this officially proved connection of the American Woolen Manufacturers’ Association with the appraisers’ department. have been repeatedly referred to by importers in Textile America. tmrroribi*.
The most damaging accusation that could be raised against a supposed government of law lies in the terrorism that seems to have been spread over the whole importing community. Every one of the many interviewed came out plainly in his denunciation of the C. T. A. and its manager, of the false pretenses with which it bolsters up its claims and the annoyances to which it has subjected importers. But with two
highly commendable exceptions, not one was willing to have his name affixed to his statement. All advanced as a reason for this reluctance the dangers and risks they would run. Now the C. T. A. have no executive power. They can not injure any one directly. They can do, however, infinite harm by their close affinity with the appraiser’s department, and this is explanation of the existing state of mind which would be expected in Warsaw, but not in New York.
OFFICIAL ClRCLKB BTIRRKO.
The investigations made by Textile America reveal a state of affairs which is not creditable to the Government. The statements printed have made an impression. It is but natural that official circles should be stirred. It is but natural that the Assistant Secretary should make a denial to one of our contemporaries in behalf of himself and his predecessor that the C. T. A. is extended any privileges at the Appraiser*s stores that were not open to everybody.
The admission of the president of the C. T. A. that their organization decides who is to be removed and who is to remain, that it had the power to fill the appraisership and three of the most important assistant appraiserships with men of their selection, would induce impartial observers to consider the assertion of Assistant Secretary Howell with the grain of salt usually applied to official utterances. This doubting attitude receives firmest support through the case of Mr. Schoenhof.
MR. BOMOBHHOF’B RBMOVAL.
Mr. Scoenhof is recognized as an expert in wool and woolens. His integrity has. been emphasized as beyond doubt by an ex-President and by the de facto president of the C. T. A.
It is known that he supported Mr. McKinley in the last campaign. His pen was active in the vindication of the sound money principle. His book on “Money and Prices” was a welcome storehouse of information of which campaigners availed themselves with profit to their cause. His retention was generally expected on these grounds. He was summoned to Washington by the Secretary of the Treasury to attend to the Senate Finance Committee in an expert capacity. It is owing to his practical statements that the impossible paragraphs of the original Dingley bill in woolens and dress goods were replaced by workable provisions. His services were rendered so impartially that Senators Aldrich and Allison felt constrained to call on the President and ask for Mr. Schoenhof’s retention. As our readers were informed, the promise was given that Mr. Schoenhof should be retained as long as any Democrat. Textile America is credibly informed that about that same time the manager of the C. T. A. expressed himself to the effect that Mr. Schoenhof would be removed within a fortnight after the termination of his extra duties. Within not Original from
NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY
more than a week’s time that the President gave his promise to the Republican senators Mr. McKinley signed the papers removing Mr. Schoenhof.
thk iMroRTmrra ARRmanammioam.
An outside body exercising such power over the Executive is not apt to retire into innocuous desuetude after having filled the offices with their own satellites. It is the use the C. T. A. will make of opportunities thus acquired which seems to fill the importer with apprehension. He judges from his experience under a Democratic administration. In his eyes the remark of the ex-president of the C. T. A. that “Mr. Schoenhof was a stumbling block in the appraiser’s office, and had room in his head for one idea only,” is full of significance. Those who look upon these utterances with a critical eye, and with a knowledge of the facts, say that Mr. Schoenhof knew neither friends nor enemies in his official capacity. This “one idea” is the proper standard of an administrative officer. Was he the stumbling block there that had to be removed for the attainment of objects that are not within that line?
This is the point the trading community is interested in, “the one idea principle” in the administration of the law.
FRANKLIN FORD.