Newspapers
.com
https://www.newspapers.com/image/80624909
The Wichita Daily Eagle (Wichita, Kansas) • Tue, May 4, 1897 • Page 4
Downloaded on Mar 14, 2017
Copyright © 2017 Newspapers.com. All Rights Reserved.
Newspapers™
Traffic Associations.
(From "Textile America.”)
The decision of the supreme court la the case of the Trans-Missouri Fre'ght Aaao-
tho nature aad effect of euch efforti on the part of railway manor yet perceived that some method of hunger the complex freight and passenger traffic under a common direction i* at wary aa waa the Introduction of the raph to the movement of train*. When It waa flrvt proposed to ru by telegraph a deal • of oppotltl aroused, and numbers of railway •ifcned becauae of 1;. The attack traffic association* are due of their true function, and disappear through the grow.ng effective-eas of the very mechlnery that la
The traffic association In the railway •yatem la of the same nature and function aa the clearing house In the eyatt
■ Injr, each being instrumental of **IX-temulation—the natural outgrowth of condltkma. The New Torlt Clearing Houae l» without so-called legal Incorporation, yet it la gradually assuming greater power* as an organ of government, and this without exciting even passing remark. The boards of trade are center* of regulation for the several businesses connected therewith. their purpose being to facilitate transactions and compel Integrity therein. A* communication, seen as a diet; branch of commerce, reached administrative unity In the postofllce. great business of transportation is struggling for its unity a* the m
> the highest economy and effective-The common instrument t Is the derided traffic association.
Happily, the supreme court decision and all other forms of obstruction will go further self-regulation for the railway. They will aid to clear stray misunderstand Ing. and to teach the necessity of avoiding conflict with wayside opinion by finding the moat direct road to the goal that be reached. The notion Is widespread that regulation of "commerce between the States" la only possible through the intervention of congress; the movement of commerce without such Interference Is ht to be lawless The opposite this, that commerce of necessity works Its own regulation, cannot be proved save by actual progress. A thawing of ' ' her* on the port of the railway
a would Tie of value. But any such report would be lacking In* point were It boldly prefaced by the assertion that the traffic associations are themselves of wholesale government; that all the governing la not done from Washington and Albany, however loud the clamor.
difficult to see how a clear solution can be gained without defining the issue as one between "the government at Washington” and the railway association aa an organ of self-government. The new legality, In fact, la to be eeen in the outworking of the transportation system Itself under the guidance of It* own Inherent law. Congrees may give registration to thi* law when determined by the action, but It
working toward the hlgheat qualify of service at the lowest price. Involving the w.deat distribution. One mean* to thli enlarged publicity. It la fair tc -he true measure of the service of the Inter-state commerce commission la its work as an agent of publicity, especially a* one effect thereof has been lo promote uniform railway accounting.
Railways have to be run by railway experts—there la no othgr way. The railways of Belgium or Swl^qrland may be ru a bureau of "the government." or for that matter "owned” by It, but for the r of country lying between Maine and California It will have to be done by experts —by science, which Is government. Again. It will be done by the individual, who is everywhere the instrument in man’s
The idea of "government ownership.” so far as it has any claim to attention, is simply tha dream of the unified transportation system. There Is still a widespread fear of unity, which should, however, find correction through observing the posioflW, whoae perfect diversity Is due to the fact that It la operated as a single system. The railway traffic association* stand for the approchlng unity or the trnsportatlon interests.
It is easy to lay down the rule that freight rates are to be equal and uniform, but this, like other good thing*, has to be worked out In practice. The problem is vastly complicated owing to the fact that the railway tariff continues to be based on distance, and. further, that it varies as to clsasea or goods. Statutes assert that rates shall be uniform, but it so happen* that the statutes fall to provide for changes In rates. From the very nature of things, important reductions to freight charge* cam* about In the past through the aggressiveness of individuals, who by offering guarantees of large buslnms or by other means secured for themselvri advantage* which were not at on e given to the who!* people. The herd is to reach such a stage of organization that successful warfare by Individuals for lower rate* will take effect an once for all shippers. To get to tha the governing Intelligence ha* to be centered in such bodies as the trsfflc associations: in other wodrs. the railway m»n have to provide for their own law-making organisation*, and this has to be mad# up by selections from, their highest experts.
cm# source of confusion and error lie* In the prevailing belief that the associations have as their end the maintenance of rate* at a certain high level, ar.1 for this the traffic managers *r» largely to clam*. The end Is :o regulate and govern rale*, and to arbitrate the various questions whs h are constantly arising In railway administration. It Is not possible for any set of manager*, however compact J the organisation, to rerist the counties* tn-fluetr -es which are determining railway freight and passenaer charges To accomplish It they would hsve to hold down the forces of nature, and put ar. effective ^heck upon the Inventive genius of man A given train - asro iation Is but the Instrument through wh.ch the competitive force* are mov ng. and these forces gain freedom and
effectiveness Jus tration of power—to unity or admlnlstra-Th# locomotive t* competing for it* p'ac* in the round up of commerce, end all paasible traffic as sort* t-one can c ' facXtate the action —Franklin Ford.