FORDS
Broadilllliety New York
FRA^Klil nSPORD, Director
Bank News Bulletin
». 1.
FROM GOLD COIN T(' . \\’K Tl'Ck
(Copyright).
On each Grid ay ('veiling at New York advices are received by telegraph giving the bank exchanges for the week at hinety-one clearing centers outside of New York, extending from Montreal and Jacksonville on the east, to San h’rancheo, Portland, and Los Angeles on the west. The summing up at the main center. New York, is telegraphed to all outside centers lor simultaneous publication on the folkwvirm
baiT v carings are followed by r licit the summary thereof mtj: both as to the immediate bankin,
ing. It tluis appears that 4 Y \ oekl parallel clearing of bank neww in oral once give light to the emit e country movement and the volgnie of tiade.
A-■■■■■fact of the highest interest is disclosed in the assurance that clearance of news so preeL ' a far-reat hiug has *cr ae possible. Th discovery, for it amounts to that, is that the banks of the country ar coming to be a single, intern elated g stem. I k ogress to a workin unity, in the case of the banks, results from the further conquest of disj-tauce, following in this the analogy, of the letter-carrying business, as it was only by gradual steps that all letters came to be transmitted through the centers of a single post-office.	j
The function of the banks in commerce is to conduct the system of payments. Their efficiency turns upon the degree of integrity or certainty of payment which is attained, Upon the mobility or ease of payment, and upon the wisdom displayed in regulating or governing the system, the practical resultant being equally dependent upon each of these three qualities. But for the presence of an exact standard of payment in the gold unit, the Clearing House returns could not be added together, while the modern banking system would be impossible but fof the ease with which debts are paid by set-off through clearing centers The problem of bank regulation or government is encountered whenevejs area or extension has to be provided for
The important thing is to determine the actual state of the America^ banking system, but the inquiry must proceed in the light of all the pas In defining credit, money, and the bank or clearing center, each has t be placed in exact relation to the other two. Credit is the thing dealt i by the banks; it is their commodity. A l^an is an advance of credit, t be made good whenever called upon or on a day named. Money, what| ever the form it may take, is the instrument for transferring credit. Th| business of the banker is to register and certify credits—of corporations of trading firms, of single individuals. A credit is immediately available! means; the English courts decided a number of years ago that a bank| deposit, subject to check, is “ready money/' The bank or clearing-house  is the regulating center in the Credit System.	|
In a late address Secretary-of-the-Treasury Gage made the state4 ment that “credit, with its multiform instruments, is the real money o commerce/' “It is created as transfers of goods and wares take place.’
Had the necessity^of distinguishing money as the instrument of transfer occurred to Mr, Gage, he would have thereby separated completely the tangle of shanking literature, while introducing us to the Credit System, which is the monetary or accounting division of commerce, embracing in^its circle of action the remotest bookkeeper The Credit System comprises all the agencies directly engaged in registering or certifying credits and hi adjusting payments. Men of business pay-their debts with their credits, since no other means of payment exist. Every purchase or sale involves the transfer of a debt or credit, the accounting thereof being in terms of money-—the universal language of value.
Money has to be defined with direct reference to its function, which lias not changed since gold was first coined at Aegina. In the progress of commerce gold came to be, after subjection to trustworthy coinage, a universal certificate of credit; a gold coin conveys a credit fact. The only possible use of a gold coin as such is eitherj to open or close an account Men had to conceive clearly of debt and Credit before the need of devices for transferring them.
A primitive certificate of credit is seen in the “store order” given by a farmer to his workman; it is good at one place only. In it the farm hand possesses a credit, and the fanner has discharged a debt, while the order functions as money just so far as it is tramfrrable. Progress from this to the gold coin, which is good at all stores, everywhere, was a change in degree but not in kind, as the gold coin is still a “store order.”
d lie owner of a gold coin, or a bank deposit, is a creditor of the entire community; either certifies that lie has rendered a service to some one of its members. I he books of the New York savings banks show an indebtedness of 'society to their depositors; the savings banks aid in keeping the score; they are one agency of the Credit System.
Interest is payment for the maintenance of the Credit System. The lower interest charge, whose cause men are just now seeking, is due to an increased registration of credits at the banking centers, and to a decrease in risk, owing to improved banking methods.
With the introduction of secure means of certification, such as gold and silver coin, exchangeable credits began to; accumulate at trading centers in the hands of particular individuals, and in time men made a business of dealing in credit or of lending money. The traffic in credit rose in importance and dignity with the extension of trade and the growing necessity of a distinct system for effecting commercial payments. Some men accumulate titles to lands and houses, while others serve the community by storing up credits. The process has continued until now7, when, under more perfect communication, the bank emerges as center of registration for the credits of the whole community. The direction of the Credit System is the banker’s division of labor in the State; he functions as governing center of the moving commerce. The credit of each individual in the community is registered and determined at the banking center. The bank registers credits just as land titles are recorded at the Register of Deeds office.
The arrival of a single standard in the gold unit is the central fact in the growth of integrity or certainty of payment. The use of gold moved parallel with the conquest of distance, becoming a necessity as transportation grew7 and extended itself, until with the incoming of the bill of exchange and the bank, the need of gold began to lessen. It was thus that the way was prepared for the adoption of a given weight of gold as unit of calculation for the entire system of payment, whatever the instrument of transfer.
The necessity of a single standard of payment was first; touched upon by English writers about 1690; the date marks the dawm of modern bank-
iiig liiethods. Commerce was then taking on a larger meaning; conditions had ripened lor the appearance of new unities. Th-- post-office, seen as a single administrative system, was coming clearly to view, and altogether commerce had begun to find its way to its own integrity, to its Own organs of regulation. By the middle of the eighteenth century the more convenient gold had gained the preference over silver, the century’s outcome being that England fixed upon the gold standard in i8l6, through giving registration by act of Parliament to the previous edict of commerce. Since then the gold standard has been steadily universalizing as a necessary basis for carrying forward the organization of the Credit System.
Mobility or ease of payment scored a great advance when the sale or transfer of debts became a legal right. The advance had its grounding in the systematic bookkeeping which was given to commerce by the Romans. The recording of debts assured, creditors conceived of selling their claims, as against their debtors, and in time the paying of debts with other debts or credits became customary; at the outset, the consent of tlie debtor had to be secured. The principle of compensation* oi*
was a tortuous road, therefore, to the present deposit-and-check develof rnent in banking, which stands for- the larges! freedom in the sale an
The sale of debts, < >r rights < «f action, fully accorded, t he t urtlier d< velopment of the Credit S \ stem i timed up«>n the widening use of tl bill of exchange, and the rise of the bank as a general accounting cent! for all the transactions of commerce. Bui means of com mu meat ion ha to be extended greatly before banks c, >uld venture upon discountin commercial bills, while a further advance in conditions was required lx fore the modern deposit-and-check system could begin forming. a j The goldsmith bankers at London are credited with, the first dist counting of commercial paper as a distinct feature of banking; it is aJt least certain that the innovation received a great extension at their hands!. It took place toward the close of the seventeenth century, when the seat off empire of commerce was moving from the Dutch cities of Antwerp and Amsterdam to London.	j*
To discount bills of exchange and give bank credits therefor was a far-reaching development; it was a vast addition to the efficiency of the Credit System. Under its stimulus progress was soon made to the conh ception of a bank, as standing for an aggregation of individuals and repj-resenting their combined credits or capital.	*	#	j
The incoming of the Bank of England in 1694 marks the first syaj-' tematic use on a large scale of bank bills or notes. Once the discounting of commercial billsfivas entered upon by bankers; the transition was ea to issuing bills of their own, and so the “bank of circulation” aro<
were called “promissory notes, payable on demand,” but gradually th came to be known as bank-notes simply. At the start the notes of t goldsmith bankers were written out on ordinary paper, the printed engraved form being of a later date.
The bank cheek passed into considerable use at the same time, but 1 long they were no more than orders for the payment of coin, or bills particular individuals. Following is a sample:
“London, 16th November, 1689. “Mr. Jackson,—Pray pay to the bearer hereof, Mr. David Croke five pounds, and place it to the account of,
set-off, so commonplace now, was only le N il /ed auer a struggle. If
transfer of debts.
For some time in public documents the bills of The Bank of Englai
Your loving friend, JOHN WYNYARDE.”
At the founding ofhthe Bank of England the issuing of demand notes for general circulation was EAl f o he the chief function of a bank. The'check was not understood, and A to was hardly a suspicion of the ■ banker's real-function in registering and certifying individual credit. The great convenience of drawing a check to order, as means to facilitating the transfer of bank credit, Had not then been, grasped, nor could it be until the deposits should reach large dimensions.
The disclosure enables us to understand the relative position at the time of the bank-note and the bank-cheek. The point is charged with meaning, as it is chiefly through noting the successive changes inythe .instruments for transferring credit that we are able to trace the evolution of the (.iredit S\Oew
The check was hvffi ,n alley an ce in English backing till the close of dir last eentun, notwithstanding the erection of: a clearing-house at London in 1775. Adam Smith, who on5dished the (“Wealth of Nations” in 1770, seal rely mentions the check when discussing hank integrity, his attention being chief!v dip^o-d to safeguards against the overissue of bank-notes.
. In :1.70b the Emuloji baiTrws as a class discontinued the issuing of demand- noum ;md - fell in w ii.li t u <' growing preference of their customers for the rheA a. a m< »rc m vrn lent. a 1 k! safer instrument for making hausfem of rrclit. 1 lie e v-em ion of the' check,, along with a convsjHaiding ngglec; « d ba”! 1 ai 11 s, continued until about 1830, when the main profits A banks in England no longer turned upon the circulation of their own notes,
(.naming to America, 0 appears from the Treasury returns that it was
not till 1855 lh<ot die aeti a deposits of the banks of the United States, taken in the aggregate, owe above their note circulation. Thereafter,
lx.Ph in .England and hug the rapid increase in hank deposits and the
growing use of the check, furnish the key to understanding the further v, development of tin* banking business.
The change fr< .m bank-notes or 1 dlls to the check is one with progress toward the appearamv • n the bank as center of registration for all credits, in 18(><> the capital acmuni of the Clearing House:banks of New York eitv waas $69,758,000, and the number of hanks 64. The deposits in i860 were $106,382,000. The same group of banks in December, 1898, had $823,000,000 of deposits, and a capital of $58,272,000. It should be said that the statement of December 24, 1898, credits them with, a surplus of ■ $757°5>°oo.
The probable- further development of the deposit-and-check system, under the conditions peculiar to America, is of absorbing interest. The 'facts show that the tendency is to unite the bank’s credit with that of
the individual in a single check. The new thing here is the express “order” and the acceptance it lias gained. The new “money orders” are widely sold in quantities where need exists for certified checks. The action is equivalent to certifying the check-book for individual use. It is fair to say that each express offi.ee so acting is in effect a bank of issue.
As covering the United States and Canada, the express order is at least suggestive of a universal paper instrument for transferring credit; it is paid everywhere by set-off through the bank clearing houses. The express companies are beginning to receive deposits. They solve the collection of “personal checks” by meeting the demand for a universal check. The express people are operating through some 25,000 offices.
There remains the supreme question of bank regulation, which is seen in a new light under American conditions. Modern banking is the organic development of credit and of clearing. The difficulty of bank regulation from Washington increases just in proportion as the deposit-
and-check system-obtains, until with more rapid growth in deposits bank government from Washington as a single center is becoming fairly unthinkable. Since proprietary control, as exemplified in the Bank! of France, is impossible here, the alternative is self-regulation through the Clearing Houses.
The possession of the clearing privilege in the banking system is power. As one hand: cannot get to the other save through the brain center, so one bank can only compass the trading circle through the: clearing house. The bank at Harlem touches the National Bank of NArth America through the Hearing renter in Cedar street.
Going further, it is seen that, b\ means of the clearing system, the i banks of the country are in organic in Htion with each, other, which means j that each center is connected at nine' with all Hhcr centers. The ppwer | which lias come to resuF in the Henrmg-F ><or pri\ ilege is such that tp-j day the vitality of the Hinted States got ofHv nsmev-order is dependent [ on its being allowed to clear through Hr Hub- mg eentrrs. The excels-| sion of power on the side of the ]kmh (’tearing Home is constant. t I	The issuing of Clearing House Hon * ertif'u ates at important junje-
J tores from :186c) to 1893 is the signal illustr non of self regulation through :	the clearing house. :! When toiiridden by the statutes to continue dis-
counting, the banks1 have kept on under authority from the Clearilg House, which speaks for the hanking system. A new governing uni|:y intervened.	i	!
Facts alamin! on all sides which show that the regulation of American banking is proceeding through its own centers, or Clearing Houses. Besides, a representative system lias been forming through the American Bankers’ Association and the local bodies.
It is no longer possible to inquire profitably into the state of American banking', save through perceiving the advancing unity of the system. 11 is on account of this fact that the fullest investigation is now needed.
FRANKLIN FORD. j
January 3, 1899.
■
Mr. Seymour Dexter is President of the Second National Bank af Elmira. In his address as President of the New York State Banke ;s’ Association, in 1897, Mr, Dexter had this to say:
“With the changed conditions, banks occupy a very different plat re in the social body from what they did before the era of rapid communication, transportation, and centralization in commercial and industrial activities. As related to the social body, they are no longer merel^jjla place for the safe keeping of money which persons are afraid to ke|p about their persons or their homes, and a place to borrow money good security when they have need. They are that now; but very mu more at the same time. .	.	. Banks are the very heart in the circu
tion in the social organism.”