FORDS
68 Broad Street, New York
'. .-FRANKLIN FORD, Director ‘
Bank NewsBulletin No. 2.
THE EXPRESS COMPANIES AND THE BANKS.
(Copyright.)
11 ic trouble tit main centers over the Hood of country checks, the. growing use of express “orders,” and the effect on the money market of currency shipments to “move the crops,’’ are .incidental to the further development of the deposit system, and a still wider use of the cheekyis-the preferred instrument in transferring 'bank credit.	£
The deposits in the banks of the United States outran their note oir-J dilation about 1855. Since then the check has been steadily coming! Unto general acceptance, along with a corresponding neglect of the bank|
I bill. Between 1855 and, 1885, a period of thirty years, the check came to |be tlie customary and usual medium for paying balances between traders in a given locality. 1 Hiring this period, when making remittances be-; tween centers1, Midfiespeciallv ..when arranging to pay. debts at the me-Trdpolis, tlicTTile was to buy exchange on New York, or, in exceptional A§ses,hdn sonic leading' provincial center, in other words, tile country j trader down to-'about 1885 bought his New- York exchange from tlie local bank, and of course paid for it the customary charges. It is said Uthatfcountry-banks m those times were frequently able to make ordinary ""(expenses from theesale of domestic exchange.
After 1885 a far-reaching change began to come in. I....laving grown
|accustomed to the use of checks for meeting all local demands, the single (individual or trading firm took to sending them to remote towns. The yinovement gradually extended itself, until it has come to pass that every-afibody who has a bank account anywhere is Insisting upon sending his ■...(.check everywhere.
i. It ds nearly ten .years since New York bankers woke, up to find 1 themselves in daily receipt, of a huge volume of country checks. The .^movement has increased until now, when some twelve million dollars w:br more of checks drawn on local banks throughout the country are fidally deposited by tlpe merchants of New York in their respective banks. ;NThe causes which have led to this are still operating, and the receipt of 'Nmerelygpersonal cheeks is certain to increase until mn adequate remedy u Is provided.
One effect has Teen to transfer the cost of domestic exchange, soj Tar as the habit indicated is followed, from the remitters (where it proper-! : Ty belongs) to the Tanks and merchants at the main centers. When a 1 country bank receives for collection a check on itself,: which has been iNsent to New Yorkfior some other center by one of its depositors, an Taverage deduction of one-tenth of one per cent, is made ; in other words, Nthedocal: banks,.exact, a charge for the payment of checks: drawn on therm ATelvesYgThe TM	have	sought	to	makefile	receivers	of
Ngcount^	cost of collection, but, in spite of .all-efforts,-more
..■ Than threeTouA|ff|TTthe. expense is now borne by the banks.
lids a sliipfffehUof paper throughout. The country debtor remits
his personal chetk,! and when it is returned for collection the bankf-on
'which it is drawn sends m payment itmdraft on New York/'Chicago, or other center. The movement as a wholeYuggests a further development in the use of; the paper instrument for transferring bank credit, which, as tilings stand, is only partially attained.
The personal check is sent to New York or Chicago, only to come back over the same path with a demand for payment in another paper instrument, namely, a bank draft on New York or Chicago. This double movement is required before actual payment is held to have been made.
'Against this the express companies have introduced a plan whereby payment at remote points is effected in one movement, and a single paper instrument, which the remitter is enabled to issue from his own office when wanted, just as he does his personal check. In short, the express people arc certifying the check-books of traders through the sale of their money orders in hulk, the users signing as agent.
The American Express Company, in. particular, is now selling its orders throughout its held for the use of commission merchants and others who have frequent need of certified checks. ; The American Express people have in this way brought bank credit; and that of the individual together in a single check ; the action amounts to systematizing the use (if the cashier's check. Each express office so acting is in effect a bank of issue. Commission merchants in Detroit and other cities keep amounts at the American Express bank because of the convenience it afhnds them through being able to get from it certified checks in quantities, to he issued at convenience irorn their own offices, just as personal cheeks or hank are issued. The understanding is that the orders are sold in quantities to merchants at one-third off from Tegular rates.
'flic express companies must lie regarded as banks, so far as their work has to do with the sale and movement of exchange. Moreover, thee are beginning to receive 'deposts, being compelled to do this by the sale' of orders in bulk. They are an integral part of the banking system.
The general problem that Is demanding solution looks to finding the most convenient and inexpensive' manner of shipping hank credit. The example of the express companies in selling their orders in quantities, lo be signed and issued at the pleasure of the buyers, suggests, at least, the incoming of a universal paper certificate of value. The express people solve the collection of personal checks by meeting the demand for a universal check.
The notion of collecting an express order has now quite left it; they are paid by set-off through the clearing centers of the banking system. About $150,000 of express orders are now passed daily through the New York Clearing House; The average size of these orders is not far from ten dollars, so that 15,000 pieces of express paper are handled each day at the Clearing House. The bank clearing houses of the country pay the universal express draft, but the banks proper are without such draft of tit eir own. The banks pay the express companies for shipping currency, but make no charge for handling their orders at the clearing centers.
The local or personal check when received at main centers is sent to the point of origin as quickly as possible in order to hasten collection, but the very contrary is true of the express draft. Until a local check is paid, the forwarding bank is not in possession of actual value on account thereof. The force of the express order is not hurt or lessened by the time element; each order is in effect so much New York exchange; the longer it remains out, the greater the number of debts that will be paid by it.
The twelve express companies of the country, inclusive of the Canadian lines, act as a unity with reference to dealing in exchange through
the sale of express orders. Any one of them stands ready to pay the orders of all the others at the Clearing Houses of the banking system. Telegraphic transfers of credit are made bv and between the twenty-five thousand offices which the express system of the country maintains.
Through the sale of orders in quantities, to be used in the manner indicated, the express people meet the demands of merchants who have need to use certified checks widely. aBv supplying a universal draft at low cost they lessen the movement of personal checks. The “ travellers check” has been introduced, and is sold to merchants for tire use of their salesmen when moving from town to town remote from headquarters.
There is no record of any successful attempt at raising an express order.
Nothing has been done by the express companies to bring either the order or the traveller’s check to bear upon the problem of shipping bank credit to “move the crops,” yet the check-books of the crop-movers are as much in need of certification as those of the commission merchants. As indicated, the express order, the country cheeky and the ^disturbances due to currency shipments, are all phases of one problem. f
The express companies have struck out an advance in the orgamza] tion of the Credit System. Their work abounds in lessons for th masters of banking. It is worth noting that the American Expresl Company is successfully marketing their travellers check for use in aljl parts of the commercial world, foreshadowing in this wav universal recognition for the American Check.
The express order hasrn signal advantage over the post-office-;ordeil owing to the fact that the latter is only negotiable at the town or postf office on which it is drawn. The express order is equally good wheiji presented at any center, and is everywhere regarded as New York ex} change.	!
„	.	...	.	i
When the post-office., order was introduced in 1864, the aim was tcj> keep the system entirely distinct from the banking movement; postmasters were '‘prohibited from depositing money-order funds in any bank.” So late as i8()p Postmaster-General Wanamaker spoke of the order as “a means .of remitting small sums without interfering witlji vested banking interests.” Yet the post-office people have been com} pelled during recent years to give it the form and character of a banker’s draft; and to-day the postal order would be shorn of its vitality were it not to havd free movement through the bank clearing houses.	f.
The daily receipt of postal orders at New York is $50,000.* O 1 these, one-half are paid by set-off through the Clearing House, the Chas National Bank acting as clearing agent. Of the remainder, $15,000 arl paid by check to a few large receivers of orders, so that, only $10,000 ar paid by tellers at the post-office, and the latter item is constantly d creasing. At all leading centers the post-office pays its orders throng! the local clearing house, and the movement is extending; just recentl at Toledo the local post-office became a member of the clearing hous The New York banks handle postal orders as low as twenty-five cent in value.
These facts are cited to show the growing dependence of all seller!! of exchange on the clearing privilege. In 1897 the total sales of posta orders were $175,000,000, the average value for the year being $6.93. A last accounts the total sales of express orders and travellers (checks wet something like one-half those of the post-office.
It appears that in the progress of the clearing principle the post office and express orders for the payment of “money” have themselve come to function as money, or instruments for the direct transfer o credit, being paid by set-off at the clearing centers; in other words, thl
daily claims against the express companies at thefNew iXorkcCleafingt House are met by them , with checks on their respective banks. A profound change is indicated Payment by set-off has now progressed so far that it is to be seen as the typical action in banking, giving to the bank its definition. Banks register and certify credits, and conduct the payments of commerce through set-off or clearing. ■ Any bank, therefore, is -;KHf a clearing hoiw< , dir ig" which debts are paid with .credits. The New York Cbm mg Horn, acts as a mam center dor numerous lesser banks or clearing centers, and, m fact, for the whole country. The Cedar Street institution in New York is the National Clearing House.
With the deposits in the New York banks doubling every ten years, it is not possible to hold longer to a narrow view of the banking function. At one time it was thought to be “a liberal expansion’’ for a bank ‘do loan two-and-a half t lines the amount of its capital.A Owing'to the rapid advances in registering credits, the shareholders of a bank are coming to be seen simple a - its first dep<wit;ors. To-day the individual depositor, in place of Inning -i bill from tlw I sunk, is every wli ere insisting upon making Ins personal cbvf serve as a bill of exchange. The action is already so far-reaciring' that die union of bank' credit and that of the individual in one check is presented as one solution of the. problem. Here is the Am .erica n Express Nwnpanv advertising that its travellers check “is practically a certiFn I dieck, payable to one’s own order,” and that the checks “are virtually a uni versa! currency.”
As heanur on the solution demanded, the work of the (leorgia banks
■ ;	<	■	f	...	,t	_
in providing what thev call a “circular cheek” is in point, and will repay investigation.
The 'right solution of Hie country check problem cannot fail at the same time to correct the disturbances in the money miarket resulting from
shipping currency to ” move the crops.” While the depositors in country banks arc* sending their personal checks to the main centers to the extent of millions of dollars each dag, the franks are compelled to ship currency to the interior.
Progress is constant toward increasing ease of payment, and the appearance of the country cheek in great numbers at main centers bears every indication that an advance m banking organization is not far away.
ddic effect- of impn..wed facilities of communication has outrun frank
regulation.
A demand has arisen for special clearing centers, through which the country checks can Ire paid. It is based on the fact that paper of this order does not move at par. There is* no demand for special clearing machinery in the case of the post-office and express orders, and for the reason that they both move at par through the clearing centers already in existence.
The right solution of these important matters is bound up with the question of frank revenues. As things stand, the banks are paid in the shape of interest for making advances of credit through discounts or loans, but not, save infrequently, for credit certifications. Owing to the larger and larger registration of credit, the rate of interest is everywhere declining, thus forcing the revenue problem to the fore. Now, the post-office and the express companies are receiving pay for CERTIFYING credit; they sell credit certificates, which go everywhere at par. At one time, as already noted, the country banks derived considerable revenue through the sale of exchange, or credit certifications, but this has in the main been taken from them. .
It remains to be asked whether the banks as a class are not; now compelled to get pay for their primary work of registering and: certifying
credit. The general bookeeping otT Commerce is in the hands of the banks, but for this service they are not paid.
The personal check is the quickest-means of transferring bank credit,
and is therefore the readiest money. The possession of a check-book is quasi evidence that one has a bank account, but the bank’s■;certificate has to be added before the evidence is conclusive. When the bank credit and that of the individual;are united in one instrument, the result is a valid order for goods—that is to say, it is money. The personal check by itself simply is no more than a debt, subject to collection; it does not carry the authority of the bank.
From this it appears that the first need in dealing with the country check problem is to distinguish the checks clearly as debts. Bank credit in all its forms moves freely through the clearing centers, and is paid by set-off when reaching the point of origin. Personal checks are taken at par in the localities where drawn. The determining influence is the time
In England the country check is cleared through supplementary machinery at the I.ondon Clearing House, because all the English banks, liarring a few remote exceptions, are within one night’s mail of London. Each bank lias a clearing agent at London, and the entire area is oared for in a single movement. It is a matter of twenty-four hours or l|\ss, instead of one or two hours, as in the case of local checks.
| it: lias been proposed to divide the area over which the American flanking system extends ihto districts for the clearing of country checks; But the difficulty here is that checks drawn in one district may be sent to all other districts, and especially to the main centers. The difficulty is extreme, owing to the variation in the time element,
j
A radical solution is compelled by the increasing need of economy in hauls management. The initiative on one side has passed to the individuals who are in possession of bank accounts and check-books, and who are insisting upon making transfers, however remote the point of payment, by direct issues from their own offices.
[The remedy lies between a chain of district clearing houses for country checks, where checks from main centers would be sent for collection, and a refusal of all recognition at main centers for country checks, save so far as they are authorized by the home bank, which means the certification of the check-book, as the express companies are already doing. In either case, the outlook is toward a more commanding unity, a further reach in self-regulation, for the American banking system.	‘
To sum up: At one time remittances to remote points were of necessity made in gold, as ijnder early conditions nothing else would have had recognition among strangers. Afterwards gold and silver coins came to be' deposited in bank, and certificates issued therefor were used in making payments over wide areas. At a later date bank bills, which were issued without direct reference to deposits of gold and silver, found shipment here and there as a means of effecting commercial payments. Subsequently, the bank check rose and grew into the customary medium of payment between local centers. Until now, for the most part, the personal check and the banker’s draft have been used separately. .But it now appears, as already shown, that the express companies, both in their “money order ” and the “ travellers check,” are uniting bank credit and that of the individual in a single instrument. Moreover, they 'are doing this on so large a scale that it is of importance for the masters of banking to take strict account of the movement.
FRANKLIN FORD.
Februarv 8, iSqq.