FORD
A
CTDTTRAL HKWS
re\’t ’/orlc.
STAFF OF FAiTRTr
RATE	of Tm'-’ii
mere	■Q today
f the	rate of
s in b	ranking
Tbe to	CD ■ O o j—1 CD
A >bO A
.The imporant tliIng in American c real state of banking and the future o is t tep s t age of o om * yam i c at 1 o n .
■The tact is reveaied. fhat Dro^aes points jY/itix growch in coiuimuiicat 1 on Americ4 wife re freed conditions exist) o full, and of necessity realises in prac
the -.business.	_	f
■Tge effect must bo to reduce interest to a nominal; ratej- of o .cent oil less, and to made the rate root harm lor the who 1 e cou|:itry * ■hath ot interest follows the analoay of she rate oi po stage; jy grovn c;GKirnun:|cation reduces cott in both cases .
order do understand dearie the nature ol: banking; ana
The 1’
ies bank organization to s the underlying urine In 1!
f Tile nee of the telephoned* a recital, c Money was introduced as means m man five dollars is to authorize him to and stay there for a day; this fact is Money, therefore, whatever its drm, d transfers a right.
The possession of money certifies one?s credit
:n
rj
fact
the in p i n t '*
I v a a
certain fact * osisi.r n i c a u inr
n t o t J; e l'! .1 f t h Av e r!uo f’ ot e .1 ortveyed by trie m.oriely -he has 1 c ;•a j. -I d e a;	1.1 c d r t i f i e s
Plato uyucl to
told was only needed when
S3
for use among st ahi oh v/a
nrroars,
I sue in
Among them gold alone would certify one ' s cren.xr, the time	of Plato.	r
The 'word CREDIT is used just as the bookkeeper uses^ it 1 In the books of an accountant one trader has a credit as against the de bit another trader. The bank has now appeared as ^ the general bonkkeepei. commerce* A credit at the bank, therefore, is a claim against the whole communityr The work of the bank is to register and .certify tr
credits of the people .
Money, whether is the form of gold coin or bank chepk, lls the x strument for transferring credit. The tendency has been cdjnstant toward the readiest tool for transferring credit, down to tpp bank check which makes its own change,	I 1
The	business	of banking	is	the	accounting	division	of	Jpmmerce;
the bank	conducts	the system	of	payments.	The	bank	is	one	sp.de	of	v
organization of acience or news; a gold coin or bank check jtransml' a. credit	fact „	§
The distinction between money and credits has to be kept! in .min;.
It
s the universe
Credit is bought and sold at the banks;
Money is used, to transfer credit.
The Issuing of money is an act of authority, as witnesif
common:
the
"Money is a function of government, ” On the side of metallic
2-
t he bus ines c e u t1 f
0 V	0 "	r co	ining	money a		lame to	be
al	j r- -3	min	ts .				
	' j'	h o c	e r t i i	i c	at ion	and tra'	n s i
t r	UA6'	nt s	has c	on	e to i	che full	i ‘
0	t he	i	i i ng	of	111 Cl I. ’	-' -L aii oi 1 a	
r g	an i	G ; -	CD	o r	that	of perf	e g
hi	n g	t, 0 y e	I l in r	w i	b il P 0 .	ference	to
	T	lie b	ank c	: 1 e	ar J u'~	house I	s
lO t-	o pin	i n al-	ion e	,f	a cue	- it bv a	T->
, ... m in u	ure	as	t h e c	i o i.	V\ 1 1-1 o- ,	f gold	b y
■at	. e i	s th	,e new	-I .JL	Q fr ;:i _ i	lender b	e c
00 s	, i ne	o s .	'The	- P o	wer ii	as passe	d
d with particular individuals whose stamp '
-f n mioCe of gold or silver. Afterwards the entralized through institutions
the value or a piece of
ismission of credit through paper inti the banking system of America, Owing ion American banking has reached the t mobility, with all its parts cooper-a-common end. public authority in money matters. The ank is a government act of the same the mint. The clearing-house certifi-ause it is accepted as a necessity of to tlie clearing-house because it knows
the business
Interest is t e n a n c e o f t h e ( 'Hie, "money-blend* that farmer who ually the bank ; ter becomes the by means of the The cost o
cnar
r
arid,
r
3rtifping credit; it is for the maIrish is one with the system of banking.
i s,(o certifies the credit of this or hii oh to busy cattle and horses* Grad-full communi cat ion, the banking ceil-' credit and the sole issuer of money
just in prop	or tie	n as bank
banker finds	hims	e1f in eas
The inc	oming	cm a now
false notpon	fc i ia I	,the safet
creditr or the rate of interest, runs down organization becomes' more .effective and the y command of the credit-making fact. and uniform interest rate is retarded by the v of the deposit-and-check system of bank-
ing is dependent on be in system. A sufficient and co calculation as without it th of the gold unit is
us
o~ called le? The soundn*
tied in a mechanical way to the gold coinage inning tie exists in the gold unit of bank clearings could not be added togetInhabit of mind which exists independently
slation
3S 0
f th*
ml
eposit-and-
the integrity of each transaction
ieck or paper system turns upon ui-ansacoover the bank counter. The gold in his vaults does not aid a banker in appraising the shares of American Steel and Aire., Instead, the problem is one of credit reporting.
The rapid growth in deposits is compelling American bankers to find safety by organizing all sources of credit information; the gaze is away frorn the gold reserve.
w.The notion ghat the supply of money is limited still prevails and this helps to keep up the rate of interest. It is a survival from the time when a single governing center, or a single bank, was the sole ‘ssuer of money. Today the money supply is issued by the individual hrough his check-book under authority from the bank, and the supply oi loney constantly equals the moving-volume of credit. Each acceptance
of a deposit permits a new issue of money through the cheeky Owinh^to growth in: comniunication? the bank or governing center and. the individual co-operate in the one operation,
In this way a revolution in the point of view is rained, A bank * does not lend its capital when certifying the credit of "its customer^ The possession of capital by the organizers of a bank	'Prove	°	’
their competency to certify the credits of others, The^redits bed onr to the individual customers in all cases* The bank acts "as 'ornter op" authority,and provides a check-book for transferring its certif1 eat Urn* f o.-redi t The applicant for a bank credit on the^bar ^	^	A'i/i"	UA'~'M
.toclt is not "borrowirs money." T]f ^k^gMaMfge' he A hi
is of Standard
g
red.it
deal'
hate of Interest true
of credit Oil
some down from the early history of the	l;s	,or crec|.	whpn
applications for "loans” came for the most part from peo-Dl g g 'g strc as It is tmt a part:;.al analysis to suppose that |.j,9	..
is upon the sup piy of capital „ Jot is, of cor];
”cheap money*5 cannot obtain -without a great [banks; to do, A low rate of interest, or cha>
[it, is the product of a perfec11 y org-o1.i ze0, i c end it ions un d e f wh ich Amer i c an b a 11j \ :i n g !:' g < oomde1ling a clear departure from the oustomary i kindred poilits . Ting 1 And was first in reach111f of infroiwBfr. America is to lead, in a corres] rate; of interest.
of
however, ;ert i fvi.ng
for
cl
kcl
CT 0	for cj	>rtifyin	O'	
ank	i n f; s |	citem .	if	'•
d e	vAIo]:i	?c(. are r	) :	t
h i :n	kitip: 1	on this	r i	d
1 OVv	an,rJ |	mi it.) rm	I" O	t e
Ann	n e • J	rtion n f	t	lie
May
O /I
1900
.,
Franklin k
o rd