Franklin Ford Tells Why a Clearing House of Facts Would Be of Inestimable Value.
To the Editor of the Brooklyn Engle:
The letter of Mr. Samuel tl. Bishop in your Issue of June 4 supports my contention that the reform in city government of which wa hear so much, necessarily Involves the definite and systematic organization of municipal Information or news.	Mr. Bishop
sees no danger "in concentering power at tho City Hall" if means are provided whereby tho people of every section may "know what they want and know how to convoy what they want to the City HB}|.,•
The end marked out will be reached by giving to the existing news system a responsible center through which the facts can bo co-ordinated and so transformed inlo a governing force.	Municipal	betterment,
therefore, is a question of commercial organization; it is as far removed as possible from the plaints of reformers who have no remedy to propose hoyond the defeat of one party and the substitution of another.
The new center would report eltv business as a whole, and In all Its parts: it would become the clearing house Tor all municipal facts.
The conduct of city affairs must be confused and wasteful in the absence of n comprehensive system of reporting and of central registration. Until all the facts are accessible at some one point the various divisions of the city government can hove nn clcor understanding of each other and no adequate working relation.
The true rc-formatiaa of city affairs must be based on a scientific and full organization of municipal news. In contrast with this or that propaganda of opinion.
In the telephone, or instantaneous communication, the modern press, and the fast mall train, the newspaper has come to possess a perfect working machine. Prior to those conditions news organization could not on the whole be more than nominal, but It can now be made actual and responsible on all sides. The method of journalism is to become scientific in all particulars. The news traffic involves la Its sweep the entire organization of intelligence from the university center to the remotest social happening.
The news system consists of the dolly paper, tho trade or class journal, and the buroau of Information. In Srs outworking the reporting system will connect with all sources of expert knowledge, and with every Individual In the community as any one may at time* possess a fact of value to his neighbor, to his class or to the people as a whole. But the dolly newspaper is center of action.
The proposrfl organization of municipal new* Involves the closest co-operation between the various organs of the system. As now. the different parts of the news system do not buy and sell of each other save very incidentally. It is a singular thing that when a new fact is disclosed In tho news movement It carries three possible sales or profits; Its general meaning to bo distributed through the dally paper. Its class bearing to be cold through the trade paper, and Its value to particular Individuals which they can obtain at the bureau of information. The dealred co-operation will be reached through division of labor and the freedom of action which the telephone permits.
Tho new center will be called the City Nows Office. It will act as a common medium for the exchange of all Information having a direct bearing upon the regulation of city affairs, doing In this respect what the Ship Nntra Office docs In Us field and with equal precision. The City Sews Office will bring the municipal facts of Chicago, London and Berlin side by side with those of New York. At the same time the facts of New York’a government will become accessible to the world, and the natural demand for authentic news In this field will be met.
Through gaining a common center all the parts of the city's news syBtem will be at the service of every citizen: without this It lo much In the condition that the telephone system would Ik* were there no main center connecting all together The town Is replete with useful bureauK of Information which will become available through the City News Office.	.	_	„
As Mr. Bishop writes from the Brooklyn Bureau of Charities, of which he Is assistant sccretnrv. I am led to point out the Inevitable effect of a scientific nows renter on the Important matter of charity regulation. The Charity Organization Society of Manhattan was Instituted eighteen years ago. It was Intended "to be a center of intercommunication between the various churches anti charitable agencies In the city. To foster harmonious co-operation between them," and to "promote the general welfare of the poor by social and sanitary reforms." It was to be a clearing house for the city’s charity system.
dregt eood ha? been accomplished hv the Charity Organization Society and Its Brooklyn nllv. the Bureau of Charities, but the reruns are small In comparison with the benefits that would follow the Incoming of. a responsible general center for Ihe city’s news system. Such n renter would Invite and In fact compel from the charily now* center in great efficiency In clearing that the utmost of wise, governmpnt would he nauurefl.
Tills lesson from the field of charity regulation goes m make plain that the nne road to cltv government reform Is through the ays-lematic handling of municipal science or n<u»*.	FRANKLIN FORD.
City Club. Manhattan. June 8, 1901.