— — _ ' — , -	_	—	-	-	r	■
Letters to the Editor of
(CONTINUED.)
The Times
THE COURTS AND STRIKES.
To the	Editor of The Xcto York Times:
Tour articles on the coal strike are truly critical, while fairly impartial. Your endeavor is to report the inside in place of filling’ your columns with 44 both sides.” This is especially true of your editorial in to-day’s issue, which deals with the idea of ownership and its real meaning.
Property is propriety! Had Proudhon said this without going further he would have escaped the police, but the world would have refused him attention. Yet his real point, as shown in the course of his writings, was that property is, or should be, propriety.
In operation the idea of property presents two antagonistic elements, use and abuse. The movement of social organization, with the growth of science and exact business methods, is inevitably in the direction of increasing the use and lessening the abuse. It is so important that the rightful owner,
that is, the individual best fitted to develop use, should remain in secure possession of a given piece of property, that society endures all manner of incidental or minor abuses in order that the maximum use may obtain. But, in spite of all misconduct, the general tendency is toward the highest use. A Judge of Probate, of long experience on the bench in a Western State, has told me that during the last thirty years the courts have shown an increasing disposition to take property from the hands of a profligate or drunkard on a. less showing of fact than in previous years. In short, the social necessity of right usage has been encroaching on the area of abuse.
The doctrine to which you give emphasis, namely, that the control of any and all kinds of property may be forfeited through a certain degree of abuse, varying with circumstances and conditions, can be found easily by President Baer of the Reading Railroad in the leading decisions of the courts on the law of property. The recognition of a merely arbitrary will has no place in the decisions.
It seems to me that the quick adjustment of strikes, or, better, their entire abolition, is necessitating a large extension of the equity jurisdiction of the courts. In fact, it is already taking place in the. current injunctions against acts of violence or wrongful interference on the part of strikers. Is it not strange that the labor men or their representatives do not perceive that the
line of progress is to demand that the courts take account of all the facts in each case that exact justice may be done to all concerned? This outcome is inevitable. Wrere a compulsory arbiti’ation law to be enacted by the Pennsylvania Legislature, its interpretation would have to be left t& the courts, Which, under our system of government, are charged with the last word. We are living under ” government by injunction.”
In the coal region to-day two arbitrary wills are confronting each other, with no court accessible to determine the conflicting claims. The whole course of social organization is to get rid of the merely arbitrary ' will' attd to substitute therefor the reign of science.
A word about Mr. A. S. Hewitt's statement. whose superficiality you have de- ! tected. Mr. Hewitt fears that if the strike j is compromised or arbitrated, irresponsible power to decide as to what men shall be ! employed in the mines will pass to John | Mitchell and his associates. As a remedy | he proposes only that the operators shall j be left in possession of a power which is i equally arbitrary, and whose use or abuse | thereof has resulted in the present deadlock, though Mr. Hewitt writes vaguely of remedies through legislation.
The truth of the matter appears to be that the beneficial results of labor unions cannot be realized short of full organization or complete unity with respect to a given union. On the road to this all manner of violence and cruelties occur, but when unity is achieved in fact, with full recognition on the side of capital, the outcome will in all cases contradict Mr. Hewitt’s notion. In practice under such conditions. all men must join the union, but no one of them can stay in it unless he behaves himself. Every man is under efficient dis- j cipline by reason of the positive relations ! with his fellows, and^the effect is a higher morale on all sides. The record shows clear- j ly enough that the coal operators cannot J discipline the miners without the direct co-operation of their own labor leaders.
I have had opportunity to observe closely the working of this principle in two in-stances—the street car men’s union in Detroit and the longshoremen’s union on the * great lakes. In both cases complete unity ? was achieved, and the practical outcome ! was highly beneficial for both men and employers. The longshoremen of the lakes furnish one of the best examples of the advantages of labor organization, so much so, indeed, that Mr. Hewitt would do well to study it. In the case of the Detroit street car men infractions of discipline were tried by a committee of the union in connection with an executive officer of the
road, and with the best results. In effect, a committee of the union became the employing division of the one unified system.
Mr. Hewitt needs to take account of the fact that the labor organizers intend that a trade union shall be something more than a 44 pink tea party.”
FRANKLIN FORD.
New York, Sept. 4, 1002.
JfcUr JJork Simca
Published: September 7, 1902 Copyright © The New York Times