“CREDITS SAFEGUARDED—COLLECTIONS CERTAIN/'
THE CREDIT OFFICE
Credit Reporting
Collection and Adjustment Departments. Accounting and Auditing
(INCORPORATED.)	NEW	YORK	LIFE	BUILDING.
Telephone, 956 Franklin.	346	BROADWAY.
New York, April 25, 1908
Dr. James H. Canfield,
Columbia University.
My dear Doctor Canfield:
Your suggestion as to a dinner some evening soon is capital. It could logically take place any time now, but I should want Edgar L. Marston of Blair & Company, bankers, to be present. Marston has known me for over twenty years. Were we to have the dinner, it should occur at a time when Dr. Woodward is in the city. By the way, Marston is a trustee of Brown University and also of Vassar College.
What I said is true, that I have yet to meet a master of physical science with whom I have not been able to confer profitably in my science, which is Politics. On the other hand, I have rarely been able to talk my subject to the men who are professing social science. Dunbar of Harvard was an exception, as also W. G. Sumner of Yale. What do you suppose Giddings said to me the other day? Why, that the understanding hereabouts is that in spelling out Sociology he is not to intrude upon the field of economics. I did n't say it, but the thought came to me that a parallel decree might be issued to Goetze that in teaching engineering he must keep clear of physics. I fear that some of the compartments are almost air tight. What a field for a humorist!
Really Doctor, we are near to great action. During this last week I have fortunately been able to determine all the main points on the more practical side of the Bank Report. The chief considerations are:
(1)	The necessity which the Credit System is under to move forward
on the basis of the ideal unit (there is no ether), lest thro, an unduly prolonged devotion to the gold fetish there may occur a dead break with the past, the danger being that economic anarchy may result owing to the destruction of the money of account. The inch started	from three	barley-corns, but the abstract inch is more than	that now.	I freely	admit that	the fic-
tion which asserts that all credits are payable in gold has served a useful end, but	the danger	point in	the course	of government is the period of	succession	from one	dynasty to	another.
Fictions have held empires together, but, nevertheless, Charles T. lost his head through insisting on the permanence of a given social classification. The bank deposits of the United States now figure up some twenty thousand millions; rather a tidy sum!
(2) The advance must take place in order to make, through a single or
unified banking system^ the greater end greater credits which the development of industry necessitates.
(3)	The Exchange System must advance as means to a more efficient gov-
ernment for the organs of production.
CREDITS SAFEGUARDED—COLLECTIONS CERTAIN.
THE CREDIT OFFICE
Credit Reporting
Collection and Adjustment Departments. Accounting and Auditing
(INCORPORATED.) Telephone, 956 Frankliiu
NEW YORK LIFE BUILDING.
346 BROADWAY.
New York,
Ihe idea that the charter of The News Office, or main centre, shall establish, through Contract, the title cf the university centre to its rightful share cf the revenues cf the nev/s system is no idle remark; far from it. Nowhere in the world to-day is there a university which is grounded in the science cf Politics. Why should not Columbia University fall heir to this unexampled endowment, inclusive of the material outcome?
You tell rr.e that Dr. Burgess is cold blooded. Well, the spirit of true science is about the nearest thing to a cola-chisel that I know about. My enthusiasm relates only to the business action in hand.
I enclose the paper on Maitland which I gave Burgess. Please return it to me in a day or two through your secretary.
I have to acknowledge that the gratifying progress in my work is largely due to the recognition and eid I have received from you.
Very truly yours
COPY OF A LETTER FROM DR. J. BEATTIE CROZIER, OF LOUD OK, ERG.
TO MR. FRANKLIN FORD.
9, Elgin Avenue, W.f London, Apr. 5, 1908.
Dear Sir:
I must apologize for my great delay In thanking you for your kindness in sending me your aooount of your Clearing House Soheme. I have always felt that it is a very poor oompllment to pay a correspondent to give him a hare acknowledgment of the reoelpt of his letter; and have In oonsequenoe always made It a point to read over what Is sent me before acknowledgment. In this instance I have not had a moment free until now, having had to write against time a series of articles for the "Fortnightly Review."
I am not quite sure whether I clearly and fully grasp your idea, hut I take it to he the beginning of a practical scheme in which I have the greatest possible interest, and one which seems to me to he the next advance, on true lines of evolution, in the economic world.
In my "Wheel of Wealth" which I Imagine has your general approval, (relatively at any rate to the work of the old School of Economists) you may remember that I had figured a number of men standing on the axle of the wheel—|p*eat financiers, industrial magnates, eto.—organized and keeping their eye at once on the production and the consumption side or aspeot of it, so as to make these two sides keep time with each other, as it were, and bo steady the pace and revolution of the wheel as a whole.
Row, if I understand you rightly, your scheme consists precisely in the organizing of these bodies of men:- the financiers through a universal system of inter-oonnected clearing houses, with a oommon oentre whloh shall keep its eye and hand on the double aspect of Production and Consumption through its News Agency, and whioh shall ooeroe Trusts and Corporations (1) into hone sty by making it impossible for them to deoeive the pUfelio as to the real value of their stookB, (2) by making it impossible for them to get a penny more accommodation from the BankB than the public demand for their commodities as socurately oolleoted and registered by the News Department will Justify. In this way the rate of interest will be lowered (for why pay interest when you have a certificate as reliable as that of the mint (so) that there is no risk?), and besides when fully organized it will do away with the necessity of a or other percentage of gold reserve to issues whloh would then beoome as antiquated as carrying pistols at the present day is as a defence against highway robbery I
Now if I am right that something of this kind is what you mean, you have my full permission (if you think my name carries any authority at all as an economist) for saying publioly that in my judgment your scheme is the most perfectly self-acting and regulating
\
(2)
piece of economio moohonism that I have yet oome across, and that the future must lie with it or something of on analogous hind.
Ky book "Tho Kheol of Feelth" las made so much headway among the younger economists hero that Prof. Ashley, who roprooents the more liberal sohool, actually went so far as to say in hie address ao President of the oonomlc Seoticn of the British Awsooietlon last summer, that the old Economy of Adam Smith and Kill was quito doad, and that of the ’marginal' Austrian and American school was in littlo better plight! But until you oen get the Columbia University gong with Prof. Clark os leader out of tho way,
X am afraid your scheme will hove little ohenoo on the Amerioan sido.
I an sending on your lottor and documents to Jojin Hobson to see how your soheme strikes him, end T hove told him that personally I am inclinod Altogether to like It and wish it Cod's speed.
Kindly let he hear from you from time to time as to how your propaganda is progressing, and you may bo suro I will read all you have to say with tho greatest interest.
Should you be in England at any time, end lot me know of your arrival, I will, if you are agreeable, arrange for a mooting and e good talk on all the so matters. Thanking you again for your courtesy, and again apologising for my delay, I am
Yours very truly,
I.	Boattle Crosier.
Franklin Ford, Esq.
P.8. If you oould let mo know where I oan got Hrs. Ford's book I shall be much obliged.
L'nrch 30 1908
Ao A'j'tuidu for .r F.ankliii Ford The trouble with "The Industrial Union" ie tho fact that ninety-nine
fl I	4	*
people out of every hundred who see it or hear it will think it is some sort of a trades union — that it has something to do with labor union organisations etc. This is absolutely inevitable, as it seems to me.
J H C
CREDITS SAFEGUARDED—COLLECTIONS CERTAIN."
THE CREDIT OFFICE
Credit Reporting Collection and Adjustment Accounting and Auditing
Departments.
(INCORPORATED.)	NEW	YORK	LIFE	BUILDING.
Telephone, 956 Franklin.	346	BROADWAY,
New York, March 30, 1908
Dr. James H. Canfield,
Columbia University Library,
New York, N. Y.
My dear Doctor Canfield:
I have searched high and low for the right title for the new Society. I have in mind to name it The Industrial Union, this being the idea, as it appears to me, for which the principle stands. The name is technically correct and the words are at the same time of universal meaning or recognition. It is possible of course that the name has been preempted at Albany through some incorporation or other. As to this I shall inquire at once.
From one viewpoint it is The Self-help Society, in contrast with the
f general tendency of the time to rush to Washington or Albany for all manner ^remedies by statute. Again, it is the League for Self-government, but I think that all distinctly legal or economic terms should be excluded if possible.
I take it that the phrase indust rial union stands for the opposite of the political union. The moment the word political is used nearly everybody at once thinks of Washington and of 'partytics.' The definite organization of intelligence points to the new union over the remains of what were once supposed to be ’indestructible states.' It is suggestive to recall the phrasing from the preamble to the Constitution of 1789: 'in order to form a more perfect union.'
I cannot see that the phrase industrial union is in any way suggestive of class distinctions, which I want to avoid. It seems best not to use terms which would suggest that the Society is made up of 'reformers.' We are only reporters.
The name, The Industrial Union, will lend itself easily to the organization of local branch societies.
So, unless you can find something better, I shall organize
THE INDUSTRIAL UNION.
Very truly yours.

The Credit Office.
Dear Doctor Canfield:
It seems to me that, on the score of money economy alone, the business of the University Centre will soon have to be conducted on the open-shop basis. How much do you think the annual waste is on account of the seeming necessity of maintaining the closed-shop?
Credit Reporting	1
Collection and Adjustment I Departments.
Accounting and Auditing \
(INCORPORATED.) TELEPHONE 1464 FRANKLIN.
NEW YORK LIFE BUILDING,
346 BROADWAY.
New York,
October 1, 1907
Very truly yours
Dr. James H. Canfield.
?*b 11	1907
I4r Wrwnklin 7ord
r>->n«ral Wow» Offloo 346 TJ-oad’/ay ’i T huur 5 r	»
I * . t;if oraed by the Sur, ointondent o f	:	8	bWl	s	:nn
let you havu roo* 205, Hell, fy the orv. wt}teb yon rid? tr do — r • ivf.y-
.
or rtlnot: dijl —	#	i*lbly	fa#	1	i	rest	of	the	ihiiverel ty Jftfcr, t‘	cannot
•)'• <t ii at :>tv lent.
I1- I*	*•	of	any	Kind,	J un-1ffrfft*	,	,	v	no
%
of fu iahing-- *!»». m •	>	1 *•. i ;oi'v*nlf,
• key win be jlwen you on application ftt the tffleA rf the 8*ffrt*» ten Con t,	oom-- -i . rt of ►/i •,building acc or.. ar. 5 by thlp
jf t .
I do 99.t	that	-il*	will	rmot your denandif but 11 in all t*9 Off do*
1 /
I hoffltatod when you epoke tome about n f-t, wining, fo * * * «'*vlo roaoon that
1 new > rf v: tly 'fell that *o hid oat had f	r.	•	floor	u*f	co to
s;*3ffc fr-vr. 4>r	.	.	ii
Ylll bo **tt«f ae'-ory h*mw ’^d that you c*,, onrwork here wlt>nut *®rlou»
Incon 7« nlonce.
CoVjr, Uv yo»rs
V

GENERAL NEWS OFFICE
FRANKLIN FORD, Director
TELEPHONE 14G4 FRANKLIN
EDUCATIONAL DIVISION
New York Life Building, 34(i Broadway
new York February 11, 1607
Dear Doctor Canfield:
The enclosed statement will convey to you just where the action is which I have been plotting, while it will explain also why I must now have the facilities asked for this morning at the library.
Please return the enclosed letter. C. W. Sweet is the controlling owner of the Real Estate Record and Guide, the Architectural Record, the F. W. Dodge Company, and Sweet s Index. He is also the controlling owner of the great clothing industry of Sweet-Orr & Company. He is the largest man in the class news system.
Please let me hear from you.
Very truly yours
James H. Canfield, Librarian, etc. , etc
(COPY)
GENERAL NEWS OFFICE 346 Broadway, New York
f
January 30, 1907
!!r. Clinton N. Sweet,
R19 Broadway, New York. Donr Sir:
7 h nve invented the New s Centre which follows upon the Telephone, and have ready for final revision and publication the ner.r literature of Politics which re stilt a from the appearance of e positive or systematic news system. This literature is, in the first instance, eduoaticr.nl; it amounts also to universal advertising material for the project in hand. For the first tine, the ADVERTISING of a business can be sold.
Tho invention I hfive perfected in, in effect, an extremely valuable trade secret, forming a scientific basis for organising the news Trust. However much we nay reveal the nature and detailed application of the principle, before others could hope to occupy the central position in tho News ryshon, and so supplant ns, they would be compelled, in groat measure, to pass through tho experience which has resulted in the new discipline. Moreover, since news organisation in essentially Unitarian, before anything of moment could be done in that direction, we would be no far along that all attempts at competition would but operate to advance our own work.
I have now to put down for yon the procedure to bn followed in launching the news Tsust.
1. I would .incorporate the General Nows Office cn an ordinary business corporation, under the laws of New York or some other state, making tho basis of the incorporation ny accumulated literature and copyrights. The capital stock at tho outset should be small, and the shares should remain for the time being in the hands cf myself and my .immediate associates.
2.	As the literaturo in hand is the gateway to general acceptance for tho project, I would next proceed to revise and print in pamphlet form the following seven reports;
(a) (b> (o)
fa)
(e)
(f)
f.v)
ms industrial STATS and its goykrhxjwt.
THE RAt	WAS TRAFFIC ASSOCIATION, AN ORGAN OF SBIF-GOTSEJES ’.
HISTORY TEE POET OFFICE; A '/’EY TO THE TT NOT f.TJEOTIOS.
TIE DEVELOPMENT OF A -OPITIVE OR SYSTEMATIC RENT OYOTEM. EVOIUTION OF BANKING Ac AN ORGAN IN THE STATE.
PRESENT POSITION 0? K1C: YORK’S MUNICIPAL THE RKPREEKNTATIVE SLAVS.
gov
The last named report is the story cf my collision with the Newspaper.

I would print one thousand copies of each of these reports, and have the page foms of each stereotyped.
3. I would then set about introducing the project to the representative men of business in New York fpossibly two hundred in number), seeking to get from each of them individual subscriptions to the reports named above; the subscriptions should be '100, or perhaps “350. The purpose I have in mind here is to make of this individual approach the entering wedge for large sales of the literature to the great corporate interests of the country, which for the most part head up in New York.
The aim should be to take to these leaders of commerce written committals to ^he project from the foremost class newspapers, and ether important news centres.
4.	On securing adequate support from the loading commercial interests, I would issue an edition of the reports la:-me enough, for distribution, under well known references, to all prominent newspaper managers in tho United ftntes, to the Judiciary, to the foremost lawyers, to bank officers, to members of Congress ana the state legislatures, to loading merchants, and to the masters of industry; the last named class to incline the railway men. The aim will be to invite criticism from representative men, with a view to incorporating in the now literature such of the results as are valuable.
5.	Tith the action carried to this point, we will hove in full operation the Educational Division of the Cieneral Hews Office. It has to kept in mind that we are, primarily, organising a business action, and that the literature already in pos ess ion is a by-product of t"is action. The first thing is to use the literature for enlisting money support, and at the same time for educating the news managers up to the point of free co-operation through the General News office as main centre of the News System. Following upon this, we will own bo°k copyrights constituting, in and of themselves, a profitable educational publishing business, "'he preliminary work on a Commercial Geography, of world-wide usefulness, is already far along. There exists an insistent demand for the true commercial geography, but it cannot be produced without the application of the principle underlying the General Ne”s Office.
b. Ac an incident in the development of the Educational Division, working relations will be established with all University Centre0, TT,ith a view to imparting .he principle or method to the schools of political science, and so to bring about far-reaching co-operation in political inquiry. It is proposed to effect the university connection through the °ocial and Economic Section of tho American Association for the Advancement of ’cienoe. Three members of tho sectional committee have rlroo.dy considered the plan favorably.
7. As an outgrowth of tho Educational Division a Business News Service for .tho daily press of tho country and tho world will be established, on tho line0 of tho Associated rrons. One main purpose of this division will be to create a market for one part of the by-products of the class newspapers, consisting of general ners relating to each division of commerce. As an ultimate outcome here, it is proposed to introduce a weekly report on the state of trade and industry, to consist of contributions from the class journals representing the various divisions of commerce.
-3-
8.	As soon as the Educational Division and the Business News Service are in the hands of competent managers, I would begin organizing the news of New York's municipal system, fust two things require my further personal touch, namely, the full development of the literature of Politics and the systematic reporting of municipal news. The report on the Present Position of New York's Municipal Government would be used for introducing the new centre to this field, ’"ith this literature distributed judiciously, I would proceed to make demands on the city’s general accounting centre, the Department of Finance, for information, each item at the outset to involve an important development in statistical accounting. For example, our first roquest would be for a report on the oity's miscellaneous revenues, which are not now so much as audited by the Finance Department, yet they are increasing rapidly end now amount to a good many million dollars annually. The Comptroller could not do other than fall in with our demands, and so be led into direct co-operation with the News Office. The vantage ground would bo with us, since we have mastered the procedure and know the end. By this means the News Office will pass into organic relations with the Finance Department.
r.'e would bring up with a’full report on the Evolution cf the City Government cf New York, thus restilting in an epoch-making political document.
9.	Tith the working relation with the Finance Department established in a practical way, we would proceed to issue a dail’r bulletin giving the transactions of the Finance Department for the twenty-four hours, consisting of all claims filed and the completed audits. At the same time we would clear each day, by mail and telephone, all contract or opportunity news of the municipality. About a thousand contractors are constantly dcing business with the city. The stream of contract news should bo sold through the F. Dodge Company. This double step will for the first time open up real publicity for the municipal affairs of New York. Kaoh item, when registered, which promises news cf general interest, would be followed up and reported ir all essential details.
A monopoly of municipal news would result.
10. Following upon the mastery of the opportunity news in the 'local municipal system, together with all nows of the same order in the metropolis, we would proceed to clear the contract or construction news for all divisions of the recognized governments, national, state, and municipal, and for the entire country, the Dodge Company to be selling agent for the ?/hole field. In addition, all general news in the building and construction line should come to be cleared by the Dodge Company.
bureau for the metropolis daily bulletin giving the The conditions sre ripe
all parts of the local made to contribute its
in-
nuota
11.	/:	universal or central information
can be announced at the time of issuing the transactions of the Department of Finance, for a telephonic news centre, through which formation system can be called up, and each of fact for the guidance of the business public and the people generally. Tith the list of local news offices perfected, and a business relation established with each, the General News Office will be able to advertise all inquiry centres in the system through a single outgiving. A trading relation with the New York Telephone Company is proposed, which will permit all pay stations in Greater Tier: York to give the News Office wire to any one in need of information, the fee, by special arrangement with the telephone people, to be paid to the station operator. Touching the development of revenue for the telephonic news centre ° it or of the ’.'all Street Journal, has been
saying
V
;o
me
that
Pratt, earn any
very
-4-
individuals and trading concerns will gladly pay a reasonable fee for the right to call up the centre for miscellaneous or routine information. A news stomp could be introduced for attaching to letters of inquiry.
12. Revenue creation in support of the Municipal News Division should have special treatment, T'e should introduce the pro Tittccrrin-ciplo, as it has obtained in the field of ordinary taxation: that is, we should induce a bank or other corporation to make a yearly subscription amounting to a small percentage on its volume of business, and then proceed to extend this over the entire revenue field. It appears that all taxation began with voluntary contributions. *"e are proposing a re-formation in Government which will result in vast social benefits, and the fact should govern our action. Already, what amounts to a new system of taxation has cone tc exist in the city, consisting of regular contributions by the varied business interests to all nanjiar of ’'municipal reform societies," several hundred thousand dollars being paid to then annually, Those revenues must bo systematised and made permanent by ub, if we are to achieve the highest success* Through the centralizing of Industry, news revenues in gonoral arc undergoing a radical alteration; the change is basic and we must follow the tendency. To organise the news business, we must placo its revenue system on a permanent basis. It is a system of taxation, which permits the publication of daily papers like the New York Times and the Rorld for one cent, the prico being hardly more then the cost of distribution.
in. It has occurred to me that we might with advantage enter into some sort of business arrangement with the New York Board of Trade end Transportation for delivering tc it cortain of our municipal reports.
They could recommend action on the strength of cur scientific findings.
I have known the secretary and active manager of the Board since my Bradstreet days.
14.	The traffic in news between sub-centres and the General Nows Office will be handled on a commission basis, at least to begin with, and on a basis, say, of fifty perccefct of the net receipts. For example, if the General Nows Office noils a report furnished by the Real Estate Record and Guido one half should go tc the Guido* It may be that later an tho source of supply should receive more than one half. Regarding contracts with sub-centres, I take it that nothing more than memorandum agreements will be needed, as the parts of tho system are bound together by tho closest inter-dependence; they must buy and sell of each other, yet each is entirely free in its own sphere.
15.	In relation to the larger development of the Educational Division, it may bo that an alliance should be made with an old established bock house, especially when it is considered that a great central literary factory is to result at the main news office, kith respect to this,
I fin in touch with George' Haven Putnam p?	^ltnam’s Eons.
16.	A firm contract is proposed between the General Bows Office and The Credit Office, which will provide for a continuing payment to the formor of a fixed percentage of the latter's receipts. The large promotion of The Credit Office is dependent on its introduction to the Nows Pystem by the General News Office. The class newspapers will be important factors in perfecting the centralised organisation of the credit news field. Thus, all credit information concerning tho building industry of the metropolis, apart from the opportunity news, should be cleared through The Credit Office, and An furthering this the Real Estate Record
-5-
and Snide can 7)6 node a potent force. It in proponed to develop the weekly sheet now if?mad by The Credit Office, under the sane name, into a universal newspaper organ of the banking or credit ayetera; there is no olers journal on modern lines in this field, yet the necessity cf such an organ is imperative.
1?. I invite attention to the peculiar relationship to be occupied by the General Hews Office in ro the development of revenues for the Clare news system. The class or technical papers have reached their presort position through two sources of revenue, subscriptions and the sale rf advertising space. But nor, through becoming scientific centres for the registration of fact on a great scale, their expenditures inevitably ride sc that the certain tendency is to outrun the old-time basis of revenue. It means that the payments from corporations or firms for the support of a given class journal must come to be in difoct proportion to* the place of such firm cr corporation in the related industry, ir place of measuring '• he payments merely by the amount of advertising speco used. In other words, while the editorial or reporting work is progressing on organic lines, the revenue system has continued on a merely individualistic basis in accordance with the ordinary notion of competition, "’ho basis of revenue cannot be changed without the rise of a general nows office through whose action the place and claims of each class paper can be determined and given universal publicity. In short, the situation is such that the main news centre noooscarily becomes a revenue-got ting agent for the class nev/s system* I withhold judgment as to whether the General ’Tews Office should seek by direct method to exact a share of such enlarged revenues.
IP. Both the General ’Tews Office and The Credit Office must be treated by ourselves as public institutions, though operating under the principle cf Contract, which means that full details as tc thoir finances must be published at proper intervals.
19. It Is proposed to orgar.ise the professional accountants through registration at The Credit Office, so that the standing of an accountant will come to be tested by the fact of his acceptance cr rejection by the universal credit reporting centre. The developed Credit Office will have rank as the Bank Clearing Rouse, both being organs in the Industrial Ttnte.
CO. I withhold judgment, both in general and detail, as to the wisdom of placing stock of the General few?. Office with the class newspapers and other snb-contres.
21. are to introduce the natural or simple method of classifying and organising nev/s. If news can be organised on a scientific basis it cannot long be handled in any other way. I may add that the principle laid down is common cr easy to men of the mental order of your Hr. Eos-raond or Hr. BeInhold.
I have Bought to put down for you the leading ideas controlling the action in hand. I ask you to join me in the work of conferring upon commerce the greatest single benefit in all history. My feeling ia that the character of the enterprise glvos it a just olai#°£p&S y'(5iSrjC16>rg^c11S' knowledge, your experience, end practical judgment*
6
direct business interest on acoount of yciir prominence in the class news field. The facts spell Opportunity.
Oho force of the principle is such that all related news interests must enter the proposed combination or be left outside the breastworks.
A universal trading relation is requ red in the news business as means to furthering the general advance in co-operation which the new conditions permit and compel throughout the entire field of trade end industry. In point of principle, the co-operation in the news field which I am proposing is nothing more than has already taken nlace in what I may call the commerce in physical things; for example, you buy buttons from other concerns and sell them as parts of the finished garment.
The path of an enterprise so new and original as this cannot of course bo marked out in advance in any great detail, but it is plain tc me that if oufficent freodon can be secured to enable us to revise, print, and circulate the new 1itorature of Politics all else will be certain and ea*»y; all further steps will take place in their natural order, and the right men will come to hand at the right time. The literary preparation has been difficult, but I have accomplished .it to the letcor.
The time element is with us in all resrects, and, owing to the nature of the business, the social forces will further the action at every point. The cnief risk was moral or scientific rather than financial, but I have won everything on that score up tc this writing.
A credit of a few thousand dollars is needed in order that the bold-' ness of the first steps may be up to the level of the prineiplo. I ask you to furnish this credit on such terras as may be agreed upon. I have no alliances or obligations which can stand in the way of ray making an exclusive contract with you. I am satisfied that with freedom gained for the initial handling of the new literature, all the succeeding ste^s will be insured by the creation of revenues. The individual who will have the courage to make the initial credit which is required, will of necessity reap a large money reward, since, as already indicated, the service to commerce will be unexampled. * have already said to you that the nan who will take a now proposition at its fnce value, is about as rare as its oroator.
A powerful financial institution is contemplated. There is money in the scheme for all concerned.
Very truly yours,
(signed) Franklin Ford.
GENERAL NEWS OFFICE
FRANKLIN FORD, Director
TELEPHONE 1404 FRANKLIN
EDUCATIONAL DIVISION New York Life Building, 346 Broadway
new York Jan. 31, 1907
Dear Doctor Canfield:
I am trying to get into touch with Mr. Root.
I enclose copy of a letter to him, and suggest that you write him a note by way of helping to secure his attention.
I enclose two copies of the circular referred to in my letter to Root, and suggest that you might one of them in the scrap-bock which you have started in the library.
Please return the copy of my letter to Mr. Root, as it is the office copy.
Very truly yours.
Dr. .Tames H. Canfield,
Librarian, eto., etc

•	Auguet	22	1906
i
t
'‘r Franklin Ford
TKo Credit Office N Y Life Building 346 Broadway Mew York
Doar Sir
I have been eearching far and wide for the galley proofs of the report on the Industrial State and its Government, and for some reason cannot lay hands on them* They were sent to the Periodical Department to be mounted and hound just as we were making a change in the head of that department — and eomevrhore a oog in the m chine must have eltoped*
I may find them yet, and I have not stopped looking? but if you happen to have them in galley proof or in any other form In which I can make use of them in the Library, I would be glad to have you se d me another set.
Cordially yours
/

Credit Reporting	j
Collection and* Adjustment I Departments. Accounting and Auditing )
The Credit Office.
(INCORPORATED.) TELEPHONE 1464 FRANKLIN.
NEW YORK LIFE
New York,	•
/
J?[ tr^ t r __________ x	^
IU^AA~ J	C	.
A^?
(1^	6^4.	^	^
_^L 4_-^<L L/^aA ^	LlacL C f~
■/tim?—v l i .
building,
346 BROADWAY.
V
(L ^	.
'I
Feb 23	1906
f
Mr Franklin Ford Director
fcneraJ News OffJco 280 Broadway Vew York
Dear *!ir.
/
I have been mieh interested in t.he development or the general Jews Office, upon 'our initiative and under your general dirno'. ion — and am glad that you have reached the point where you can make a definite presentation your plans to the intelligent people of this municipal I ty*
%
The educational results of this undertaking rou«l bn highly beneficial, in the publicity thue given to all roinlolpil \ff '.Irs, Tills pmat city Is after all not a political entity nut a great buelnoH* corporation. In which every citl-ten is a stockholder: and it behoove* the stockholders to unilerttand quite eon* pletol; what 1* being undertaken nod accomplished by those whom they aelect an director* of their company.
I wish you all possible «ucceee,
Cordially you no

A Central Bureau of Information
TBI.*PHOSr*
2 Fjla.btki.iw
CiBLK ADDBEB6
GBiriTBVBOFS
GENERAL, NEWS OFFICE
FRANKLIN FORD, Director 280 Broadway, New York
February 22, 1906
Ity dear Dr, Canfield:-
are sending' out can-inforraation. Please
send U3 a good. word.
Very truly yours,
As told you over t'ne telephone, we vassers to get business for the central bureau of
Franklin Ford.
difficult, if not impossible, of access to any individual. The facts will be furnished promptly touching any city contract. Reports will be made concerning taxation, assessments, improvements, or property condemnations in any quarter. Taxpayers and citizens should apply to the News Office for any desired information in relation to city affairs. It is in instant communication with the Department of Finance, and with all other departments, boards and commissions in the city government. It also connects with the title insurance centre, which has systematized the information relating to real estate ownership. Thus all the required facts are now at the end of a wire, and all the wires connect with the General News Office.
INFORMATION FOR MUNICIPAL CONTRACTORS
Contractors having payments due from the city will be kept posted as to the progress of their vouchers. They are informed when the vouchers are transmitted to the Finance Department, when audited, when ready for payment, etc., thus relieving them from the necessity of personally following a voucher from place to place. Contractors are also informed, in advance of the advertisement, of the preparation of contracts.
PROPERTY OWNERS WILL BE KEPT POSTED
Property owners will be kept informed of proceedings affecting their interests. Often if an undesirable street opening or other condemnation proceeding is opposed at its inception, it may be avoided, whereas it is difficult or impossible to obtain relief from the same proceeding in its advanced stages. Taxes and assessments, and water charges are looked after.
THE MUNICIPAL SYSTEM ABOUNDS IN CREDIT NEWS
The General News Office will place the great volume of credit news contained in the records of the city departments within easy reach of the banks, and of the retail dealers and their associations. It is no longer necessary for the banks to send a credit man to the Comptroller’s office or other city department to learn the facts governing the standing of a city contractor. Such information, and any statement made to a bank official in relation to a city contract and payments thereon, may be verified by telephone. Any information in relation to the salaries and positions of city employes may be obtained by merchants and their associations by telephone.
THE CITY PUBLICITY QUESTION LOCATED AND DEFINED
The General News Office has located and defined the much talked of publicity development for municipal affairs. The point to be grasped is that the general publicity which is demanded in this field cannot he aUainad without first classifyingand reporting the municipal facts from the technical point of view to meet individual and business needs. This done, the foundation will be laid for an authoritative publicity concerning city affairs.
THE DEMAND FOR MUNICIPAL INFORMATION
The General News Office is ready to meet the growing demand for exact information concerning all phases of New York's municipal business. The amplest preparation has been made for this sendee through a scientific study of the function of the Department of Finance, which is the city’s general accounting centre, and its working relation with the municipal system. A practical connection with the Finance Department has been effected, and with all divisions of the city government, each of which is a bureau of information on its own account.
MAGNITUDE OF THE CITY'S ESTABLISHMENT
The municipality of New York employs directly 50,000 men,, and indirectly through allied institutions, contractors and supply people, 25,000 more. Over 1,000 contractors are constantly doing business with the city. The magnitude of this centralized industry has compelled a technical news centre which will organize and report the facts for all interests concerned.
THE LOCAL NEWS SYSTEM TO BE PUT ON THE TELEPHONE
Municipal reports will be made by telephone. In fact, the entire local news system will be put on the telephone so that any part of it can be called up at will. Subscribers will be registered on payment of fees, varying according to the nature and extent of their business. The interests of subscribers will be watched and new facts affecting them promptly reported.
THE NEW CENTRE WILL SUPPLY THE NEEDS OF LAWYERS
The growing need of lawyers for trustworthy municipal information has been provided for. The 6,000 lawyers who are now connected with the Manhattan telephone centre should all take advantage of the News Office service. In matters relating to the action ol any city official, board or commission, lawyers should get a report on the facts from the news centre as the quickest way to determine the merits of a client’s case and the procedure to be followed. The News Office does such work better and cheaper than a lawyer's clerk, because its experts know exactly where to go for information. No time is lost in making inquiries of various-officials. Moreover, the News Office experts have acquired facility in the work, and transcripts of many of the official records are already in hand. A central office, which is constantly studying all phases of the city’s business, is vastly better equipped for meeting the needs of particular interests than any individual can be, even though he may give his entire time to one interest alone.
INFORMATION FOR MERCHANTS. BANKERS, CITIZENS AND TAXPAYERS
Merchants and bankers should get a report on the facts from the news centre before entering upon litigation with the city. Reports will be furnished on application concerning the records and proceedings of any city department. Through the News Office organization facts can readily be supplied which would be
SUGGESTIONS FOR LETTER
Address:
Franklin Ford, Director,
General News Office, New York.
Your offer to place all municipal information at the command of
everybody at a moderate price is an inviting business proposition for all
interests affected and each individual citizen, but the special attractive I
tion to me is that the execution of r plan necessarily carries with
oity
it a far-reaching and actual reform in the methods of aeodtodcpadc govero-
already in hand are ment. The educational results of your work sera	fcne	hr	highly
m
beneficial. The project has my highest coMHiendation.
section »
CHAIRMAN or SECTION
Hon. MARTIN A. HNARR
SECRETARY OR SECTION DR. JOHN FRANKLIN CROWCll 1102 14th ST. N. W.
AntPriratt A&anrtatum far iljp Aiimmrpmpttt of £>ripttrp
SECTION l: SOCIAL AND ECONOMIC SCIENCE
VarijUiglmi. 0. CL
cTli
Simeon C. Baldwin John Franklin Crowell H. T. Newcomb C. L. CORTHELL Carroll D. Wright B. C. FernOW FRANK R. RUTTER WM. R. Lazenbv-
March 23> 1905#
Mr. Franklin Ford, Director,
General News Office,
New York, N.Y.
My dear Mr* Ford:-
I have watched with more than ordinary interest the stages of the development of your idea of the organization of a central bureau of newsclearing* Permit me to say that you have made a new step in the direction of developing public opinion to a degree of intelligence which it has never heretofore fouhd means of attaining.
Your organization applies essentially to Greater New York, because there the need has in the past been the greatest. I anticipate that the results of your efforts will immeasurably exceed your expectation and that you will find that every phase of public opinion will sooner or later call for current facts which are necessary for the formation of intelligent opinions on all kinds of public questions. You have, to put the matter briefly, begun to give democracy a power of insight and foresight such as it has never heretofore enjoyed.
Let me congratulate you and wish you every measure of success.
Very sincerely yours.
DEPARTMENT OF FINANCE,
CITY OF NEW YORK.
EDWARD M. GROUT
COMPTROLLER.
February 24, 1905.
In Replying Reter To
MR. FRANKLIN FORD,
Director, General News Office,
New York City.
Dear Sir:
I have followed with great interest the successive steps in the developement of the General News Office, and in the work of founding a central bureau to meet the growing demand from institutions, the legal profession, and the general public for exact information regarding the municipal business of New York City. I recognize that the amplest preparation has been made and that you are now ready to serve the public. I am convinced that the scientific registration and reporting of municipal news is of vital importance in the further progress of city government. Having examined the results of your prolonged inquiry into the evolution of municipal government in New York, and appreciating the value of the conclusions reached, I herewith request you to furnish me the full report of the investigation for the use of the Department of Finance.
i
Very truly yours.
Comptroller
Dec 5	1905
Mr Franklin Ford
230 Broadway ttew York Dear l'r Ford
I Kayo yowr* 0f r>or 2d with encloeure* a* stated which I	r	d
wit tercet.
I will try to get thin matter Wore Profoeeor najif! eld at tho edrlieat moaa it po**lble.
He ha* already told me that ho I* more than willing to eee y0u %mj thl* matter oTer with you, and I eu^eet that 11 will be helpful for thi* conference with him.
Hurriedly, but
Cordially youra
A Central Bureau of Information
Tslxphoits
2 FBAV KLIN
Cable Addbxss
GIKNKW80P8
GENERAL, NEWS OFFICE
FRANKLIN FORD, Director 280 Bhoadway. New Tohk
August 20, 1905
Dr, Janes H. Canfield,
Columbia University. Vy clear Dr. Canfield:
I an counting on your giving careful attention to tde manuscript left with you on yesterday. I an sure you will be interested and', above all, I an certain that your criticisms will be of exceptional value to me. One stands in special need of advice when breaking new ground.
Thanking you in advance, I am,
Very truly yours,
The copy you have should be returned to me; it contains ray latest corrections. I will call on Tuesday or Wednesday.
THE INDUSTRIAL STATE AND ITS G0VER2U03NT
RISE AND ORGANIZATION OR MODERN COMMERCE—-THE CIVILIZER OR Jm: AND NATION!
THE INDUSTRIAL STATE, DEVELOPING UNDER THE PRINCIPLE OR CONTRACT, IS FORM ING ITS OWN CENTRES OR CONTROL OR REGULATION
THE CORPORATION THE HEAD AND RRONT OR THE LARGER COJL'fERCIAL ACTIVITY-
THE PRODUCT UP ASSOCIATION THROUGH THE REPRESEN-TATIVS PRINCIPLE
THE TRUST OR GREAT CORPORATION A REGULATING ORGAN IN COMMERCE—ITS RISE DUE TO NATURAL CAUSES—-THE RESULTING SOCIAL BENEFITS— PROGRESS THROUGH DIVISION OR LABOR
POPULAR OPPOSITION TO THE TRUSTS AND THE RRICTION WITH THE WASHINGTON GOVERNMENT--THE REMEDY IS TO TAKE ORR THE CLAMPS AND FACILITATE CORPORATE DEVELOPMENT
REGULATION THROUGH THE RAILWAY TRAFFIC ASSOCIATION AND THE BANK -LEAKING
HOUSE
THE WAR-CRY OR SOCIALISM—DANGER OR SOCIAL VIOLENCE AND A RAIN OR BLOOD
I

1 "« W isos
Mr Franklin Ford
280 Broadway Now York
Soar ' r ’or'l
aearcn for	it	Chr.	wualopu*	caa«f	and	roaocna)	'	tw	*o fur-
f	*
ni»h . .1 Vooku horn called fcr»
.. >r	••	; -.n.blw *«• po«dfbl«( if v©« can e...
at ay , hcri of «U , day* i *111 iv u- ju* • littlo row freodom of airotilv.* toward IK* and ot the auuraor '►hoo * will b»gtn to n?*d th* roorc n,or* th«*n	*	I	r	a	*•
O' Hi ail- oil r*
V
%

JtlBti 1'"'
Ur Franklin '’ord Director etc .
y 280 Bro&cvr»> "<rwYork TV>ar >	**o	rd
r^i.l 1 to . tv f mo l'th, I bay lneve to i«ay that I would ba
sl.d o have Information fr<Rj you coneemlnr the realltio underlying *»)eBo*rd or
Ald«t.4i»n of .-•»*	•	'	•	-	totak	r—	itw
•Id time po* r, . .	altogether* r’ nur Gonero1 vatni
Office hr, m8 %nj. llcht n?0n kh||j qu„BtloB#
Cordially youre
A Central Bxireau of Information
TELEPHONE
2 FRAyKUX
Cable Address
Genstewsofs
GENERAL, NEWS OFFICE
FRANKLIN FORD, Director 280 Broadway, New York
New York, June 15» 1905#
Dr. James H. Canfield, Librarian,
Columbia University, N. Y.
• {
Dear Dr. Canfield
I should like to receive a letter from you making
inquiry of the General News Office concerning the realities underlying
* ■; \
the Board of Aldermen of New York City; the tendency, as you know, has bee>i. toMB to take away from the Board its old-time power, and now the disposition seems to be to get rid of the Board altogether. "What is the meaning of all this? I will reply in a page of typewriting. My purpose in,asking you to do this is to enable me to add the report to an exhibit showing the actual working of the General News Office, in relation to the needs of men.
Very truly yours,
Chairman of 3option
KOJJ, /(ARTIF try/ws T.'iflhington, 0. 0,
Sscre vftrv of section Dr. J0TD7 WdfXJJP ORO^JJ,
1102 uih .n. 't. ■«?.
'A'aBh : n&t on,	0.
Feet.tonal Committee of Feet ton:
Simeon P. Rnldwin John Prenklin Crowell P. T. Pe^corib ft. L. Corthell Carroll I). Tright P. P. Porno?/
Prank R. Rutter ¥n. R. Lar.anhy
ajmrpjcatt pep mT~ AT^ARCTTRTT Op CCTP/TCP Section:!: Soe'u'l and Poononio Potency wash1neton, 7>. C.
January pc, loop.
RECEIVE CE81
>?.r . Prnnklin Pord, flew York, P. v#
:r- do ,r >rr. Por d:~
v'',,r? of the *th In.’Amt came to hand ir due tlru. T h\--s road •* l+h iiur’i ca.v" 7'vy. ah.li> discuss 1 ■'r ■>* t?*e -*;net ion of the General 5ew« Office in Relation to Co-ct -.l ' tg><r.isp.tten.	Tt	p ‘oa» to	y_o that.	yoi haye
very clearly brought	out the fact of the	importance
of the growth of associations as ret; ;lut, iv.-; centers.
1 cannot now enter Into a disc ir.slon of the .-subject on acc'.’ Vit of e. yr»r,ir;rft of busi-no,;u. h it she- ii.d like	to	bir-e you	present	a paper
g'-inn r"»’ir r-sults,	at	the next	moat ing	of the
A. A. A.	tn	TTen- Orleans near the and of
Pecember 190^,
Very sincerely yoirs,
JOE?" PRASKLIP CRO’A’ELL
A CENTRAL BUREAU OF INFORMATION FOR GREATER NEW YORK
GENERAL NEWS OFFICE
FRANKLIN FORD, Director


the department of Finance, and all Centres of the Municipal System
THE UNIVERSITY CENTRE
The Credit office
The class Newspapers
Title Guarantee and trust Company
NEWS CENTRES
CREDIT NEWS
Telephone, 1331 franklin Cable address: gennewsofs
Facts for individual Needs
News of the Metropolis Business news
MUNICIPALAND GENERAL

280 BROADWAY
NEW YORK January 6, 1905.
Dr. James H. Canfield,
Columbia University, N. Y.
Dear Dr. Canfield:
I have your letter of January 4th asking for some sort of estimate as to the cost of furnishing to the University Library the articles of permanent value which appear in the leading daily papers from time to time.
The question cannot be answered in a way that would be satisfactory without entering into the nature of the comtemplated business relationship. It has to be borne in mind that the News Office and the University are organically related centres in the one news or science system. I will reflect over the points involved and write you in a few days. Suffice to say at the moment that I am very desirous of effecting the practical connection; it is a logical necessity for both centres.
The enclosed cutting from last night*s Evening Post is a good example of the literature in question.
Very truly yours
fu	1
*©*,	j iatr
I roo#/{ cm**!	i	•
XD- • ;	‘	■•-■-•
' ;i i l jo .,
aoO. t>*&TL rfid OX «xi (k;.. *
oue uiM 01. t	*	it	I	•TTT	*.#X	-
J7 ^ VU OL'^tT 'll* *.«T*$*f CITIUM Ttr fj©
rrw» fO pw pOUJO JW Vflfff (V*t *T»®	0U.T<*«	**•*<?	f*'C
'xn.® ox pr® ooi-r«fc’*'79,r*T l#r®|v«»o Loj®ffO*'®,vT&* If MUX? P* ®®fi«Lrc#®iA	®iif«uirC	|uro	o-
1P® dn®«^7®v oomtof p« whom**.*! Ji» « wft rt*wf
*r*J« t* (TK*
aotho ^nor iMkw, yp f] •_7®*nv£	*71*	’	■*	*1.®
7® rr® i;I?1aWf\ * iru*I«J®® ox &®kain»»mf •on© doi.; ox 0®<rjr.3.f® »'* *0 fj*® e«®f ®L UiH T«TT71 ”
I j vis *om.	ox lrrnnJX <f*P	x®1-
-• C	:
cojf«r r r.i-’jAoL 4ir *	•	•
L#»* IP * a r c*1	*
*

Jan 4 1905

¥
Mr Franklin Ford
0 noral Hows Office
280 Broadway Now York
Dear «r Ford
Thfi pressure of othar bunlnosn has prevented ny taking up ono detail of your letter of D cumber 17th, concerning which I w.lsh now to aBit a question.
Can you make any estimate whatavor as to what It «*>uld cost thi« Lib-rary to bo eo related to rci>r novenent as to receive 'from time to tins the clippings which your office will determine to b of such Interest »" to be worthy of
preservation here.
Cordially yours
»
A CENTRAL BUREAU OF INFORMATION FOR GREATER NEW YORK
GENERAL NEWS OFFICE
FRANKLIN FORE), Director

NEWS CENTRES
MUNICIPALANDGENERAL
THE DEPARTM ENT OF FINANCE, AND ALL CENTRES OF THE
Municipal system
news of the Metropolis business News
Credit news
Title Guarantee and Trust Company
FACTS FOR INDIVIDUAL NEEDS
The UNIVERSITY CENTRE The Credit Office The class Newspapers
TELEPHONE, 1331 FRANKLIN CABLE ADDRESS! GENNEWSOFS
280 BROADWAY
new YORK December 17, 1904.
Dr. James H. Canfield,
Columbia University.
Dear Doctor Canfield:
I have been able to get a third letter into the Evening Post aa per enclosed cutting. It is by Mr. F. W. Shepard aho is one of the young men attached to the General Hews Office. I purpose making a leaflet of the three letters. I also enclose a reprint of the Brooklyn Eagle’s report of Mrs. Ford’s address bef ore the Mew York library Club concerning the School-Library relationship. It might be well to bind it with the three other things given you the other day.
It seems to me that this cutting from the Post is a good illustration of the things now appearing in the daily newspapers which should be culled out,, put into scrapbooks, and catalogued at the University centre. \ Without such nTTIoii 11 ijiiII I mr nhrijn I IlfMi will ii multi imo to be lost beyond ' recall. I submit that it would make a go6d beginning of the proposed direct working: relation between the news centre and the University, simple yet important. The volume of matter ’would not be large. An occasional legal decision should be extracted and catalogued as a piece of political.
\literature. It is a constant source of surprise to me that the writers on political organization, per se, have so little acquaintance with the decisions of the courts.
Yotir aict in1 sending my papers to Mr. Root is an encouraging thing for me. From a talk over the ’phone with his sec ret airy I am expecting to meet Mr. Root next week.
Very truly yours,

»
•	1*^	u	kutK,J+	ATT	--
CiXX- *•* .	**j	!?-•	a	-	.-.*	,.	jp.« k ; i* mt +- *>.'us.?*-- r^T
q«or«loLT4 ov #3M «Mi-f a*
. ;	•	-	.	.	•	*	j*
IP !• *	01 •^rki>w,* fv •	|	• j-ifML#
I* :rfT	/^1 oMf*.m-im/ m ir !»*•;• sj, . i.i-*i
I	. ■	* y* oo.;n
L*C.	•	>	lf«ff	—•	1
—
: •'	•	l	wi.	,V	uil4> ...	..	rt
C	'	»	»	:	.	•
rr°o *l &• cn *a *»*	*v	*-*• A »>«wyrfj«w «rrc-j	p#
if mm to m» ipm m+ «*#rr*t l*** «*• ym$ f * * fnn*f&*-
O? ‘Si- K'l * riA« >©.'f
. * -
•
, xo* '	-	-	--	°	r	•	:■•-	.*	,
- * !:• " . *
- ■	1	f	*	-	*	*	*	•	'	o
I ]M §mm *PT'> t* "*$ 9 rr*TM Tmm r*M fjm	If	we	Bel
:
ojm i -r il -IrtU!. IT A*
? >
\
A CENTRAL BUREAU OF INFORMATION FOR GREATER NEW YORK
CITY NEWS OFFICE
FRANKLIN FORD, Director

NEWS CENTERS The Departmentof Finance,
AND ALL CENTERS OF THE
Municipal System Title guarantee and Trust Com pany General News Office The credit Office The Class Newspapers
«$» «$»
Municipal and General News of the Metropolis
business News
Credit News
Facts for individual Needs
TELEPHONE, 1331 FRANKLIN
cable Address: citnewsofs
280 BROADWAY
NEW YORK December 20, 1904.
Dr. James H. Canfield,
Columbia University.
My dear Sir:
I am expecting to meet Mr. Root on Thursday. I have in mind to suggest to him that the General Mews Office he employed by the Department of Commerce to make an exhaustive report on the question of railway regulation, and thi3 of course on the plane of fact.
I ask you to consider the wisdom of the suggestion. Certain it is that something, should he done and at once to get the recognised Government on the right tack. Socialism cannot he warded off hy acting on its tenets. The Government should recognize and encourage the new regulating centres in place of fighting them.
Very truly yours,
**«o tun
4 -n»	c»^;j	«K^m	'	j'
*«W*s*	^rirri	«r?
«rar* wi nt4* Pv w^fwf e^ > <•
■rw 9*A«r,t«!r *j .- •	.	•	r	tt
Wu	***•	0|ff	■	fr	.
ar*~*«W|c^*	\S	ir*1.	♦♦.*4
I 0*» %#t ;<» wj*tts*l , '<* **#£»U iL &*•
t; wr.f*
’ r i* at,	ft	.	*	*
«cn-r.: *{*+ -• -V.	4	;	*»	j^,	ajrr:»^
___r f"« t.«fr*-r , - , i	r	^_____
FI'T ~>far. ■* s* • 8	i	♦<	UK*. ‘ - ,
jjwi<»r* i	<*	i>*v	#•	e^ceer	#6
j nr ^w:i »? ^ >1* f f|t* )T
-,;\ ?•*:. e. .«
Q0Ji«rf}-fV AP|llt fA* r** *.p»» r*	1

o
GENERAL NEWS OFFICE
FRANKLIN FORD, Director
«$» <£»
NEWS CENTRES THE DEPARTM ENT OF FINANCE,
and all Centres of the Municipal System
TITLE GUARANTEE AND TRUST COMPANY THE UNIVERSITY CENTRE THE CREDIT OFFICE The Class newspapers
280 BROADWAY
NEW YOR
♦ ♦
MUNICIPALAND GENERAL NEWS OF THE METROPOLIS
Business News CREDIT NEWS
Facts for Individual Needs
telephone, 1331 Franklin cable Address: Gennewsofs
K December 19, 1904.
Dear Dr. Canfield:
The enclosed papers are: self-explanatory. You may return them at your canvanien.ce.
Very truly yours,
Dr. James F. Canfield.
/J
i

10
CITY l£v,7s 0EEIU3 260 Bro adwsy
HEW Y03KT, September 27, 1904,
Dr. James, H. Canfield,
Librarian, Columbia University.
Dear Dr. Canfield:
I have your appreciative note of yesterday. Oil nof it would not be advisable to bind my letter with either the baiik matter or the pa fillet on the Depart nent of Pinance. It is too personal when read, between the lines, the reference being to the second paragraph. Sometime what you suggest might be done but not now. Instead, I suggest that you file my letter and put with it the following memorandum! This is Hie first time that political, science was ever submittal to any academy.
Very truly youra,

I
Sept 21	1904
Mr "ranklln ord
0	City Nowe Office 280 Broadway i.'ew York D«ar Sir
I a:r under \ny obligation!* to you for t-,e copi'.s a.' ext acte oft for ■■ last-evening, aa wall r<s for your enlightening letter — whlc I
1	will >lnd up with none of the other natter.
With kindest regards
Cordially you re