'	*■“ ’	-ww**-.***
f	BANK	CHECKS. '	•
Thinks Their Part Is. Overlooked by Teachers of Fincmcea
To the Editor of The "New Yorli Times:
I haye Just read with Interest your leading article of this date on " Crops and Money/* May I(venture to say that the astonishing , thing In the current discussion over the bank 1 situation Is the almost total failure of Our official teachers to recognize clearly that the universal currency of to-day and to-morrow is the bank check? From the technical viewpoint the check can no longer be regarded as a mere order for the payment of *' money/* Instead, In and of itself, it Is to be seen as .money In every sense of the word, being an order for the transfer of credit on the books of the bank.
As a help in understanding the profound alteration which has taken place in the banking or exchange system, the following Retract from an address by G. H. P own all before the
London Institute of Bankers as far back as 1881 is In point. After depicting the wonderful Clearing House development Mr. Pownall said:
There Is a certain grim satire in these figures (of clearing) when one thinks of the libraries filled with blue books full of weighty arguments, all curiously wrought out to help in the settlement of the great note Question. It is clear that the check and the clearing system are the main lines Upon which banking is destined to run. Dead theories respecting notes and the right of issue belong to the generation to which
they were living verities. To us the living fact is the substitution of a new instrument of credit. For the present generation the improvement of the check and the clearing system, the mechanical details of office organization, those details of bookkeeping which save time are from the enormous number of documents passing through the hands of a banker of more weight than the most learned treatise on notes and note makers.	FRANKLIN	FORD.
New York, Aug. 12, 1009.
Stye iNVurjjork Simcs
Published: August 14, 1909 Copyright © The New York Times