The Textile year is divided abruptly into two distinct parts—the Fall and Spring Seasons.
Every merchant knows by December first the initfal amount he is to ship to each customer for the Spring Season.
Very few merchants, outside of the National subscribers, know exactly bow each one of these customers has paid his bills due from September first to December first, or in fact know that the Fall payments have been made at all.
No merchant, excepting the National subscriber, has any knowledge of the total number of orders placed by each customer.
The idea of checking credits on net worth and financial statements is a myth.
The National Credit Office has eliminated this statement myth from its calculations in the majority of credit risks. No one is in a position to know, without actually auditing a concern's books, whether the figures in the statement are approximately correct or not, but everyone using the National Service is in a position to know exactly how any concern is paying its bills and the approximate amounts of orders placed.
No concern paying its bills promptly and buying normally will go into bankruptcy and not pay very nearly one hundred cents on the dollar.
While it is true that a concern’s statement or claimed net worth may have a qualifying effect on the line of credit and terms to be granted, the main consideration — line of credit and terms—must be based upon the earning ppwer, and this can only be determined on a basis of the known facts—orders and payments.
The National Credit Office has a new system of automatic unlimited service, which eliminates all possibility of loss by bad debt.
The terms for the service are based on the number of accounts.
The plan is of extreme interest to any concern selling the Textile Industry.
Write to-day for prospectus.
National Credit Office
50 Union Square, New York City