Q Every merchant is aware of the fact that there are constant improvements in mechanical devices to simplify the manufacture of merchandise.
Q The successful merchants instantly install the machine or attachment that increases the efficiency of labor, or safeguards the welfare of employees.
Q Surely, the successful merchant has the same interest at heart in securing the most efficient credit service.
<J The National Credit Office has introduced new features in the credit reporting field that increase the efficiency of the sales force and decrease the loss by bad debt.
<J As this service is automatic, and unlimited in its scope, every manufacturer can afford to use it.
<1 Do not renew your contract for credit reporting for 1915 until you have a demonstration of the National Service.
Write to-Jay for full particular* of thi* new, automatic CreJit System.
NATIONAL CREDIT OFFICE
50 UNION SQUARE
. NEW YORK