Bradstkset’s pays that che crop reporting of the future is to he done by an organized journalism ne tho metropolis. This Is assuming for the metropolis more, perhaps, than nil! be fulfilled. But of that no matter. A line is ultimately to be drawn between governmental and newspaper publicity. tTbereror the sovereignty has to be impressed iu order to get information, the wort of the government Is a necessity. But whoa the required facts are reached through a potent sympathy and far-rsacbing activity, the collecting agent :s tho nu'trcpolitan newspaper. The work of Bradstreet's, in particular, iu. cotton crop reporting, affords abundant evidence Of the soundness Of the distinction between government and newspaper publicity. Its field of activity has been gradually extending over the entire line of commercial facta through drawing to its service journalists, mon of business and others given to investigation and accurate reporting. Twenty-live years ago ihe Produce Exchange reporter had little more than taLles of prices to present. Today, through the ramification of the telegraph, ' tbo in finer coa which make prices are very largely nt tho command of the journalist.