NEW YORK AND THE COUNTRY.
The brief work of the Merchants’ Association shows at least that in laying hold of the transportation interest New York should act for the entire country instead of placing itself in antagonism thereto. New York is the national clearing house and as such its true business with reference to railway passenger fares is to set about organizing opinion to compel a general and radical reduction in rates. As it is now the metropolis has the unfortunate position of a bidder against the smaller cities in place of enlisting the aid of all in furthering the common welfare.
The danger is that President King's enthusiasm is to have the effect of raising up a deal of friction between rival cities and railway systems, while failing to disclose a principle or large action on which the forces aroused can concentrate. Here is a complaint from the South that cut rates to members of a particular trade association are in violation of the Interstate Commerce law, while the New York ticket scalpers arc stirring to see wherein they can benefit by the differences which have come in. There is time enough for the Merchants’ Association to make the most of the controversy by utilizing it as a means to advertising the underlying need of a radical and permanent cut in passenger fares. There is no time to lose, however.
To provide wise guidance for associated effort like that which Mr. King has in hand is a delicate and difficult task. To arouse the social force and fail to employ it in large action must result in harm owing to the lethargy which always follows upon such misdirection.
The most far-reaching usefulness lies before Greater New York in bringing about closer relations with the great
empire which finds here its social and trading center. The error is widespread that New York is lacking in civic pride. The notion sprang, it is fair to say, out of justifiable indifference on the part of its citizens to ill conceived projects of local import chiefly. Far more than any other city its interests are interwoven with those of the whole country, and the present need is to appeal to its enthusiasm on ^his score.
It cannot be too often repeated that action on the part of New York with reference to railway passenger fares should be in the common interest. The metropolis is in no need of advertising. Given cheap railway fares the people will come to town.
FRANKLIN FORD.