Franklin Ford Takes Exception to Some of the Remarks Made by
To the Editor of the Brooklyn Eagle:
The New York papers of this morning contain a strange speech by Mr. Bourke Cock-ran at the City Club last night. Mr. Cockran harks back to King Alfred and suggests, as a remedy for municipal ills, that the city be divided into a ward system of • government as means to distributing power to the localities, and he calls this a return to original principles.
To Mr. Cockran’s way of thinking the regulation or government of the city proceeds from a single center only—the city hall— and he fears the centralization of power therein. He got this notion from his Black-stone and. the writers on political science, the natural history or government being quite away from him. He has never seen in their true relation the bank clearing house, the board of fire underwriters, and the other organs of regulation which commerce has been developing, nor does he know that these have been coming about through influences Identical with those which raised up the king, the legislature, and the courts of law.
Mr. Cockran appears not to know the progress of the last hundred years, the steam railway, the trolley car, and electric communication. He fears the appointment of a policeman from the Bronx for the Borough of Queens, thus Ignoring the fact that all parts of the town are within easy traveling distance from the city hall and that the entire city Is bound together by means of instantaneous communication.
But the organization of city government has to be extended and deepened to correspond with the new conditions. 'The way la through a systematic organization of municipal news. Once th§ true nature of the news business is grasped, we are able to see that to subject it to scientific method Is but to carry forward the organization of government. The pedantry of the books to one side, the natural history of government is disclosed and we see parliament or the legislature as the first attempt at the definite organization of news or intelligence with reference to a given area: the members brought in the facts from the various districts for comparison and co-ordination as means to right action. The degree of news organization which telephonic conditions permit would be a development In government corresponding to the rise of a regularly constituted parliament in England at the close of the seventeenth century.
In presenting this view for acceptance, one has to contend with the inherited notion, which so afflicts Mr. Coekraa, that all social authority is inherent in a single center, usually called "the government” or "the state/1 It is because of this darkness that men are
Former.
slow to perceive that the only possible solution of - the city' government question is through the organization of municipal science Kor news. True gbvernpentjs, of course, the “reign of science. * At* a ‘ given juncture the iron trade of the world was compelled to answer to the new fact which Bessemer laid down. Likewise In 1840 the English post office had to respond to the facts presented in Rowland Hill’s report.
In 1688 the political re-formation in England amounted to far more than the substitution of ’ one king or boss for another. It consisted in pushing forward the intelligence system by means of a fully organized parliament. A corresponding change has now to be effected in the news system.
To the municipal reformers the state is the police power, and thus it turns out that through exaggerating the single center the place of the city ball is so magnified that the gaze of the people is fixed upon it as the one source of authority and pelf. All the plans of the reformers turn upon the idea of repression; the policeman is the clima* of government; the- various antithis-and-tbat societies, are but additions to the police system, and police corruption is a necessary consequence, Proceeding on the false assumption that prostitution and ordinary gambling can be suppressed by statutory devices, a premium is placed in the most direct manner on corrupt licensing by favor of the police.
The new freedom which is Turnished by the telephone and the trolley car permits the responsible organization of municipal news, and this is the idea which the reformers are seeking. As now, the city is without a center of authority corresponding to the new’ conditions; the fact does not have way. Exact reporting in the field of city government news is as feasible as in the case of a yacht race or a base ball game.
FRANKLIN FORD.
City Club, May 25, 1901.